We will now be arriving at Torishirojima
Fishing Port, Torishirojima Island.
We may experience a strong
impact upon docking.
Torishirojima, huh?
Please remain seated until further notice.
Guess this makes me a wounded bird of passage.
What's that?
Who's a wounded bird of passage?
Er...
Me?
You?
How's that?
Because I'm hurt.
Hurt where?
My heart.
F-Forget I said that.
This is my first time on the island.
Why does it feel so nostalgic?
What's that?
Ah, whoops, I was thinking out loud?
Quite a bit.
Have you ever gone somewhere that felt
nostalgic even though you'd never been before?
Oh, it's that thing...
A hijab.
What?
You mean deja vu?
That's the one.
Hijab.
Let's go.
Pardon me.
I'm sorry.
I'd planned to pick you
up at the port, but...
Anyway, again, I'm Misaki Kyouko.
I've been taking care of the house
since Grandma passed away.
Takahara Hairi.
I appreciate you looking
after me over summer break.
I'll show you to your room.
Sorry about the musty smell.
I did give it a clean, but it's been
a storage room for a long time.
No, it's a perfect reflection
of my emotional state.
After all, I'm a wounded bird of passage.
Sorry?
No, never mind.
Oh, right, I have another
relative here right now.
Family, huh?
Yeah.
Feels like she's always out of the house.
She isn't here right now.
I'll introduce you later.
"Want to come to Torishirojima Island?"
So read the letter I received from
Auntie Kyouko just before summer break.
My eccentric grandmother passed last month,
leaving behind a shed full of things
she'd collected while traveling the world.
Some of it's of sentimental
value to our family,
so we can't just call on a cleaning company.
Accordingly, Auntie Kyouko was looking
for a relative with some time to spare.
I happened to fit the bill.
Though I never had a day to spare
until last year.
And now, the weather for tomorrow, July 26th.
The Setouchi region will see high pressure...
Um...
Have you gotten any rest?
Sorry to bug you right off the bat...
Sanuki udon!
With a massive helping of kakiage tempura!
That light broth and smooth texture!
It's Sanuki udon!
Sun Curry Golden
Sanuki Udon
I wish this didn't have
to be your first meal here.
I don't mind at all.
I'm sorry.
I would have cooked for you, but y'know...
Yeah, I get it.
Huh?
Hmm?
Oh, I know! There's a nice place nearby.
Hairi-kun, can you ride a scooter?
I have a license, yeah.
There's a dining hall down the hill.
The food there is delicious.
Marin Diner
Katsudon
Cream Bun Meal
Happy Combo
Morning Combo
Lunch Combo
They have...
Excuse me, I'd like the Happy Combo.
Sure thing.
Here y'are.
Um...
I thought I ordered the Happy Combo.
The chicken and its egg died together.
Happy, no?
Guess I'll do a lap around the island.
Torishirojima
Elementary
Ah, shoot.
I'm completely lost.
Hey...
Who are you?
Uh...
Takahara Hairi.
Taka...?
What about you?
Your name.
Shiroha.
Shiroha...
What are you doing?
Practicing.
Swimming?
I'm the one who should be asking questions!
Sorry?
So you're lost?
I'm trying to get back to Katou-san's place.
Don't you mean your place, Sakahara-san?
Oh, no, it's Takahara.
S-Sakahara?
No...
Okay, Sakahara is fine.
Sorry, I should go.
Up the hill and right at the end.
Take a left at the third crossroads.
Thanks.
By the way...
Why are you practicing at night?
You shouldn't. It's dangerous.
What if you get a leg cramp
when no one's here?
...koi.
Dosukoi!
B-Bye!
Thanks for the directions!
Um...
Well?
What did you think?
Yeah, it was surprisingly good.
By the way, what's "dosukoi" about?
Incessant.
Oh, er, I'm sorry...
No, it's like a thing people say around here.
When someone's being incessant
or annoying, you say "dosukoi."
Lay off!
Ooh.
So I was being annoying.
It's a walk-off grand slam comeback!
He knocks it out of the park!
Hello.
Get up, will you?
It's already eight in the morning.
You're, uh...
Nice to meet you. I'm Umi.
You must be the other relative.
I'm Takahara Hairi.
Nice to meet you.
Pleased to make your acquaintance...
Takahara-san.
Please, dig in.
Fried rice? First thing in the morning?
I made it myself.
Wow, that's impressive.
Not really.
You're right.
How dare you?!
Oh, sorry.
You're amazing.
Okay, let's dig in.
Help yourself.
That's good!
The rice is so fluffy,
and it's seasoned just right.
Thank you.
Rock, paper, scissors!
I lost again?
You're cheating!
Chore Duty
Mon
Tues
Wed
Thurs
Fri
Sat
Sun
Trash
Umi
Dishes
Laundry
Clean room
Clean bathroom
How could I cheat at rock paper scissors?
There's no way I could lose so many times!
Fine, I'll tell you.
So you are cheating!
It isn't cheating.
It's written all over your face.
You make this "hnnngh" face
when you throw rock.
And you make this "skreee" face
when you throw scissors.
You're so obvious.
Hang on...
So I could win if I gape
my mouth when I throw rock.
Except I totally heard that.
Rock, paper, scissors...
Shoot!
How?
Fine!
So what if I make a "hnnngh"
face and throw rock?!
Rock, paper, scissors...
How...
How, how?! What gives?!
You wanna know?
How about this, then?
She's...
gone void.
Rock, paper, scissors...
I win! I win!
I did it!
Yay!
Take that!
Okay, I'm heading out.
See you later.
I'm off!
You can take a break if you want.
I'll ask you for help with the shed later.
Why not enjoy the island?
You might meet someone special.
Someone special, huh?
She's just asleep, right?
Seriously...
How is it so safe out here?
A dog?
Careful!
Uh...
Morning.
Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-Who are you?!
Why are you holding me?!
A-Are you going to have your way with me?
Please go slow at first!
So I can be aggressive eventually?
Of course not!
Takahara Hairi?
Weird name.
You can take it up with my parents.
And you're going through your grandma's stuff?
You'll be here a long time then, huh?
For a while.
Do you have to be so blatantly
creeped out by me?
I'm not that emotionally secure.
How could I not be creeped out?
You attacked me in my sleep.
I never attacked you.
Anyway, if you see me
sleeping, leave me alone.
Oh, crap!
It's two!
I'm late for work!
Inari! Let's go!
Pon!
It's two?
How did she know?
I need a change of pace.
The sea swallows everything.
Spending summer in an unfamiliar land,
all my little worries just...
Summer is always cruel.
He's really taking it in.
Wh-Who are you?
You shouldn't be dressed like that.
It's dangerous.
It's dangerous?
That freak!
She shot at me without warning!
Shot?
You there, flasher!
You are not to be undressed
outside of the bathing area!
Dress yourself and turn yourself
in immediately!
Wh-What's going on here?
A shirtless hunt.
A what?
Run for your life!
O-Okay!
I'm home.
Welcome b—
Wh-What? What's wrong?
That's my line!
Why are you half naked?
Huh?
Half naked?
Is this some custom on the island?
What?
Yesterday...
I saw a half naked man yesterday too.
Oh, the shirtless hunt...
Shirtless hunt?
No, never mind.
Forget I mentioned it.
Just hurry up and get dressed already.
Oh, right.
Takahara-san...
You got a delivery.
Noichigo 100%
Is it from home?
Were you on the swim team?
Nope.
The swim shorts club.
There's no such thing.
Just ask Kyouko-san.
Kyouko-san, what's a swim shorts club?
Please, Takahara-san! Kyouko-san
just made a weird face, and...
Huh?
Takahara-san?
Takahara-san!
Not bad, I guess.
What part?
S-Sorry, I guess I said that out loud.
Are you lost again?
Not exactly.
What, then?
Dosu—
Listen, you need to extend
your arm as far as you can.
Once it's out, hold it there for a second.
That'll make a big difference.
Wh-What?
Okay, bye!