Welcome home.
Let's eat.
It's good.
I-Is it?
Don't worry about the shed yet.
You should go have some fun.
Have fun how, though?
Uh, er...
S-See you.
W-Wait!
Huh?
Me?
What is it?
Thanks.
Huh?
I mean, for that time at the pool.
I followed your swimming
advice, and it worked.
See you.
Thanks.
Look, look! It's that guy.
Offerings
The one Grandma Kido mentioned.
Fortunes
I'm a man who's lost his wings.
The fallen angel.
It's Lucifer!
I never said that!
This was farther than I expected.
Hey!
Mugyu?
"Mugyu"?
What are you doing up there?
I'm looking for something!
What are you looking for?
Myself!
I'm also trying to find my purpose!
I don't think it's safe up there!
Mugyu?
It isn't dangerous!
You could die if you fall!
I won't die!
What are you, invincible?
I'm invincible, yeah!
I envy her.
Attention, Takahara Hairi-kun,
visitor for the last two days.
Please report to the public office.
You're late.
You... You're the shirtless hunter!
Don't you call me that.
I have a proper name. It's Nomura Miki.
Is that vicious-looking water gun
what you shot me with the other day?
That's right.
Meet the Hydrogladiator II.
You know, they used to call me
the Water Soldier myself.
The what? Weren't you
embarrassed to be called that?
Hey, you made it.
You're...
I haven't introduced myself yet, have I?
The name's Mitani—
I told you not to undress in public.
I'm sorry you had to
witness that first thing.
Anyway, once again, I'm Nomura Miki.
Everyone calls me Nomiki.
I'm Mitani Ryouichi.
Nice to meet you, Hairi.
Oh, yeah, nice to meet you.
So, what's up?
Right.
We're having a gathering tonight.
A gathering?
A welcome party for you.
I'm only here for a short vacation.
No need to be shy.
Torishirojima opens its arms for visitors.
We call long-time visitors
to the island migratory folks.
Point being, we have a tradition
of welcoming people like you.
So just shut up and accept our hospitality.
Thanks.
Then it's settled.
But that reminds me... Where's Tenzen?
I think he's hiding out on the mountain.
Hiding out? On the mountain?
We have to get ready for the welcome party.
Could you do us a favor
and go fetch Tenzen?
I don't even know what he looks like.
Pardon me.
No one's here.
Um...
Who are you?
S-Sup.
Excellent!
Huh! Looks like you've got some experience.
No, I'm definitely a novice.
Then I'll just have to bring it.
You had those on this whole time?!
I don't remember the last
time I took them off.
I feel so light!
I could fly right now!
Stop being ridiculous.
Is it time already?
Everyone's waiting for you.
By the way, who's this guy?
You're just now asking?
Marin Diner
Welcome to Torishirojima!
Welcome to Torishirojima Island!
Th-Thanks.
I appreciate it.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Sorakado Ao.
You can call me Ao.
Let's be friends.
Huh?
Yeah, let's be good... friends...
Rokuhara Tandai!
My name's Takahara Hairi!
"Hara" was the only part you got right!
What, you know each other?
Since when?
Oh, uh, er...
We just kinda ran into each other.
S-Speaking of which...
Are you guys, um...
We're the executives of
the island's youth group.
Executives, yeah...
Not that there are many people
our age around here.
Stop playing with your food.
What about Shiroha?
Shiroha?
I mean, she's roughly our age, isn't she?
Oh, you mean Naruse?
You caught me off guard,
calling her by her first name.
Do you know her?
No, I don't really know her.
And yet you're on a first-name basis?
I thought Shiroha was her last name.
Shiroha is...
Long story short, she doesn't hang out much.
She's shy.
Don't go messing with her.
What?
What do you mean, "What?"
Don't tell me you already...
I haven't done anything!
I just bumped into her.
So, is she not coming?
I did invite her, but...
I'm gonna be late, I'm gonna be late!
Morning, Umi-chan.
Heading out this early?
Yeah!
For the radio exercises.
Oh, I already made breakfast.
Okay, thanks.
Please clean up after
yourself when you're done.
See you later!
Off you go.
Man, it's so hot.
Shaved Ice
Come in.
Another scorcher, isn't it?
It sure is.
Want some shaved ice?
Oh, yes! I'd love that.
That'll be a million yen.
She really made that joke!
Ice Cream
It's hot out here.
Come on and eat inside.
I have a fan.
It's nice and cool.
Okay, thanks. I appreciate it.
Now then, explain yourself.
I mean, what can I say?
It was an accident.
Uh-huh.
You open the door on a girl who's changing,
and then you throw shaved ice right on her.
That's an accident?
Well, the shaved ice was, uh...
I was just startled.
Sure, sure.
I get it.
You open the door, and there's
a girl in her underwear.
Of course you'd be surprised.
Is that it?
I go to an all-boys school.
I'm not used to seeing
girls in so little clothing.
My first thought was that
I had to cover you up!
Ah, I see.
So you threw ice on me.
What the hell?!
I'm sorry!
Although, what were you doing
in your underwear in a snack shop?
Some kind of fetish thing?
You aren't actually sorry at all, are you?
I work here!
Ugh, my underwear's all wet! It's so gross!
I apologize.
Please throw shaved ice
on me to make it even.
What?
That makes no sense.
Like, an eye-for-eye kind of thing.
I think we need to Hammurabi this one.
Oh, so that's your idea.
That's your idea, is it?
All right, here I go.
Are you ready?
Bring it!
Ready, and...
Why are you throwing it back at me?!
Because...
It was colder than I expected.
You little...
An eye for an eye!
W-Wait!
Hold... on...
My eyes! My eyes!
Watch where you're aiming!
H-Hey! Not there!
H-H-Hold it! I never said
you could touch me there!
I never said you could touch me there either!
Man...
That was brutal.
You there, exhibitionist!
You are not to be undressed
outside of bathing areas.
Dress yourself immediately.
Where is she?
I won't miss next time.
O-Okay, I will!
I'm getting dressed now!
I'm home.
Welcome back?!
Why are you exposing yourself again?!
We were throwing shaved ice at each other.
What does that even mean?!
I drew a warm bath!
Go wash up already!
It's only been three days.
There's way too much going on here.
Why did I come to this island again?
Say, I'm headed out for a bit again.
I heard you've made friends
with the youth group kids.
Yeah, I guess so.
That's great.
I'm glad you're having fun.
I'm sorry I haven't been any help at all.
I'll ask you for a hand soon enough.
Soon enough?
Yup.
That's right.
I came here because Kyouko-san asked me to.
No...
That's just an excuse.
I just wanted to escape somewhere.
I'm trying to find my purpose!
Huh?
Good evening.
What are you doing?
Just taking a walk.
I see.
Uh...
Shiroha-san, are you...
How do you know my name?
We introduced ourselves.
Back when we first met.
Haibara Satoshi.
Nope.
Takahara Hairi.
So, Shiroha-san...
My name...
Oh, sorry.
It's actually weirder with the "-san."
Oh, okay.
So, what is it?
You were about to ask me something.
Right.
Yeah, well...
When I first got here, Shiroha-san...
Shiroha, I saw you at the port.
No, I didn't mean anything by it or anything!
I just spotted you from the boat.
You were looking at something.
Birds.
Birds?
Yeah.
There were two birds over the water.
Why come to an island like this?
Actually...
I can't remember.
Remember what?
I thought...
I could finally put into words...
Why I came to this island.
That's right.
I couldn't remember.
I felt like I was drowning
in the passage of time back home.
I was suffocating.
I came here because I wanted to remember...
How to spend summer break.
Hey, listen...
When was your favorite summer break?
When I was little, I guess.
Yeah, I figured.
It's gotta be when you're a kid.
A long time ago, when I was little,
I'd run around in a seemingly endless summer.
One full of family and friends.
There was always something to do.
And the sun was always
shining brilliantly in our lives.
At some point, I forgot what that was like.
But...
It's something I'm sure I remember.
Ever since coming to this island,
I've been able to recall my time as a kid.
I don't know why...
But it's kind of exciting.
Maybe you feel that way because
the island is right for you.
I see.
That would be nice.
Yeah.
So...
There's something I want to ask.
Um...
See...
What did you mean
about your wings being broken?
Grandma Kido told me you came
here to mend your broken wings.
That was just a metaphor.
I've been through a lot.
I went through a lot,
and my wings were hurt in the process.
Now I can't fly.
Something like that.
Something like that?
Weirdo.