Crab fried rice!
I kinda want the crab on its own, but hey.
That's good.
Where'd you get crab, though?
I got it for free at the port.
You did, huh?
Never thought they'd just give away
something as expensive as crab.
Tell me if you have any requests,
and I'll put it in the fried rice next time.
But fried rice is a given, huh?
Of course.
Don't worry about the shed yet.
I should really start working, though.
I still need to separate out some more trash.
How can you be so lazy?
Going out again, Umi-chan?
Yeah!
Bug hunting with friends
from around the island.
The weather's so nice.
Don't waste it flopping around at home.
Summer break won't last forever.
Why not go out on an adventure?
I'm a bit too old for adventuring.
A grown-up adventure, then!
A grown-up adventure?
Noichigo 100%
You look like you're thinking
about something dirty.
I-I'm not!
I don't know what you had in mind,
but I'm talking about catching the big
one at the reservoir or something.
The big one at the reservoir, you say?
Yeah, I can totally picture
there being a big one here.
Shiroha?
Radar!
Radar—
U-Um...
You got me!
S-Sorry!
That's on me.
R-Reigen iyachiko nare...
Huh?
Reigen iyachiko nare.
Wh-What?
Reigen iyachiko nare!
R-Rei... what?
I-It's a jinx that's been
passed down through my family!
It's a perfectly normal thing to say
in my family and, er, all over the island.
I was chanting a greeting
to the lord of the river.
Everyone on the island does it!
It's not weird or embarrassing in any way!
Maybe it took you by surprise
as an outsider, but...
It's totally normal in my family!
I mean, on the island!
S-Sure.
Reigen iyachiko nare!
R-Reigen iyachikoma—
No!
Reigen iyachiko nare!
So...
Do you like manga?
I like manga,
but I hate you!
I mean...
I never asked how you felt about me.
Better apologize next time I see her.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Oh, I was just wondering what the matter is.
It's stuck.
May I help?
There we go.
Thanks, Hairi.
Er...
Do I know you from somewhere?
No, this is the first time we've met.
But you know my name.
You're more famous than you think.
Kushima Kamome.
My name, I mean.
It'd be weird if only I knew yours.
Kushima Kamomay...
Would you mind not saying it
with the long "may"?
But "Kamome" just makes
me want to shout "may!"
Just your namesake seagulls.
Those are black-tailed gulls.
Oh yeah? Then what does a seagull say?
Let me think...
"Kyah, kyah," I guess.
Gosh, stop staring like
there's something wrong with me.
My bad. Sorry, I couldn't help it.
Then you can make it up
to me by doing me a favor.
You know...
I don't mind pushing the suitcase...
But why are you sitting on it?
Ease and comfort!
Sheesh...
I guess you're royalty or something.
Straight down this road?
Yeah.
Something like that.
Hey, what's in this suitcase?
I wonder.
Not telling!
What's that song again?
It sounds familiar.
"With" by Median Sherlotte.
That's an oldie, isn't it?
Yeah. It was big a long time ago.
Takahara-san?
Hey, Umi-chan.
What are you up to?
Beats me.
Pushing a suitcase with
a girl on top, I suppose.
It's pretty surreal when
you say it like that.
Do you want to get on, too?
I'm not a child!
Hey!
Yeah?
There's a lady in a kimono on the ground!
She says she's too hungry to move!
This island's full of weirdos.
Oh, there's a hill up ahead.
Be careful, would you?
This looks dangerous.
Hop on off.
All right, let's give it a go!
No, it's too dangerous.
It'll be just fine.
Here we go!
Whoo!
Hey!
This is gonna test my balance!
Can you make the turn?!
I'm good!
I'm going for it!
Kamome!
This is... that day.
That's right.
This is the start.
Take your marks!
That's where it all started!
What a shame...
That wasn't the start of anything.
In fact, that's where it all ended.
You all right?
B-Barely...
Gosh, why'd you dive in in the first place?
I don't know what to say.
Thanks, though.
You jumped in even though you can't swim.
This cat...
The symbol of the Higenekos.
The Higenekos?
That's funny...
I feel like I've seen it somewhere.
Wh-What gives?
It's so nice and cold.
Yikes, I'm soaked.
No kidding.
It won't take long to dry off in this weather.
Yeah.
It'll be...
I saw the heavens.
They were blue.
The sky was, I mean.
Although I think her underwear was too.
Is something the matter?
Nah, it's just so blue...
Blue?
The sky.
Oh.
You're right. It really is.
For sure.
You know, I've been to this island before.
How long ago was that?
A pretty long time ago.
Back when I was about as big as this suitcase.
Wow.
Must be nostalgic for you, then.
Super.
There was a summer camp here
with kids from all over the country.
It was just for that one year.
I took part in it.
So you've come to retrace some memories?
You could say that.
What brings you to the island?
Me?
I...
Shall I guess?
Let's see...
An adventure?
Summer break won't last forever.
Why not go out on an adventure?
An adventure, huh?
I'd love to go on one
if there were such a thing.
Granted, I'm not expecting anything
on such a tiny island.
I wouldn't be so sure.
Let's go! This way!
Wait!
Where?
To find adventure!
How far are we going?
You'll find out when we get there.
That doesn't even make any sense.
Ice Cream
Sorry, just a sec.
Shiroha.
S-Sorry for scaring you.
Wh-Wh-Wha... Wh-Wh-What?
I just wanted to apologize
for back at the reservoir.
So, uh...
Are you here to get something?
Well...
Want me to go buy it?
Really?
I owe you one anyway.
What's your order?
A watermelon bar.
Got it.
Just a sec.
Here you go.
What is this?
A melon bar.
They were out of watermelon ones.
You can have it.
Huh? But you paid...
It's on me.
O-Oh.
You're acquainted with that cutie?
I didn't think you had it in you.
Want it?
What? Really?
I kept you waiting.
Okay. I'll take it, then.
Thanks.
We're here.
Isn't this...
Yup.
The elementary school.
Hey! That's not safe!
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Hairi.
You should join me.
This is a design flaw.
Kids are bound to climb up here.
Astute observation.
All right, this way now.
Where are we going?
Over there.
Where our adventure starts.
Hey, be careful!
I'm fine!
It's just ahead.
The lock on this window
is broken, if I remember...
Should we be going in?
It's fine, it's fine!
Come on already!
What's inside here?
Found it!
Thank goodness.
It's still here.
This is it?
That's right.
The start of our adventure.
I climbed up here with my friend
at the end of the summer.
And we put up this flag.
All to prepare for the day we'd reconvene.
That drawing...
Higeneko!
It was our crew's flag!
From the summer camp you mentioned earlier?
Yeah.
That summer, me and my friend took
our flag and set out on an adventure.
Then we hid our secret along with the flag.
Your secret?
You sure?
Yeah.
"For when we gather ten years from now...
We hereby lock the island's treasure
we found today in this chest."
So that's what's in the box?
Yeah.
It's locked up tight.
Should I bust it?
Hey now.
Well, what did you find?
What's the secret?
Hairi, the view from over
here is spectacular.
I came from beyond that sea.
Thanks for tagging along with me today.
Sure.
Did you have fun?
It wasn't bad.
I'll take you on an even more
special adventure next time!
A special adventure?
Yup.
Until then!
Later.
Adventure, huh?
Today was pretty modest
to be called an adventure,
but in the attic of the elementary
school beyond the pool fence
lay treasure that Kamome
apparently hid there as a child.
That kind of thing is exciting.
It was definitely an adventure.
What's up?
I'm beat.
It's going to be a pain
getting home lugging this.
Why not ditch it somewhere?
I can't do that.
And you know what that means.
You're pushing me.
I appreciate your service.
You'd better.
How do we get to your place?
Straight this way.
Straight? That's the port.
Yup.
Take me to the port.
Are you getting on a boat or something?
Something like that.
I thought you were heading home.
I kinda am and I'm kinda not.
Why the riddle?
Why not?
Where do you live, Hairi?
Me?
I think I'm that way.
Katou-san's looking after me.
That's in the opposite direction.
Maybe I shouldn't have imposed.
It's okay. I'm bored anyway.
How kind.
You're a good guy.
What are you trying to say?
Exactly what I said.
Yeah, you're welcome.