Check this out, Taka!
A map of this island?
Yeah!
Torishirojima
I wanna get to this X.
Okay...
Is something there?
Treasure!
You're lying.
There's no way there's treasure.
Well, we gotta go find out!
Why do I have to, though?
Because you look athletic.
I bet you'll be fine, even if there's danger.
In that case, there's someone
who'd be even more useful than me.
Really? Who?
Hup.
Tsubame is my name.
Where did you come from?!
I'd swear you came outta the trees!
That is a secret.
She's a ninja!
You kids.
You look like you're up to no good.
Uh-oh...
Who are you?
I'm Hayato.
As student president, I can't just stand by.
Um...
You're... Suzume-chan, right?
Yeah.
C-Can I have some treasure if I help out too?
Sure!
Let's all find it together.
I see, I see...
Hey.
You came, huh?
Look at you!
You made it here!
C'mon, you! C'mon, c'mon, c'mon!
Y-Yeah...
C'mon, c'mon!
We hid the secret of this island in this box,
then we all locked it together.
Four locks, huh?
Yup.
There were five of us.
So the five of you hid the keys?
But there're only four...
As the leader, I was tasked
with holding on to this notebook.
So I didn't have a key.
You were the leader?
Wh-What's wrong with that?
Who else was on board?
A dog and a pheasant?
Bah!
A sheep?
I'm angry!
I made a great team leader.
Okay, now if you find the keys
and open this box,
you get access to the island's secret.
So, what's the secret?
Come closer.
The secret is...
not something I'd spill!
Anyway, the keys are hidden
according to the hints written here.
The castle in the sky where
the sea eagle lives
Beneath the kaitei
watched over by the kaijin
The guard dog sleeps by
the gateway to the next life
The desert where basilisks gather
Riddles, huh?
But these are ten years old, right?
Wherever you hid the keys,
I can't imagine they're still there.
Like, "kaitei" here means "under the sea."
If that's literal,
there's no way you're getting it back.
I'm confident we thought things
through when hiding them.
For example...
Doesn't look like there are any keys here.
Yeah...
Well, what do you think "kaijin" means?
Kaijin...
If it's supposed to mean "sea god,"
maybe there's a statue somewhere.
I've been around the whole island,
and I don't remember seeing one.
Kaijin...
A sea god?
Protecting the sea?
Maybe the lighthouse?
That keeps the sea safe.
That makes sense!
Mugyu?
Aren't you...
Do you know each other?
Yeah, kinda.
I'm Takahara Hairi.
And this is Kushima Kamomehhh.
"Mehhh"?
Hold it.
That's not right.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Kushima Kamome.
Hello there.
I'm Tsumugi Wenders.
You're cleaning up litter, huh?
Good on you.
I'll lend you a hand.
Count me in too.
Mugyu...
You're both such nice people.
I see. So you're looking for keys.
I haven't seen any.
Figures.
I wouldn't have thought so.
But we do know...
it's underwater near the lighthouse?
If that's the case, we're never finding it.
"Beneath the kaitei
watched over by the kaijin..."
Maybe there's some other meaning to it.
What are you, a kaijin? Like the humanoid
monsters from sentai shows?
Yeah, those.
I really doubt that's what it's going for.
Maybe it's not the "kaijin" part
we're not getting, but the "kaitei."
Excuse me.
Do you happen to have a dictionary?
Here you go.
Are we really going to find it here?
If my reasoning is correct.
The key!
We found the key!
So I was right.
How did you know?
Written this way, "kaitei" means "stairs."
Kaitei
The "kaitei" being watched over
meant the stairs to this shrine
Fortunes
Offerings
to the sea god who protects the sea.
I never learned that...
I'm so glad the key was still there.
Thanks, Hairi. I owe you.
Man, couldn't you guys
have chosen a simpler hint?
I know, right?
Thanks for walking me here.
See you tomorrow.
It might be the day after.
Sure, fine by me.
If the day after doesn't work,
we have the day after that.
No matter how late, there's always tomorrow!
Dondon gabacho!
Say what?
You don't know it?
Not at all.
Anyway, come help me out again
if you ever feel like it.
Sure.
See you tomorrow.
That wasn't it either...
"The guard dog sleeps by the
gateway to the next life."
This dog would need to be over a decade old.
I wonder how many of those
there are on the island.
This should be the place.
The crematorium?
Oh, I see.
The "gateway to the next life."
A bit morbid, but...
Don't mind me.
Found it!
I really found it!
The second key!
Nice!
On to the next one!
"The desert where basilisks gather."
Basilisks are those bird
monsters, aren't they?
"Where birds gather..."
Maybe a chicken coop?
That's it!
Someone who keeps chickens?
I think a few folks do.
I'm looking for somewhere with a lot.
Let's see...
Maybe Naruse-san's place, then.
They have a big shed there
with lots of chickens.
I-I see.
Naruse-san?
You saw her in front of the
snack shop the other day.
Ah, that girl!
You're close enough
to drop by her place, huh?
Good going, you.
Heh, I guess so.
Naruse Shiroha and I have been acquainted
since the day I came to the island.
You player, you!
Naruse
Pardon me!
Pardon me...
Yes?
U-Um...
I-I'm Takahara Hairi.
I don't know you.
U-Um...
I-Is Shiroha-san...
You're on a first-name basis?
That's awful chummy.
Who're you?
We're friends.
Outsiders!
That didn't work out.
Do you really know each other?
I had no idea she had a grandpa like that.
Hey, that was a school uniform, wasn't it?
Yeah, looks like it.
Maybe her gramps would trust us in those.
He'd think we're school friends.
Yeah, that might lower his guard a little.
What?
Do you think we can find a uniform?
Ao, lend me your school uniform.
Huh?
Lend me your uniform.
Wh-What? No way in hell!
I'm begging you!
My friend's absolutely in love.
She's infatuated.
I-I'm no idol or anything. I don't know how
to deal with that kind of attention...
I meant she loves the uniform.
I knew what you meant!
At last, I'm a schoolgirl!
It looks pretty tight.
Especially in the b—
Bwuh!
The bwuh?
What's that?
Nothing. Never mind.
Just think of it as a kind of tic.
Okay...
Good afternoon!
What, you again?
Hello.
Shiroha!
Your friends are here!
Ugh.
"Ugh"? Really?
Hello.
Who are you?
I'm Kushima Kamome.
Hi.
What do you want?
Pardon us.
Now then, where could they have hidden it?
Found it!
I see.
Weekly Young Boy
There's a woman on there.
Naked.
That's what you were looking for?
N-N-N-No!
That's the third one.
Yay!
What's that?
It's a key for opening a chest
containing the island's treasure.
That sounds fun.
Right?!
Y-Yeah.
Wanna help us find it?
No.
I put her on the spot.
Can't blame her for that.
She's always like that.
Don't worry about it.
But man, you know...
The Higenekos, was it?
I can kinda see why you were the leader.
Y-You don't say.
You're weirdly assertive about stuff.
Nah.
You're giving me too much credit.
I just wanted friends. That's all.
I was always shy and
anxious around strangers.
Ten years ago, my friends pushed me into
summer camp to try to overcome that.
I couldn't stand it at first.
I was always by my lonesome while
everyone else was forming groups.
But then I found a map in my dad's study.
My dad's a scholar.
He was apparently studying
the history of this island.
And he kept that map tucked
safely in the back of his desk.
It had a red X and a quick note on it...
Just the word "treasure."
But you have to traverse
the mountains to reach it.
I knew the grown-ups wouldn't let me go.
So I tried talking the most promising
kid into going with me.
Talk about pragmatic.
His name was Taka.
He was a bit intimidating,
but he was athletic.
And then there was Tsubame.
Hayato too.
Then Suzume rounded out the five of us.
What's wrong?
Something bothering you?
No. It's just that all of this sounds familiar.
Oh yeah?
Then you've been on an adventure before too.
Could be.
"The castle in the sky
where the sea eagle lives," huh?
We're getting good at this.
That's the fourth one.
Yup.
That makes all of them.
Hairi!
Wake up, Hairi.
It's morning.
Morning, Hairi.
M-Morning.
Why are you...
Well, I'm the reason you got hurt, so...
I thought I'd take care of you for a while.
I appreciate the thought, but...
Why are you dressed like that?
I told Kyouko-san I'd be helping
out for a while, and...
She offered me this!
What do you think?
Looks good on her, right?
Yeah... I guess it does.
Yay!
Okay, I'll be keeping busy.
She works hard, doesn't she?
Yeah.
Hairi, I'm here to scrub your back.
Wh-Why?!
Why not? I came to help.
B-But you're...
No need to be so shy.
You're wearing a towel, aren't you?
Nope.
W-Well, I may as well scrub
your back while I'm here.
Put a towel on, though.
Come on!
Do you really need to get that worked up?
Sorry, never mind!
I can't!
Okay, let's open up the box now.
Yeah.
This is the treasure you were talking about?
That's right.
Thank goodness.
It's still here.
Kamome...
To be honest, I wasn't sure
I'd be able to recover it.
But with your help, we found it.
Thank you, Hairi.
I'm happy for you.
So, what is it anyway?
Whatever it is you recovered.
The secret of the island.
I was under the impression
it's what was in the chest.
What we found would never fit in this chest.
It's that big?
It's huge.
Must be some treasure.
Yup.
It's amazing.
And what is it?
Look. It shows you right here.
A ship?
Yup.
Well, this is an island.
A ship or two is no surprise.
Tut, tut, tut.
It's no ordinary ship.
What do you mean?
You see...
You aren't getting me this time.
You're going to tease me and
then refuse to tell me, right?
I see through you.
Nuh-uh.
I was really going to tell you this time.
What?
For real?
For real.
I wanna know, then!
Yeah?
Then I guess I'll tell you.
Ahem.
Okay, here goes.
We followed this map to
the end of the island.
Past the mountains and through caves.
It was a long journey.
And then we found...
a pirate ship!
What?
A pirate ship, uh...
like with a skull and crossbones and stuff?
Yup.
One of those pirate ships.
It had a skull and crossbones,
like one you'd see drifting
near Europe or something.
You're lying.
I'm not lying.
Right after we found that ship,
we had to turn back.
And the next day, summer camp was over.
We all went our separate ways.
So you guys found it and left it there.
Yeah.
Assuming that's true,
is it still in the same spot?
It should be.
That day, when we found the pirate ship,
we promised to come find
it again ten years later.
Then we bade each other farewell.
And so you came back to find it.
This summer, ten years later.
Yeah.
The map and keys were all still here.
So I'm going.
One more time...
to where the pirate ship is.