When I'm with you, I can go anywhere!
What're you singing?
"With."
What's that mean?
As in, "to be together" in English.
It means to be together?
You were singing it
and didn't even know that?
The title means "to be together"? Weird.
Speaking of titles for things,
should we pick out a team name?
A team name?
Oh, I already have one in mind!
Ta-da!
What's that?
It's Higeneko, of course.
So there, it's settled!
Our team name is Team Higeneko Kamome!
Leave "Kamome" out!
Okay, then the Higenekos!
Whoo!
Wh-Whoo.
Kamome!
So heavy...
Hey, get up, Kamome.
He's gonna do naughty things to me!
I would never!
Food... check!
Camping gear we borrowed
from Ryouichi... check!
Attention, Takahara Hairi!
Here!
Is your arm all better?
Yeah.
Check it out.
Good.
Then off we go on our adventure
to find the pirate ship!
Yeah!
So, which way from here?
Let's see...
That way.
Look.
So this is our starting point.
Looks like it.
"With," was it?
I remember hearing it a long time ago.
Right?
Sorry I walk so slow.
It can't be easy rolling
that suitcase on the tracks.
It's not so bad.
I switched to mountain gear before I left.
Y-Yeah?
Want me to take it?
Nah.
It's all right.
Okay.
Let's keep going.
I used to...
I remember holding everyone up before too.
I've always walked slow.
I see.
Don't worry about it.
We can just take it easy
and reminisce about the past.
Hairi...
You're such a nice guy.
Seriously, cut that out.
It's really here...
That note telling us to go toward snack time
meant in the direction of 3 o'clock.
You're on fire, Hairi!
Do you think the cave is along these tracks?
I sure hope so.
So hot...
Are you all right?
Wanna take a break in the shade?
Kamome?
Kamome?!
Hey!
Kamome!
So hot...
It sure is hot...
Hey, how far are we going?
Kamome-kun! Could you hurry up?
Sorry.
I'm gonna take in the scenery.
You guys go ahead.
You sure that isn't weighing you down?
I'll take it.
No, I'll handle it myself.
Stop arguing and give it.
No!
Give it already!
Stop it!
You're...
I'll catch up later.
I don't want to hold everyone back.
Go on without me.
Hairi?
Hey, Hairi.
Hey!
Takahara Hairi-kun!
Huh?
Are you okay?
You were spaced out there.
Wait, where have you been?
What? I was right behind you.
Oh.
We've walked pretty far.
Do you think it's much farther?
Do you think we might have...
The cave!
We found it!
Yeah!
So noisy...
Ow, ow, ow...
Hey, you all right?
Does your leg hurt?
Yeah.
I'm okay, though.
It'll get better.
You're lying.
You've been in pain all day, haven't you?
You didn't want to give me the suitcase
'cause you're using it
like a crutch, aren't you?
Yeah.
Why didn't you tell me...?
Morning.
She's gonna do naughty things to me!
Am not.
Anyway, did you get any rest?
Yeah, thanks.
Hey, can I ask you something?
I managed to sleep, but I sweated a ton.
I know.
Same here.
Well, there's a little
spring-looking thing over there.
I see.
And, so, I was thinking
of going for a bit of a dip.
Oh, hey, splashing!
Wonder what that could be.
Just kidding...
Are you all right?!
Something's there!
Something huge!
She's not lying.
They're huge.
You saw what where?
B-By those rocks.
Maybe this is his watering hole.
Must've gotten excited after
seeing you here.
Oh, right.
He got excited because he saw me...
What?
Huh?
Oh, no, I'm not talking about me!
You didn't see, did you?
S-See what?
I mean...
Stuff.
R-Right.
I saw nothing.
Y-You're lying.
I did! I couldn't help
catching a glimpse, okay?
What exactly did you see?
What?
Your b—
Bwuh!
Here we go again! The mysterious "bwuh" tic!
I know it's a bit late now...
But isn't entering a restricted
cave dangerous?
Yeah.
But there's no sense worrying about that now.
It's plenty sensible to be worried.
I'm going even if I have to go alone.
Sheesh.
I knew you'd say that.
It's just like before...
Huh?
What do you mean, just like before?
Ah, it's nothing.
We just need to go straight, right?
If I remember right.
There's a part that gets narrow
about 300 meters from the entrance.
Here?
Yeah, here.
It opens up past this.
Here!
We can get through here!
I'll go first.
O-Okay.
Hang on...
Have I been here before?
Which way are we going?
That way.
There's a stream just up ahead.
Got it.
Is your leg okay?
Huh? Why?
I was... just wondering.
Aren't you using that suitcase
because your leg's messed up?
Wh-Why do you ask?
I'm totally fine...
I wouldn't have come here if I had a bad leg.
You're right.
So why are you dragging that around, then?
This thing?
I'm not telling you!
No, I want to know.
We're on an adventure together.
Adventuring is dangerous business.
You put everyone at risk by keeping secrets.
I mean, not that there's anyone
else besides you and me.
U-Um...
The truth is...
My leg hurts sometimes,
especially on cold nights and mornings.
I see.
I'm sorry I never told you.
You said you were hospitalized.
Were you sick?
Yeah.
Most of the time,
it's just a little hard to walk.
Sometimes it gets difficult
to breathe or even move at all.
You've gotta be kidding me!
Why...
Why would you...
I'm sorry.
I was feeling well, so I thought I'd be okay.
We're going home in the morning.
N-No!
Don't be stupid!
You seriously plan on going
into the cave like this?
Please...
Please, just don't tell me we're going back.
I knew you'd say that.
Hey, we've come this far.
No point turning back now.
Thank you.
Let's take a quick break.
Okay.
Hey...
Why did you come to this island, Hairi?
Where's this coming from?
Because I feel like you've been
probing me this entire time.
It's not fair.
Jeez.
I told you I came to heal.
So you're hurt, then?
I guess.
What happened?
Hey, why do I have to get into personal stuff?
I'm curious.
No keeping secrets!
Damn it all...
I screwed up a team thing.
You screwed up?
Long story short, I let people down.
So then you ran away?
Ran away, huh?
Yeah, you could say that.
I see.
So you let people down...
Even so, it's cool that they were
counting on you in the first place.
I guess so.
It really stings to disappoint people
when they expect a lot of you.
You're right.
Being let down stings a lot too, doesn't it?
Oh, come on!
Couldn't you be a bit more sympathetic?
Oh, sorry.
Don't mind me.
I was talking about something else.
Not about you.
There's something I'm
really looking forward to.
I didn't think I was, but the closer I get to
the goal, the more I realize how eager I am.
For what?
Meeting my friends.
The pirate ship should
still be past this cave,
and at least one of them
should already be there.
They should be waiting for me.
But to be honest, I don't
think there's anyone there.
I've always been in poor health.
I spent a lot of time in the hospital.
I don't have many memories
of playing during summer break.
That's why this one is so important to me.
But I know it wasn't
like that for anyone else.
It was just one of many
memories from that summer.
It's been buried and forgotten...
But to me, it's my only treasure.
That's why I'm so obsessed.
Now then...
Wanna get going?
Just a sec.
Your flashlight.
I-It's okay.
I have spare batteries.
Kamome!
Hairi!
Please, Hairi!
It's okay.
I'm sure we're almost at our goal.
When I'm with you, I can go anywhere!
Or I'm fine not going anywhere!
When I'm with you,
I can go anywhere in the world!
Or be fine not going!
I can go anywhere—
Light!
It's the exit!
We're out!
I can smell the sea.
Let's go.
Yeah.
Hairi!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm all right.
Thank goodness.
There's no way I'd drown.
I'm on the swim team.
You never told me.
That's right.
Which means it was your swim
team you let down, in that case.
You didn't need to bring that up now.
Sorry.
Also...
Sorry if I've got the wrong idea...
But it felt like I was being
kissed before I woke up.
Were you giving me mouth-to-mouth?
I-It was for first aid!
You don't need to be so shy about it!
Right!
It was first aid!
Hairi, look!
There's light over there!
Does your leg hurt?
Sorry.
Where's the suitcase?
It fell into the water, and...
I see.
Do you need my shoulder?
I'll be okay.
We're almost there.
I wanna go without any help.
All right.
But let's take our time.
Okay.
About what you were saying...
About how everyone forgot those memories.
I think you have grandiose ideas
about summer break.
It's not as easy to make great memories
over summer as you think.
Things like adventuring across
an island to find a pirate ship...
I'm no kid anymore,
and even I'm excited right now.
I see.
Will you remember everything
that happened today, Hairi?
I think I will.
I think I'll remember it forever.