Long ago, when I was little,
I ran through a seemingly endless summer.
With my family. With my friends.
I could play forever
and still have more to do.
The sun gleamed down on us,
watching over every day.
Eventually, that memory became
a figment of the distant past.
Yet I still remember the bright
light on my eyelids.
I flew in search of that brightness.
Just a little...
Just a little more, and I'd make it there.
To that summer.
Come in.
I've heard all about you.
Thank you for having me.
We will now be arriving at Torishirojima
Fishing Port, Torishirojima Island.
We may experience a strong
impact upon docking.
Torishirojima, huh?
Please remain seated until further notice.
Guess this makes me a songless canary.
Say what?
What am I even doing?
And what is this place?
Hello.
Hello?
Hello!
Get up, will you? Hairi-san!
Sheesh.
It's already eight.
Good morning, Umi-chan.
I'm digging in.
What do you think?
I made that fried rice myself.
Wow, you did, huh?
It's good, I think.
Boo.
Don't worry about it yet.
I'll ask for your help eventually.
Make yourself at home, okay, Hairi-kun?
Okay...
It's been a few days since I
arrived here on Torishirojima.
I came to help sort through
my late grandmother's belongings.
Or so I thought, but I still
haven't gotten to do anything.
Meanwhile, I'm getting to know all the
people my age who live here.
They all seem all right.
Although they are pretty eccentric...
Especially her.
Naruse Shiroha.
Dosukoi!
Apparently, that means "you're annoying
as hell" in the local dialect.
It's not a nice thing to say to people.
What'd I even do to do deserve it?
What am I doing here?
That's him! The guy Grandma Kido mentioned.
The canary who forgot how to sing.
A canary that sings rock.
A canarian rocker!
I definitely never put it like that!
This was farther than I expected.
Hey!
Mugyu?
"Mugyu"?
What are you doing up there?
I'm looking for something!
What are you looking for?
Myself!
I'm also trying to find my purpose!
I don't think it's safe up there!
Mugyu?
It isn't dangerous!
You could die if you fall!
I won't die!
What are you, invincible?
I'm invincible, yeah!
I envy her.
The bath?
Unfortunately.
The water just shut off all of a sudden.
I can survive a night without a bath.
No way!
Skipping a bath in the summer?
You can't be serious!
You sure took your time, Umi-chan...
That was normal, okay?
N-No, I meant...
Thanks for waiting!
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
If you'll excuse me.
Puberty?
What? Who?
This feels great!
I'm gonna get my license when I turn sixteen!
Huh?
It's night, and the light's not on.
You mean the lighthouse?
From what I've heard, no one maintains it,
so it's out of service.
It is, is it?
I'm looking for something!
Looking for something, huh?
Goodness me.
Here you are.
My, thank you.
Are you looking for something too?
Indeed, you must be.
You seek the never-before-seen...
boobies.
Huh?
Did she just say "boobies"?
Anyway, what's your name?
I'm Takahara Hairi.
I see.
Takahara Pairi-kun.
Wait, I said my name's Hairi.
I understand.
Pairi-kun is simply Pairi-kun.
Isn't that right, Pairi-kun?
I'm Mizuori Shizuku.
Call me Shizuku if you'd like.
Or Boobies-san, if you'd prefer.
Shizuku it is.
Oh... That's a shame.
Shizuku!
Mugyu-gyu-gyu...
G-Give me a hand!
Mugyu?
A-Are you all right?
Yes, sorry.
Oh, we met yesterday.
You're...
Who are you again?
Thanks for helping me out.
No worries. I had the time.
Thank you so much, um...
Takahara Hairi-san!
You forgot my name, didn't you?
Yup.
I remember it now, though. Takahara-san!
Anyway, I'm surprised you two have
managed so much by yourselves.
Tsumugi insisted on gathering trash
from the beach because it might be fun.
I mean, you have to support your
friends in their endeavors, right?
Friends, huh?
Well?
Was it fun?
It wasn't any fun at all.
Why did I even decide to do this?
I'm filled with regret.
Was it that bad?
Well, I do have new friends now!
First things first,
gotta sort through all this.
Hey, what about this one?
Yumyum Flavor
An empty Paringles can?
Mugyu-gyu...
The body is made of paper,
so it goes with the combustibles.
But the bottom appears to be metal.
Then we can't just pitch it.
I suppose not.
It'd be good if we could recycle it.
Mugyu...
Recycling, huh?
Thank you for all your
help today, Takahara-san.
Now, as a token of our gratitude,
we'll show you around the
island's tourist attractions.
Look over there.
The famed Boobie Boulders.
I came up with the name!
That's an atrocious name.
Shizuku, I have a question.
I see three boulders.
Don't people normally have two boobies?
Tsumugi!
Who says you can't have three?
That would actually be even better!
And this is another tourist attraction?
Yes.
Someone powerful used to live here.
Someone powerful?
Yes.
They were ruined a long time ago, though.
No one lives there anymore.
What do you think?
How am I supposed to answer that?
You look fantastic, Shizuku.
You're pure boobies!
My!
What a lovely compliment, Tsumugi!
All right, see you soon!
I came along because you said there
was something you wanted to do.
You meant swimming, huh?
I don't care as long as Shizuku's having fun.
Are you going in in that outfit, Tsumugi?
I suppose so.
I didn't bring a swimming suit,
so I think I'll just dip my feet in.
Let's join her, Takahara-san!
I...
I'll pass.
Mugyu?
Do you not like getting in the water?
Yeah, you could say that.
Well, everyone's got their reasons.
Yeah...
I've got my reasons.
Why don't you give it a try today, though?
I think it'll nurture our friendship
if we take a dip together.
Splashing each other and stuff.
We'd be nurturing the crap out of our friendship!
I bet it'll be fun!
Let me show you what I'm made of!
Here we go!
Hey!
F-Fine!
I'll dip my feet in!
Mugyu!
Tsumugi!
Are you okay?
My... You're soaked.
Oh, this is embarrassing.
You're in the water.
Takahara-san, you're in the water!
I lost what I wanted to do this summer.
So I've been thinking...
Maybe I came here to find what I lost.
What a coincidence.
I've been looking for something too.
For what I want to do.
And for why I'm here, too.
For why you're here?
It's always felt like too much to me.
But with the two of you here,
I think I can find something!
Okay.
I don't know if we'll actually find it,
but wanna search together?
Let's find what you want to do.
Mugyu!
Thank you very much!
So, what is it that I want to do?
Straight to brass tacks, huh?
Let's do anything Tsumugi's
even slightly interested in.
Any ideas?
Let me think...
Oh, I have an idea!
That was surprisingly quick.
I want to hang out with the
two of you like this forever!
We can eat together, stargaze
at night, and talk lots and lots!
You mean like a sleepover, then?
Hey, that's my Shizuku!
That's it exactly!
A sleepover?
Are you sure, though?
You're cool having me over when we just met?
I don't mind.
I don't either.
I like you, Takahara-san.
You do?
Yeah! It's not even hard to.
It's not, huh?
Welcome, Takahara-san!
What's up with that?
I'm a cat.
Yeah, you sure are.
We also have a cow.
Moo.
So you really do live
at the lighthouse, Tsumugi?
It's pretty cute in here, too.
Is it?
You're making me blush.
Why don't we have dinner?
Okay!
Mugyu!
I'm used to being by myself,
so I only made one serving.
We're all going to starve to death!
Oh, relax.
Not eating for a day won't kill us.
Maybe it will...
I brought some snacks.
Paringles!
Mugyu!
Nice going, Takahara-san!
Mugyu...
Mugyu-gyu...
Oh, I have an idea.
Takahara-san.
Yes?
Pweeve feev me!
Me too!
Ah!
I-I guess I'm doing this, huh?
Yum!
Nothing beats Paringles!
Don't I get any?
I had no idea there were so many stars.
This is one of the nice
things about the island.
I can almost grab them.
Mugyu...
Not today, I guess.
You were singing that the
first time we met too.
She sings it when she's happy and having fun.
What's it called?
Mugyu?
I don't know.
You don't know the name
of the song you sing?
That's right.
I don't know what it's called or the lyrics.
But I've loved it forever.
Singing this song makes me
feel like I can find myself.
Like I'll find my purpose.
It gives me hope.
Why don't we investigate the song?
Mugyu? The song?
Sounds good.
We'll run the song by the islanders.
Maybe that'll turn up something.
You want the islanders to hear my song?
You mean you're going
to set up a concert for me?
That's a tall order.
I'm glad I got to spend time with you.
I'm so excited, I don't want to go to sleep.
Then maybe this sleepover is the
thing you've been wanting to do.
Huh?
I don't think that's really quite it.
But I do want to do this again!
Oh, is it all right if I invite
someone else next time?
A dear friend of mine.
Of course.
What're they like?
They're not good at making friends.
But they're very kind...
Goodness me.
She fell asleep.
Right after she said she didn't want to.
Oh well.
We've still got plenty of summer left.
You're going home?
I gotta head back sometime.
His family's going to be worried.
But...
Don't be so down.
We should get plenty of rest today so we
can have lots of fun starting tomorrow.
You're right.
See you tomorrow.
"See you tomorrow," huh?
I wonder if Tsumugi and Shizuku and I
are going to be doing this all summer.
You're finally up!
The sun's already setting!
Seriously?
Leave your laundry out, please.
Huh?
Sorry, Tsumugi. I forgot...
Tsumugi?
Mugyu?
Takahara-san.
Why are you here?
More than that...
Is something wrong?
N-No, it's nothing.
But...
Hey, Takahara-san...
Would you like to stay the night again?
I mean...
It'd be one thing if Shizuku were here,
but I dunno about just the two of us.
So you can't?
Hey, the summer's still young.
We'll have plenty of chances.
I won't.
I don't have much time.
I have to go home soon.
Huh?
What did you just say?
B-But we can meet up again, right?
We can call or write letters
or whatever else...
We can't.
It's very far away.
Once I leave, we'll probably never meet again.
You mean when the summer's over...
Is that it?
I've been meaning to tell you.
I thought you might both stop
playing with me if I did.
But before I leave, I want to play
with you and Shizuku more.
So...
Sorry.
I can't stay tonight.
But...
I'll spend the rest of the time I have on you.
The rest of my summer break...
It's all yours, Tsumugi.
Hairi-san...