You're giving your summer break to Tsumugi?
It was kinda something
I went and decided on my own,
but it'd be nice if you'd join us, Shizuku.
Do you... not want to?
Shizuku?
Why...
Of course! Why would I say no?
You can have all the rest
of my time this summer.
I love you, Shizuku!
I love you too, Tsumugi!
Gyu!
Thanks, Shizuku.
No, thank you for the fantastic proposal.
Let's make the most of our summer.
Right, Tsumugi?
Hmm?
Tsumugi?
Mugyu...
And so our summer break began for real.
Paringles...
and a balcony!
I don't see where you're going with this.
Paringles?
You mean the cans you
found picking up garbage?
Yeah.
I've held on to them because I can't
decide what kind of garbage they are.
So I came up with the idea last night.
To build a balcony!
It's recycling.
We'll turn the empty
Paringles cans into a balcony.
Why a balcony?
Because I want one.
It might collapse under your weight, though.
It'll be fine!
Paringles are indestructible.
But I'm not sure if we have enough
to make a balcony.
Okay, I'll go collect them.
Let's have a strategy meeting.
I'll be right back!
A balcony of Paringles cans, huh?
She comes up with the craziest ideas.
Just what I'd expect from her.
I still can't believe it, though...
We won't get to see her anymore
once summer is over.
I just want to dedicate my time
to her while we can.
That's become my goal for the summer.
Have you fallen in love with her?
Huh?
You're head over heels.
Tsumugi's even started calling you
"Hairi-san" instead of "Takahara-san."
Wh-What are you talking about?
I-I just want Tsumugi to be happy.
You see, that's what we call love.
B-But...
I don't know how to process that.
Love never gives you time
to process it, Hairi-kun.
Is that really what this is?
Am I in love with Tsumugi?
Ts-Tsumugi?!
You're in l-love with me, Hairi-san?
Uh, u-um...
Are you all right?
You seem a little out of it.
Mugyu! Of course I am!
A man just said that
he loves me for the first time!
I'm embarrassed!
Mugyu!
I'll lend you my boobies if you get rejected.
You can have a good cry.
I'll pass.
It'll be all right.
I still have time.
Fried rice with sea urchin today!
Did you hear me, Hairi-san?
No...
No getting depressed.
I'll just be making things harder on Tsumugi.
Buck up, Takahara Hairi!
Good morning, Hairi-san.
Huh?
Mugyu!
Another day of great weather, isn't it?
My guess is she's pretending that
yesterday never happened.
Shall I lend you my boobs?
I'm good.
Mugyu!
Shaved Ice
Welcome!
Oh?
Hello.
Yo.
M-Mizuori-senpai!
Good day, Kanou-kun.
Yessum!
And a fine day to you, Senpai!
Oh, Shizuka's your senpai?
Ouch.
You dare call her by her first name?!
Who do you think you are?!
Relax, Tenzen.
You really didn't know, Takahara?
Mizuori-senpai is our school's
wildly popular student president.
Wait, for real?!
Hardly.
I'm just a pair of boobies.
I mean, see? She just said "boobies."
Huh?
What are you talking about?
Why would Mizuori-senpai
say anything so ridiculous?
Are you really so desperate for boobs?
All right, then!
How dare you expose yourself
before Mizuori-senpai?!
Do not undress!
Anyway, you're an odd cast of characters.
I've never seen Tsumugi with
anyone other than Mizuori-senpai.
Really?
Then again, Tsumugi is a rare sight herself.
Don't see her around the island much, either.
Tsumugi's always so spaced out.
I can't help but worry about her.
And to think she's hanging
around you, of all people...
What exactly happened?
Nothing...
Nothing at all.
Zilch.
What's got you so down?
Well, what brings you by today?
Oh, right.
Actually...
Lucky us. They're helping
us find Paringles cans.
Yeah.
And the cotton candy's as tasty as ever!
Have some, Hairi-san.
"Ahh!"
I, uh...
Here.
"Ahh!"
Ahh...
Here, Shizuku.
Ahh!
That's good.
It is.
My cheeks are going to fall off!
The summer break I dedicated to Tsumugi,
our summer spent looking for a purpose...
It went by just like that.
We collected empty
Paringles cans for the balcony
and looked around for anyone
who might know Tsumugi's song.
Mugyu...
Thanks, Kanou-kun!
Yessum!
You bless me with your gratitude!
Shaved Ice
That wasn't all we did, either.
Those joyous days...
Our very own
special summer break
flew by.
Hello, Watermelon Bar-san.
Oh, Cotton Candy-san.
Hello, Naruse-san.
Hi.
Here you go.
The usual gift.
Watermelon Bar
Thanks.
What?
I didn't think you two knew each other.
Watermelon Bar-san and I
got to know each other here.
Let's reenact the day we met.
Did you catch anything?
Huh?
Oh, um...
It's going so-so.
Is "so-so" the name of a fish?
No, it means I'm doing just okay.
I see.
Are you going to eat what you catch?
I am.
I see!
What do you like eating the most?
Watermelon bars.
What?! You can catch those?!
No, I can't.
They're at the snack store.
Of course.
I like cotton candy myself.
You don't say.
Now I want a watermelon bar...
Same. I want cotton candy.
And that's how we got to be friends.
I bring her watermelon bars sometimes.
I appreciate the watermelon bars.
Wow, they're actually communicating.
Looks like it.
Yup. We're besties now.
W-We aren't besties.
Mugyu?
Paringles?
I don't have any at home.
Okay...
Oh, but I'll bring you the cans
if we ever do have any.
Mugyu! Thank you!
Thanks, Shiroha.
I'm not doing it for you.
Well, yeah, I get that.
Excuse me!
Sorry, we're out of Paringles today.
Nah, that's not what we came for this time.
I'd like cotton candy, oh, uh, um...
Sorakado Ao!
So! Ra! Ka! Do! Ao!
You remember my name, don't you?
Um...
Guy who takes his clothes off!
That isn't a name!
Sorakado Ao!
I'm part of this now?!
I've got it!
Ao-san!
And it actually helped?!
Pon!
That's right.
Pairi-kun, a moment?
You want me to get Tsumugi a present?
No, no way. She already rejected me.
She won't even look at me.
It's best to be honest
with yourself in these situations.
Put your hands to your boobs and ask them.
Besides, we won't get to see her
after summer break.
So I think she should at least have
something to remember this summer by.
But getting her a gift here?
We have everything you can think of here.
Hi, Granny.
ORIGAMI
Stamps
Hairi-san, Shizuku, what
were you discussing earlier?
N-Nothing, really.
Mugyu...
That's suspicious.
Now, Tsumugi, what do you want to do next?
Right!
I want to go to Hairi-san's place.
My place?
Ao-san was saying earlier...
The quickest way to get close to someone
you're interested in is to see their room.
You can find their pervy books and stuff, too.
Apparently.
O-Oh, I don't know what Kyouko-san would
say about us all storming her place...
My!
Please come in.
Thank you for being so nice to Hairi-san.
Thank you for having us.
He's done a lot for us.
Poke, poke...
So, which one invited you
to the sleepover the other day?
The blonde girl.
The three of us stayed together, though.
You're two-timing?!
Oh no...
I need to tell my sister.
No! Please don't do that!
So this is your room, huh?
Mugyu...
I'm getting a little nervous.
It's not so much my room
as one I'm borrowing for the summer.
Goodness!
Noichigo 100%
You get it, don't you, Pairi-kun?
Mugyu?
No, my friend forced this on me!
Pairi-kun, would you mind
stepping outside for a moment?
We're ready!
What?
Mugyu...
It's so uncomfortable.
What do you think, Hairi-san?
Wh-What do you mean?
You stuffed it.
Mugyu!
Mugyu...
Goodness.
Do you have a moment?
I definitely need to call my sister.
I'm begging you, please not that!
There it is.
Here.
It's a nursery rhyme collection.
I heard Tsumugi-chan was
trying to find an old song.
I thought it might be useful.
Thank you, Kyouko-san!
Your song might be in here!
Do you think so?
I can't read it...
Looks like it's in German.
I can't make heads or tails of it...
May I have a look?
Isn't that...
Yes, it's the song I love!
We finally found it, Tsumugi!
Mugyu...
I have no idea what the words are.
Then why don't you just make up some lyrics?
Me?
Sounds fun!
Let's try that!
Okay!
It won't be easy, though.
Why not list off the things you like?
That'll make for a song unique to you.
Things I like, huh?
Mugyu-gyu...
Thank you so, so much.
Not at all.
I'm glad I could be of help.
Please come visit again.
We will.
Get home safe now.
Thank you.
Pairi-kun, sorry if you have
trouble sleeping tonight.
Huh? What're you talking about?
We couldn't find any good filler for
Tsumugi earlier, so we used your pillow.
My pillow...
touched Tsumugi's chest?
Get a grip, Takahara Hairi!
You got this, Tsumugi Wenders!
Huh?
Boobies!
Mizuori Shizuku!
Takahara Hairi!
Tsumugi Wenders!
Mizuori Shizuku!
Takahara Hairi!
Tsumugi Wenders!
Mizuori Shizuku!
Scary...
Hey, it's the girl with the song!
You guys...
Here!
I wish Shizuku could've come too.
Y-Yeah.
I have to get home early today.
You two have fun, okay?
Why did she think she
needed to give us space?
Hey...
Wanna come in?
Wow.
So this is the view you're always taking in?
Yes.
It's my favorite sight.
Um...
I'm finally ready.
Emotionally.
You're emotionally ready?
See, I love you too, Hairi-san.
What?
I thought I told you I loved you.
That it's not even hard to.
I thought you meant as a friend.
That is what I meant at the time.
But...
It's also meant something else.
Ever since you said you'd
give me your summer.
How could I resist loving you after that?
So I've been trying not to get too excited.
I wanted to act normal in front of you.
But I just can't.
My heart's still pounding now.
Tsumugi...
But I'm leaving soon.
So it doesn't mean anything
to say I love you.
I'm going to cry so much when we say goodbye.
I don't want that to be how we part ways.
Why do this?
Why?
Why would you say that?
Is it meaningless if we're saying goodbye?
Mugyu?
Even if we part ways...
Even if we won't see each other anymore...
I don't think that means
our feelings lose meaning.
No matter how painful it gets,
it doesn't change the fact that I love you.
You're the one who reminded me of that.
I did?
Yeah.
So let me say it properly.
I love you, Tsumugi.
Hairi-san...
Me too.
I love you, Hairi-san.
I'm home, Kyouko-san.
Welcome home.
You look happy, Hairi-kun.
D-Do I?
Let me help.
Oh, sorry.
Tsumugi?
That day, Tsumugi vanished from our sight.