What's up with her?
This is unusual.
Tsumugi isn't normally gone for so long.
Do you think something happened?
Is she in trouble?
Nah, no way. That can't be it.
Maybe she got embarrassed
now that you're officially dating, Pairi-kun.
What?!
I love you, Hairi-san.
But I told her I loved her too!
Oh...
I knew it.
Sorry.
I was going to tell you
when all of us were here.
I'm really happy for you two.
You'd better make her happy, okay?
Of course.
Kind of a shame, though.
Now I'll have to share her boobies
with you once they grow.
Huh?
I-I mean, Tsumugi's boobs belong to her.
Not to anyone else.
M-Maybe Tsumugi just slept in.
Fine. Let's go get her.
She said she lives at the lighthouse.
But where does she really live?
Huh?
I have no idea.
Well, I've always met her
and parted ways with her here.
She always sees me off from here too.
Hairi-kun?
O-Oh, it's nothing.
Excuse us!
Yes, what is it?
I wanted to ask something.
Oh, good timing.
Here.
What you asked for.
It came in surprisingly quick.
Must be the power of love!
Maybe she was spirited away.
Spirited away, you say?
It was decades ago now...
There was a real uproar about it.
A blonde girl up and vanished.
A blonde girl?
The whole island helped
her parents look for her,
but she never turned up.
One boy kept searching desperately
for her, just like you are now.
I think he was the lighthouse keeper.
The lighthouse keeper...
Is there anyone else who knew
the girl that got spirited away?
Nope.
Not anymore.
Katou-san was the last one who knew her,
and she passed away just recently.
That sure was a shock to hear.
The spirited away business.
Pairi-kun?
Could you take a look at this?
Tsumugi?
But this is...
Hang on.
It can't be, could it?
This is such an old photo.
Say something, Hairi-kun!
I don't know.
But I can't stop thinking about it.
I've seen this somewhere.
Look. See?
I've seen this before.
Someone powerful used to live here.
No one lives there anymore.
Is this Tsumugi's house?
Pardon us!
Maybe no one's here.
Hey, Tsumugi!
Looks like a girl's room.
Hairi-kun! Look!
Tsumugi Wenders
Tsumugi...
I started school on the island today.
Everyone whispers about
the color of my hair and eyes.
So my only friends are my stuffed animals.
Stuffed animals?
Were those...
No one talked to me again today.
I think they're afraid of me.
They must think I'm something like a namahage.
So I'm going to work up
the courage to talk to them.
Like a namahage!
Bring me the crying children!
Bring me the naughty children!
Bring me the disobedient children!
It didn't work.
I've made a friend.
Her name is Katou-san.
She's interested in stuffed animals.
That makes me happy!
Good for you, Tsumugi.
Sounds like she made lots of friends, got
used to the island, and lived here happily.
Tsumugi was going to elope
with the lighthouse keeper...
What?!
I've decided to leave the island with him.
We're meeting at the lighthouse.
Father, Mother, I'm sorry.
And to everyone on the island, thank you.
I love you all.
Could it be you're jealous?
I am.
You're true to yourself, huh?
S-Still, this is all stuff that
happened decades ago.
But eloping...
I wonder if that's what really became of her.
No, it wasn't that.
Remember what the
granny at the candy store said?
The lighthouse keeper was looking
for the missing girl too.
What, so she was actually spirited away then?
No way...
Was our Tsumugi also...
There's more to this journal.
Tsumugi-chan is missing.
Tsumugi-chan won't come home.
Everyone went to look for her.
But they couldn't find her.
What is this?
I'm so sad for Tsumugi-chan.
Please don't forget Tsumugi-chan, everyone.
That's my hope.
So I'll make sure no one forgets Tsumugi-chan.
I have to make it sure of it.
This is...
I'm scared.
Shizuku...
The more we look for her,
the more we look into this...
The more I feel like
we'll never see her again.
Sorry, can I leave you here?
Hairi-kun?
There's somewhere I need to go.
You're all waiting for her too, huh?
Same goes for me.
All I can do is sit here and wait
for Tsumugi to come back.
So...
Tsumugi...
Huh? Wh-What?!
Where am I?
This isn't Tsumugi's...
What in the world?
Wh-What is this place?
It won't open.
Shit!
How?!
I was going up just now, right?
What is going on?
Who's there?
Um...
Tsumugi!
Where have you been?
We were worried about you!
I've been here the whole time.
Here?
But I've been looking for you all this time.
You are... Tsumugi, aren't you?
Indeed. I am most certainly Tsumugi Wenders.
Bring me the crying children!
Bring me the naughty children!
Bring me the disobedient children!
H-How do you know about my
embarrassing introduction?
You're joking...
I've been spirited away too?
I wanna go home!
I seriously wanna go home!
Is this really going to get me home?
It seemed to do the trick for everyone else.
I've never returned, so I wouldn't
know if it works or not myself.
Unfortunately, anyone held here
by something is stuck here.
And for so long that we don't
even know what holds us.
What holds you?
So you're stuck too?
Do I look that much like her?
Like your, er...
Tsumugi-san?
Yeah, you're shockingly identical.
Her personality is totally different, though.
She's more lively and more committed
once she puts her mind to something.
So you kinda have to keep an eye on her.
Is that so?
I hope you get back to her soon.
I understand well how you feel, Takahara-san.
I've long been separated from
my lover and my dear friends.
You mean the man you wanted to elope with?
I couldn't choose that day.
I grew scared.
I'd decided that, in order
to live with the man I love,
I would abandon my parents
and the people of the island.
But I ended up hesitating,
and I couldn't make up my mind.
Then, before I knew it, I was here.
I must still be hesitating.
Tsumugi-san...
But you came here in search
of someone you long for, yes?
I'm sure that if you think
strong thoughts of her,
you'll be able to return to your world.
Strong thoughts...
Please believe strongly in her.
In your lover.
That's right.
No matter who she is,
no matter her past...
I don't care.
Right now, I simply miss her.
I want to see her smile.
I want to hear her song.
That song...
That takes me back.
A breeze...
There might be an exit, Tsumugi-san!
I'm still hesitating.
If I go, the exit will surely vanish.
You'll have to go alone, Takahara-san.
But...
Please take good care of Tsumugi-san.
Yeah.
Thanks.
What are you doing up there?
I'm looking for something!
What are you looking for?
Myself!
Tsumugi...
When you said you were looking
for yourself, did you mean...
This is...
Paringles are indestructible,
right...
Tsumugi?
Hairi-kun! Hairi-kun! Hairi-kun!
Hairi-kun!
God!
Where were you?!
Shizuku...
First Tsumugi disappears...
If you disappeared too...
What would I do?!
Sorry.
Where's Tsumugi?!
Hairi!
Thank goodness!
Thank goodness, Hairi-san!
Tsumugi...
The day after we parted ways...
I was waiting at the lighthouse
in case Tsumugi came back.
Shizuku, hey...
Tsumugi! Tsumugi! Tsumugi!
But right as Tsumugi came back,
you vanished next.
I was so worried.
Sorry.
I'm so glad.
Tsumugi...
Tsumugi.
D-Don't.
You're going to get my
tears and snot on you.
I don't care.
I want to stay like this
for a little longer, then.
Sheesh, you two...
Both of you...
I was gone a whole day?
You were.
Where exactly where you?
Where?
Well...
I don't remember.
Mugyu?
What gives?
It's the truth.
I don't remember anything.
Mugyu?
Not much we can do
if you don't remember.
Welcome home.
Um...
I'm terribly sorry.
I'm sorry.
You had me all sorts of worried,
but I'm just glad you're all right.
So...
Where's Umi-chan?
She worried herself to sleep.
Go apologize to her in the morning.
Okay.
Tsumugi-chan, it's late now.
Why don't you stay the night?
Mugyu...
Hairi-san.
May I come in?
Yeah.
Come in.
Could we talk for a bit?
You know how I said I'm leaving?
It's not that I'm going home
or abroad or anything.
Um...
Well...
Mugyu...
Listen, Tsumugi.
I don't mind whether you
tell me about that or not.
I've made up my mind.
I'm going to spend my time
with you until the very end.
Whether you tell me anything
or you don't, I'll be with you.
Hairi-san...
I want to be with you forever.
Stay with me until the end.
Yeah.
There's something I have to tell you too.
I met Tsumugi Wenders-san.
I don't remember where I was,
but that part, I remember.
I get the sense that I have to remember.
Did Tsumugi-chan seem well?
Yeah.
She did seem well.
She did, huh?
That's good.
Hey...
When you said you were
looking for yourself...
Did you mean her?
Yes.
That's Tsumugi-chan.
Are you going back to her
at the end of the summer?
I think so.
Now that you've found her for me,
I think I can return to her.
Good thing too, since she must be lonely.
That's a problem.
I'll be lonely too.
Mugyu...
P-Please don't be so selfish!
I'm going to miss you too.
I won't know what to do if you say that.
Oh, right.
For you.
Shizuku told me that
a gift is the best way to express
yourself to someone you love.
Shizuku always knows best!
May I put it on?
Of course.
What do you think?
It looks good.
I can tell what it means to you.
One week remained until August 31st.
Our summer was about to end.