Mugyu-gyu...
I thought you'd both vanished again.
I read through Tsumugi-san's diary.
I kinda figured things out.
What Tsumugi's purpose is.
What this girl means when
she says she's "going back."
I see.
Well, whatever the case, to us,
Tsumugi's just Tsumugi.
No matter what happens,
we'll be with her to the very end.
That's all that matters.
You're right.
Shizuku, I came up with a stupid idea.
Good morning, Hairi-san.
Mugyu?
You're here too, Shizuku?
Morning, Tsumugi.
Good morning.
Happy New Year, Tsumugi.
Today's actually January 1st.
Mugyu?
I had this idea just earlier.
What if we squeeze a whole
year's worth of big events,
New Year's, cherry blossoms, and all,
into the week we have before August 31st?
A whole year's worth?
No, make it a lifetime's worth!
That's fantastic!
We can do Halloween and Christmas
and everything all at once.
That's too silly!
Each event has its own customs specifically
for the season and that time of year.
Well, it can be disrespectful
to do things too late,
but there's no harm doing things early.
I don't know, though...
Tsumugi.
I'm not suggesting this just for you.
Mugyu?
He's right.
I want to get in as much fun as we can.
Decades' worth.
Shizuku...
What about you?
What do you want to do?
I...
I want to play lots and lots
with you and Shizuku!
Forever and ever.
I want to be with you forever!
Shaved Ice
A lifetime's worth of events?
You're asking me?
Why should I?
Watermelon Bar
You can count on us!
W-We'd be happy to!
In that case, I'd be delighted.
Thanks.
We owe you.
This should be fun.
Yeah.
Oh, and for the last day, August 31st,
I'm thinking we should have a birthday party.
That sounds nice.
Let's make it a big celebration.
I was thinking... maybe we
can have a surprise of some sort.
A surprise, huh?
This time, I have an idea.
And so, that was how the
final week of our summer began.
We made it such a busy summer.
It almost felt wrong
to waste any time breathing.
Takahara Hairi
-Tsumugi Wenders
We made sure that summer break
was the best we'd ever remember.
Merry Christmas!
So...
I have a Christmas present
for the two of you.
Spare keys to this place.
Now you two can come in if you ever
want to hang out when I'm not home.
Thanks.
You're pretty forward though, Tsumugi.
Giving your boyfriend a spare key and all.
Mugyu!
I-I didn't really...
I did mean it like that, actually.
I have a gift for you too, Tsumugi.
Here.
Thank you so much!
It's a swimsuit.
You can't be serious.
L-Listen!
I thought her boobies might react somehow
now that she's in a relationship
with you, Pairi-kun.
There's no way they're getting
bigger than yours, Shizuku.
That's true.
That much, I'm sure of.
Come on.
I meant it in the hopes
that they'll grow bigger.
Tsumugi...
I don't wanna!
I don't want to go back!
I still...
I still want to go to the beach!
I want to wear a yukata to a festival.
I want to have a snow fight.
There's so much I still want to do.
I want to be with you two forever and forever!
It's okay, Tsumugi.
It's all right.
B-But...
When tomorrow comes, I...
We're going to have fun together
until the end, aren't we?
So we have to stay smiling.
Right, Pairi-kun?
Huh?
Right.
Of course.
We're going to be by your side.
Hairi-san...
So no more crying, okay?
Why, though?
Why are you both so nice?
Why else?
Because I love you.
Same.
I love you too.
M-Me too.
Shizuka, Hairi-san... I love you two.
And so we came to August 31st,
the last day of summer break.
Well, I'll be going now.
I have lots to prepare.
Spend some quality time with Pairi-kun.
Mugyu...
I want to spend more time with you, Shizuku.
Don't be so down.
We had plenty of fun.
I had a really great time, Hairi-kun.
Shizuku...
Thanks.
I love you, Tsumugi.
I love you too, Shizuku.
No tears.
Promise?
Okay.
Tsumugi?
Tsumugi!
Hairi-san?
Is something wrong?
Tsumugi...
Could you tell me you love me?
Mugyu!
I want to remember your voice.
I want to remember yours too.
I love you, Tsumugi.
I love you, Hairi-san.
Looks like it's about time.
Is something about to happen?
Who knows?
I can't wait.
Mugyu.
You're being mean, Hairi-san.
This is amazing.
Today is your birthday.
So we have to celebrate.
With a lifetime's worth
of birthday cake candles.
It's my birthday?
But how did you even find all these candles?
The youth group people.
They helped?
They were all on board with
Shizuku's idea to make you happy.
They made these using empty Paringles cans.
Paringles really are the best!
They're all such good people.
Yeah.
You couldn't ask for better friends.
Hairi-san, may I talk about the past?
Sure.
Tsumugi-chan is my friend.
That song I've been humming
is one she used to sing when
she was at her house beyond the sea.
She didn't have many friends here,
so she never sang it much.
Her only friends were her stuffed animals.
But one day, she befriended
a girl named Katou-san.
She was so happy telling me about her.
Then she fell in love, and she decided
to leave the island with him.
But...
Tsumugi-chan vanished.
Father, Mother, I'm sorry.
And to everyone on the island, thank you.
I love you all.
Still, I'm sure she'll be back.
So I decided to take her place until then,
in hopes that no one would forget her.
I tried searching for Tsumugi-chan,
asking if anyone knew me.
But fewer and fewer people
were left who remembered her.
Then one day, Katou-san came.
Tsumugi.
She told me to do
what I wanted from then on.
What you wanted?
The thing is, I didn't know
what I wanted to do.
Which is why I decided to make friends
for when Tsumugi-chan found her way back.
Before I left this place.
And one day, I met someone.
She complimented the stuffed animals.
That simple occasion led me
to have a new friend named Shizuku.
Then I met you.
I fell in love.
Not for Tsumugi-chan.
I fell in love for my own sake.
I've made lots of friends.
I've come to know happiness.
Now there's so much I want to do!
I can't wait to see what happens next.
It'll probably snow when winter arrives.
And it'll be a real ordeal!
The snow will jam the door shut,
and I'll miraculously make it out
thanks to you and Shizuku.
You'll save my life!
You're exaggerating.
In the summer, we'll swim at the beach.
We'll wear yukatas and go to a festival.
Sometimes we'll get in fights,
but we'll make up right away.
And I'll tell you how glad I am
that the three of us are together.
Yeah.
I can't wait.
Today was fun too.
Yeah.
And tomorrow and the next day
and every day after will be.
Yeah.
I have Shizuku and Shiroha-san too.
Then there's Ao-san and Nomura-san
and Mitani-san and Kanou-san.
Every day's gonna be so much fun.
So...
Please don't cry.
Sorry.
It's just...
You won't be there.
Hairi-san, I'm happy.
I got to meet everyone.
I got to meet Shizuku.
I got to meet you.
Yeah.
I'm happy too.
So we have to have fun, okay?
Yeah.
It was such a beautiful summer break.
I sing in search of me
Mu-mugyugyugyugyu, mu-mugyugyugyugyu,
mugyugyumugyugyugyu
I sing at the lighthouse
so that I can be found
Mu-mugyugyugyugyu, mu-mugyugyugyugyu,
mugyugyumugyugyugyu
Looking for materials, the strong bird does
Mu-mugyugyugyugyu, mu-mugyugyugyugyu,
mugyugyumugyugyugyu
The bird, the cow, and I play in the water
Mu-mugyugyugyugyu, mu-mugyugyugyugyu,
mugyugyumugyugyugyu
The bird and the cow and I
are together this summer
Mu-mugyugyugyugyu, mu-mugyugyugyugyu,
mugyugyumugyugyugyu
The bird and I hold hands; we are lovers
Mu-mugyugyugyugyu, mu-mugyugyugyugyu,
mugyugyumugyugyugyu
My beloved bird, my beloved cow
Mu-mugyugyugyugyu, mu-mugyugyugyugyu,
mugyugyumugyugyugyu
The sky-blue ribbon is my treasure
Mu-mugyugyugyugyu, mu-mugyugyugyugyu,
mugyugyumugyugyugyu
I won't forget this summer,
this lighthouse, this island
Mu-mugyugyugyugyu, mu-mugyugyugyugyu,
mugyugyumugyugyugyu
Tsumugi.
Happy birthday.
It's been a good summer break.
I've been thinking...
Tsumugi was summer break itself.
Yeah.
You meet someone for the first
time somewhere unfamiliar
and become friends.
It feels like you have all
the time in the world.
But in the end, you grieve
when your time is up.
You regret having to say goodbye.
She was my summer.
Yeah.
Mine too.
Anyway...
That song!
What are you singing?
The cat lady who does the radio
calisthenics sometimes was singing it.
We made friends!
Yeah?
Then hopefully you'll see her next year too.
Yeah!
Next year, huh?
Yeah.
That's right.
Summer break will come again.
Cotton Candy-san.
See you again, Tsumugi.
Goodbye.
See you next time.
We're back.
Welcome back!