Please go slow at first!
I awaken abruptly.
There's a field as far as the eye can see.
Next to my shadow,
a silhouette not mine wavers.
That's right...
I came here to play.
My shadow holds hands with the silhouette.
We walk out into the vast field.
Once more...
Hello?
Wake up!
Come on.
Hello!
You're finally up.
You need to start waking
up on your own, Hairi-san.
Morning, Umi-chan.
Hurry up.
The food's gonna get cold.
Has Umi-chan always talked like that?
Wait, I just met her yesterday.
What am I even saying?
I've already been
on the island three days, huh?
It is seriously boring here.
Let's eat.
It's not good...
I don't recognize him.
Then he must be Shocking Taka,
the host who lost his charm!
What?!
I heard that's your professional name.
From who?!
From Grandma Kido!
Who's the host who's lost his charm?
The lady from the ferry!
Takahara Hairi-kun.
Takahara Hairi-kun, who's been on
the island since the day before yesterday,
please come to the office.
Huh? Me?
She's calling you, Shocking Taka.
What have you gotten into, Shocking Taka?
You shouldn't make her wait, Shocking Taka.
Could you please stop calling me that?
A welcome party?
For me?
We call long-time visitors
to the island migratory folks.
A tradition of welcoming people like you.
So, yeah, just let us do this for you.
Torishirojima is kind to its guests.
Shut up and get dressed.
Hey, is it all right if I bring
a plus one to this welcoming party?
Not a problem.
Everyone on the island is basically family.
Excuse me?
Why would I go?
You can go by yourself.
Oh, don't say that.
Let's get to know the islanders better.
Reserved
Welcome to Torishirojima!
Welcome to Torishirojima Island!
Greetings.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Sorakado Ao.
Wait, it's you!
Wait, what? You know each other already?
He nearly had his way with
me while I was asleep!
Oh?
Nice going.
No, I definitely didn't.
But you grabbed me!
Oh?
Not bad.
Well, things might have gotten
pretty aggressive in the end.
You should have taken it slower!
Oh?
Nice!
No, it wasn't like that!
You're in perfect sync.
You're like a mixed doubles team
that's been playing together for years.
Who's she?
A relative of mine.
We're staying at the same place.
I'm Katou Umi.
I brought this for everyone.
Fried rice, huh?
You're so polite.
I can't wait to see how you grow up.
What's up?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
I'm stuffed.
Here. Water.
Thanks, Sorakado.
Call me Ao.
They're a fun, lively bunch.
We've been hanging out since we were little.
We also serve as the island's youth group.
There was nothing like that back home.
I'm a little jealous.
You can be part of the youth
group while you're on the island.
You're plenty qualified if you're
related to Grandma Katou.
Yeah?
That sounds nice.
Where's Shiroha?
Huh?
How do you know Shiroha?
Well...
Stuff happened.
We did invite her, but...
I'll go if I can make it.
Yeah, she's definitely not coming.
She's so shy.
Don't go messing with her.
You. Look at me.
You didn't need to walk me home.
Don't be silly. What if you were to get lost?
Pretty caring, are we?
I wouldn't want that for Umi-chan.
Yeah... You're right.
Once I put Umi-chan to bed,
I'll walk you home next.
I certainly won't need that.
I grew up on this island.
No way would I get lost.
I mean, you're a girl. You can't
be walking around alone at night.
Thanks.
But there's nowhere safer than this island.
Is it safe, though?
It is indeed.
It's sweet...
She definitely mistook the sugar for salt.
Hang on, this might be her magnum opus.
It could be a revolution for fried rice.
Or not!
Dad, could you hand me the soy sauce?
Wuh?
I didn't mean to call you that.
It happens.
Like when you call your teacher "mom."
Y-Yeah, like that.
It happens, right?
Don't worry about it yet.
Another day, and I'm still
not cleaning out the shed...
This is only a hundred yen?
Strawberry, melon, lemon, blue Hawaii...
They all taste the same, though.
Really?!
Come enjoy it in the living room over here.
There's a fan there. It's nice and cool.
I guess I'll take you up on that.
Listen... I go to an all-boys school.
I'm not used to seeing
girls in so little clothing.
This could be a sign, though.
Maybe you could help me build up a tolerance?
Wh-Wh-What do you mean by that?!
Are you asking me to undress?
You want me just barely covered
to entice your desires?!
Getting my clothes wet on purpose,
licking it off lustfully,
getting on top of me when I fall...
I'm not entirely uninterested
in boys myself, but...
Oh boy, we've got a problem.
Sounds like she isn't totally
opposed to the idea.
By the way...
Yes?!
Could I get some shaved ice?
I wasted mine and I'm still thirsty.
How could you throw it on me there?!
No, no aiming for that!
You little...
Hey!
Scary...
I never got my shaved ice.
That was kinda fun, though.
I feel like I got to let loose and be crazy.
Smells like first love.
Shaved Ice
The shaved ice here is great.
Pon!
Don't you have anything better to do?
Kyouko-san won't let me help with the shed.
Besides, I've got nowhere else to go.
Professor!
Give us an appraisal!
You get the kids to call you "professor"?
Huh?
Well, I happen to be pretty knowledgeable.
They started calling me that
since I was teaching them stuff.
Wait... What are you giving me
that sad look for?!
Hey, it's fine.
Everyone needs to feel
superior once in a while.
Shocking Taka!
Have you gotten your charm back yet?
You don't need to be a host your whole
life, you know, Shocking Taka.
You got this, Shocking Taka.
How far has that nickname spread?!
It's okay.
Everyone wishes they were
someone else once in a while.
That's not it!
Shocking Taka! I challenge
you to a appraisal-off!
Can you at least stop calling me that?
You'll have to beat us first!
I suppose, since I'm older, it falls on me
to teach you how harsh the world can be.
And I'll be sure to give fair appraisals!
I don't want any of you kids sobbing, got it?
Shocking Taka
Romio
Shigeo
Takumi
Later, Professor!
You gotta get your charm back, Shocking Taka!
Get home safe!
Okay!
What?
I just realized you're a nice guy.
Bringing me weird stuff
on purpose so you'd lose...
That was kind of cool of you.
Right...
Wait, were you actually trying?
D-Damn it!
Can I get one of these?
Oh, welcome.
Hey, it's Hairi.
This one.
That'll be 200,000 yen.
Here.
You're still short 199,980 yen.
Put it on my tab.
Why's everyone here?
You guys up to something?
Yeah. We were discussing the
festival that's coming up.
Ah, there's a festival, huh?
The island has both a sea festival
and a mountain festival.
The sea festival attracts tourists.
You should check it out if you're
going to be here for the summer.
What about the mountain one?
That's more of a custom than a festival.
So anyway, Hairi, have you
ever been to Starpucks?
Yeah, a few times.
They're selling Mango Mix
Frappuccinos right now.
W-We're working here!
Take your sexy talk elsewhere!
I've had a feeling, but...
Is Ao a perv?
Yeah, she's a perv.
I... I... I'm not a perv!
She's just a closeted one.
I'm not closeted!
Pon!
Damn it! Why can't I win?!
Is this all you've got in you, Tenzen?!
Looks like that's game.
Guess I'll head home.
I'm out too.
I should go patrol the island.
You seem to have made
yourself at home lately.
Oh, yeah, it's just kinda comfy here.
I see.
We're counting on you
to take care of Ao, then.
Take care of her? How?
Work's done.
Inari, let's go home.
You look sleepy as hell. You all right?
Hairi.
I'm fine.
See you.
So this is what "taking care of her" was about.
Ao, you awake?
Shuf uf...
What does that mean?
Yikes!
There's nothing skeevy
about this, all right?!
How pretty.
What?
I said, "How pretty."
Mind if I touch?
I-I've never done this before...
Just be gentle.
Okay, here goes.
Wow.
It really is pretty.
This glass bead.
It's not just a glass bead.
It's called a tonbodama.
Wait, you were talking about that?!
Hands off!
But you said I could touch it.
Sh-Shut up!
Just keep your hands off it!
Got it.
Anyway, I'm walking you home. Let's go.
You really look sleepy.
Are you staying up at night?
My duties are starting.
Your duties?!
Can you tell me more?!
It's not a secret or anything.
My family's in charge of the mountain
custom I mentioned earlier.
Does that make you part of some priestess
family that protects the island?!
What all do you do?!
I don't know what you're expecting,
but I don't have special powers
like in a manga or anything.
I just wander around the mountain
at night with a lantern.
I'm disappointed.
That's such a letdown.
You got your own hopes up!
You don't get to be disappointed!
So, does your whole family do this stuff?
Just me.
No one else on the island is allowed
on the mountain during the ritual.
Is that safe?
No one would know
if something happened to you.
It's fine.
Like I said, there's nowhere
safer than this island.
I mean, I guess it's fine if you say so.
Hairi...
Have you fallen in love with me or something?
No, not one bit.
Just say you have, even if you don't mean it!
Okay, I have.
R-Really?
No. You told me to say it even
if I didn't mean it, so I did.
You're totally messing with me!
Can I get one of these?
Welcome.
Oh, hello.
Is Ao off work today?
She must be at Ai-chan's
place today for a checkup.
Ai-chan?
Ao's still not here.
Gotcha!
It got away.
What's that?
Don't tell me...
My duties are starting.
Could that be Ao?
I thought it was around here somewhere.
There she is!
A butterfly?
It's glowing.
Come.
Who's there?!
Oh, er...
Me.
Hairi?
Why are you here?
What's up with that butterfly?
You can see the Shichieichou?