Ao-chan...
You can see the Shichieichou?
She never really told me what was going on.
What was that butterfly?
What do you think?
It's not good.
How dare you?!
Sorry, I didn't mean to say that out loud.
That doesn't make me feel any better!
Shaved Ice
Ao-chan should be here around noon.
Have something cold while you wait for her.
Thank you.
That was the last one.
Hang on!
Are you curious about Ao?
Huh? Wh-Why do you ask?
You seem to be hanging around a lot lately.
What do the Sorakado family's duties involve?
Dunno.
It's an island thing, though.
We aren't supposed to go up onto
the mountain during the ritual.
Ao mentioned something about that.
A long time ago, there were three families
here they called the Three Houses.
The Sorakado family, the Naruse family,
and I don't remember the third one.
But the Sorakado family's been
performing their duties all this time.
Hang on.
Did you just say Naruse?
Isn't that your family?
It was a long time ago.
We don't do anything anymore.
Sorakado of the skies, Naruse of the seas,
something-something of the mountains...
Huh.
It's not often that I see you
hanging out with anyone, Shiroha.
Hey, about last night...
What do you mean?
I went to bed early last night.
You must have been hallucinating.
Hallucinating?
True, you did look rather
beautiful and divine last night.
B-Beautiful and divine?
I-If you think I'll buy
that flattery, y-you're wrong.
So it was you after all.
I mean, that's what I would say if was!
Could you at least put
a little effort into the lie?
I can't even pretend to be fooled.
I-I-I'm not lying!
It's true!
Honestly, it's really true!
A-A-Anyway, don't go up on the
mountain at night anymore.
Respect this island's customs, will you?
That yawn just now says it all.
At least now I know why
you're so sleep-deprived.
Crap, I'm gonna run out of battery.
Wanna lie on my lap?
Thanks, just for a bit, then.
Seriously?
Hey—
Let's bounce, Tenzen.
Didn't you want unmaibo?
Bros know when to give each other some space.
Later, bud. Have a good time!
Tenzen, dash!
Sir!
Thanks for the treat.
Huh?
Wh-What?
You shouldn't go near the mountain at night.
You should probably listen to what Ao says.
She really does fall asleep anywhere.
This could get ugly.
What's going on?!
Her face is so close!
Everything's so soft!
And something smells nice!
Um, this isn't...
Do enjoy yourselves.
Morning.
Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-What is this?!
What gives?!
I-I wanted my first to be a girl!
Calm down.
I-I don't mind it rough,
but we're outside right now!
Calm down, I said!
You're really holding me tight right now...
Let me go!
You let me go!
U-Um, I'm sorry, I guess.
No, it's fine.
Were you up late with your
duties again last night?
Something like that.
Same tonight?
I will reiterate. You cannot
enter the mountain at night.
I'm telling you for your own good, you know?
Or so she said, but here I am.
Ao?
Oh, hey. Ao was touching this butterfly.
How could this have happened?
Give her back...
Give me back my wife!
My daughter!
Why did I survive?
Relieve me of this suffering.
I'm coming.
I'll be with you soon.
My body's moving on its own.
What's happening?
But now I can...
I can finally be free.
Hairi!
You idiot!
I told you not to come
to the mountain at night!
Ao?
Was I...
Someone else's memories entered your
mind because you touched the Shichieichou.
What are the Shichieichou anyway?
Residual memories of those
with unfinished business.
Touching one makes you relive their memories.
These butterflies are normally only visible
to animals and emotionally sensitive people.
Ao...
What exactly are your duties?
I gather wandering Shichieichou and
guide them back to where they belong.
That is the job of the Sorakados.
You can make it back
on your own from here.
Are you not leaving yet?
I have to continue my work.
Now you know how treacherous
the mountain can be at night.
Don't come near it anymore.
Hang on a second!
What?
Those Shichi-whatsits...
You touched them too.
Do they not affect you?
I've been touching them for a long time.
I've built up a tolerance.
Is that part of your duties?
There's a memory I have to find.
Is that really worth endangering yourself?
Hey, do you have some time tomorrow?
Sorakado Ai
This is it.
It's Ao.
I'm coming in.
Excuse me.
I'm here, Ai.
Ai?
Yeah.
Sorakado Ai.
She's my elder twin sister.
She must be at Ai-chan's
place today for a checkup.
I brought a friend with me today.
I told you about him
the other day, remember?
Y'know, the late Grandma Katou's relative.
Ai was in a bit of an accident.
She's been asleep ever since.
Uh...
I told you yesterday that there's
a memory I need to find.
It's Ai's memory.
Grandma Katou told me an old
story about a strange butterfly
that woke up someone
who'd been asleep for a long time.
My grandma told you that?
She might've made it up
to make me feel better.
But when I think about the Sorakado family
duties and about the Shichieichou,
it's hard for me to dismiss it.
Which is why I touch the Shichieichou
as I'm doing my job.
I'm looking for Ai's memories.
Are you sleepy?
Sorry, is it all right if I take a nap?
Yeah, sure.
Wake me up in half an hour or so.
Hey. Good evening.
Heya, Inari.
Pon!
Didn't I tell you not
to come near the mountain?
You did.
But I never said I wouldn't.
Why can't you get it through your skull?
Looking for Shichieichou is super dangerous!
That's exactly why.
If you're putting yourself in danger,
I at least want to be nearby.
I...
Ah, I see. I get it.
Have you fallen in love with me?
I guess so.
More than a little, I think.
Uh... A-Are you serious?
Does that bother you?
M-More than a little.
I'm kind of shocked, to be honest.
I mean, I don't have the capacity
for that kind of thing right now.
I'm too preoccupied looking
for Ai's Shichieichou.
Yeah.
But then, all the better to have
someone with you, right?
The islanders won't come to the mountain
because of the custom and all.
But I'm not an islander.
So I can help you out.
A-All right, fine.
I don't think I could stop
you if I tried anyway.
But you have to promise
me you'll stay by my side.
Got it.
I'll never leave your side.
And so, Ao, Inari, and I began
searching for Ai's Shichieichou.
Kinky
Nude
Gravure
Mayoi Tachibana is the Sorakado
family's sacred tree.
Tachibana trees normally
flower before summer.
But this one's always a bit late.
It's slightly offset from the real world.
Slightly out of sync.
It was deemed sacred because it sits on the
border between this world and the next.
I can only guide the Shichieichou with
my lantern while the tree is in bloom.
So that's the window for your work.
Yeah.
And then Nomiki turned beet red
and totally clammed up.
Say, what's the goal in talking
to her while she's asleep like that?
Sleep-learning, kinda, I guess?
I figure maybe if she remembers
what I said when she wakes up,
it'll be like we were
hanging out the whole time.
Oh, I know!
Why don't you try talking to her too?
I guess I should. Let me introduce myself.
I'm Ao's...
b-boyfriend, Takahara Hairi!
H-H-How are you my boyfriend?!
Not so fast!
I thought I'd get her on
board for when she wakes up.
I mean, I do appreciate you saying that...
I've properly fallen for you too.
Ao...
But I'm sorry.
I can't find happiness for myself
while Ai's still asleep.
I know this is selfish, but I hope
you can wait until Ai wakes up.
Yikes.
Sorry.
Finding Ai's memory isn't
just a favor anymore.
Huh?
We can date once she wakes up, right?
So that's my goal.
I-Is that how it works?
Yeah.
Now I'm really motivated.
Hey, Kyouko-san, could I ask you a question?
How can I help?
I heard there's an old island story
about a butterfly that can wake people up.
The Shichieichou?
You're kidding! There's a book?
Apparently.
I asked Kyouko-san to dig it out of the shed.
Of course!
You mean Grandma Katou's shed.
That makes sense.
Wanna come over tomorrow?
Yeah, I'll be there!
All right, I'm feeling pumped for tonight!
Yeah! Let's do this!
Pon!
I'm sleepy...
Looks like you're spent for the night.
I'm not done yet.
Onward, Inari.
Wanna hold hands on our way down?
That doesn't sound like a bad idea.
What? Really?
Huh? Did I say something?
Just how you really feel, I think.
N-N-No way!
We're outside!
That's going too far!
I need our first time to be
somewhere with a pillow.
Sorry, I think that was more
than just slipping out.
You're obviously past your limit, though.
Let's go home.
O-Okay.
Demon Lord Grudge Death Beam Dragon Wave!
Huh? Demon Lord... Dragon Wave?
What are you doing?
Umi-chan.
I kept trying to wake you up.
Breakfast is all gone now.
Sorry.
I don't know why I couldn't wake up.
Because you keep going out at night.
A Shichieichou?
Hairi-kun.
Yes?
You have a guest.
U-Um...
Thanks for having me over.
Why are you so tense?
I've never been in a boy's room before.
Plus, you already had a futon ready...
Hang on.
Kyouko-san and Umi-chan are here.
What did you think I was doing?
Huh? R-Right, of course!
Anyway, here.
Twelve Stories of the Divine Mountain
Kyouko-san found the book.
It's so old, I couldn't make any sense of it.
It's from the Tenpo era.
You can read it?
You know how you relive people's memories
when you touch their Shichieichou?
You can learn all kinds of things that way.
That's kind of amazing.
Didn't I tell you?
I'm pretty knowledgeable.
No way!
It says how to return a
Shichieichou to a sleeping body!
Really?
This is what I've been
looking for all this time!
Yes!
A-Ao! You're touching me
with all sorts of parts...
S-Sorry.
I got a bit too excited.
Yeah. I'm thrilled too, so it's all good.
So, how does it work?
Well...
We find Ai's Shichieichou, and at the Ro...
The Ro?
A-Anyway, we have to find Ai's Shichieichou.
That'll solve everything.
True enough.
Thank you, Hairi.