Burn it...
Burn the tome with the cover swapped
for that of a reference book...
Slippery Sister-Bound MILF Condo Complex.
Such intense regret.
Having your parents find that
would be like dying twice over.
That one wasn't Ai's memory!
So this is how you ended
up becoming a know-it-all.
D-Don't call me a know-it-all!
Let's go find the next Shichieichou, Inari!
Pon!
Pon?
Well, that saves us having to look for one.
Ao?
Pon!
No...
This memory...
It's of death!
I know she wants to find Ai's memories,
but she's really pushing it.
Pon!
I still think we'll find Ai
faster if we search together.
Pon...
This memory...
I can feel my chest tightening.
Is it sadness?
I knew I had no business
feeling the way I did,
but I couldn't stop my emotions.
So we made a decision.
We were going to run away together.
But she never came...
It wasn't that she didn't come.
She couldn't come.
I was sure of it.
And so I left for the war,
still believing that was the case.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't keep waiting for you.
I had to go and die before you.
I miss you.
I wanted to see you one last time.
I miss you...
Hairi?
Sorry...
The butterfly...
Stupid.
I told you not to touch them.
Thanks.
Let's take them back.
To where they belong.
With our hands.
Pon!
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I just hope the man that memory belongs to
is reunited with who he was waiting for.
Yeah.
The flowers...
The flowers are starting to fall.
Which means we're running out of time.
I'll have to wait another year before
I can gather more Shichieichou again...
I'm going to find it this summer.
Just watch me.
Don't worry.
You have me this year.
Yeah.
Pon!
It's pretty late. I'm really getting sleepy.
That drowsiness is from the Shichieichou.
When you touch a Shichieichou
and witness someone else's memories...
When you take that in, they're
effectively your memories now.
We organize our memories when we sleep,
which is why we need so much.
Is that why you're dozing off all the time?
I guess.
Then you must be in a bad way too.
I'm used to it!
I've been doing this a long time.
I've gotten good at organizing memories.
I get that you're doing this for Ai,
but don't you think it's a bit reckless?
Well...
Ai ended up the way she is because of me.
Ai was smart.
Not to mention athletic.
Any time we competed, I'd fall behind.
She was even good with her hands.
Mom taught us how to make these.
She said they ward off evil spirits.
She wanted us to wear them when we grew up
and had to inherit the Sorakado duties.
We made them together,
but mine never turned out nice.
It was so upsetting.
I got jealous of her and cried.
When Ai gave me this,
she asked to have the one I made.
So the one around her wrist...
Yup.
A bit misshapen, isn't it?
She said she appreciated it anyway
because it was something I made.
Ai really was amazing.
And I wanted her to tell me I was too.
One day, I spotted an unusual butterfly.
A pretty one with a faint glow.
It was my first time seeing a Shichieichou.
Wow...
It's true!
I saw one! I swear!
A glowing butterfly, huh?
Are you sure it wasn't just the sun on it?
I'm not lying!
I really saw one!
You believe me, right, Ai?
No one would believe me.
So I was desperate to find a glowing
butterfly and impress everyone.
I figured it'd be easier
to see the glow at night.
Ao-chan?
Ai?
Ao-chan!
Let's go home.
I still haven't found a glowing butterfly.
But the mountain's dangerous at night.
No, it's not!
You made it up here by yourself too.
I'll be fine.
Then let's go toge—
No!
There's no point if I'm with you!
You don't even believe in the butterfly!
You think I'm a liar!
Ao-chan...
Ao-chan!
I shouldn't have said that.
I've never seen Ai make a face like that.
Ai...
Sorry, Ai.
Forgive me.
I'm sorry.
Ao!
Thank goodness!
Dad?
Mom?
Hey, what about Ai?
Where is she?
They found her at the bottom
of a cliff that night.
They immediately took her
to the clinic for treatment,
but she was critically injured.
She never woke up.
Apparently, she was clutching
this in her hand.
I said something awful to her that night.
I hurt her.
I never got a chance to apologize to her.
I have to wake Ai up, no matter what.
Ao, I still want to be of help to you.
Fallen for me?
Yeah. I'm in love with you.
You know that.
I'm not afraid of falling asleep these days.
I can be myself now that you're with me.
What I feel for you is what keeps me myself.
Ao...
So, uh...
Are you going to be okay?
O-Oh, yeah, I'm fine.
Especially since you were so gentle.
No, I mean with your family.
You were out all night.
N-Never mind!
We're good!
That's my job!
Yup, yup! All good!
You really are a perv, Ao.
I-I-I'm a perfectly healthy girl!
I have dirty thoughts once in a while!
Th-That kiss s-sure was intense, though...
I-I mean, it was a ro...
I needed you to be my first.
So when you said "have a ro,"
you meant a deep, romantic kiss.
Shiroha.
I assume you had a fine night.
I-I-It's nothing like that!
Ao.
Y-Yes?
I'm happy for you.
I apologize for the early announcement.
Sorakado Ao-san, please contact
the clinic immediately.
I repeat. Ao, contact the clinic!
Doctor, how is Ai?
Out of the woods for now.
I'd like to discuss what happened
and our options going forward.
With the family, if you don't mind.
Staff Only
Hairi!
Takahara!
Did Ai...
I mean, is she okay?
The doctor said she pulled through.
Okay.
That's a relief.
You guys grew up with Ai too, right?
Yeah.
We used to hang out as kids.
Ai was always worried about Ao.
She saw herself as the big sister,
even though they're twins.
She cared about Ao.
Takahara, I know this is selfish,
but please take care of Ao.
H-Hey...
There's no telling what may happen from here.
Ao is counting on you.
So please...
Raise your head.
You don't have to plead with me for that.
But...
I'm sticking by Ao because I want to.
Thank you.
I'm home.
Sounds like you had a rough day.
Nah.
Nothing compared
to what Ao's going through.
Hairi-san, are you all right?
Huh?
What...?
I'm suddenly sleepy...
Where am I?
Takahara-san, you suck!
Relieve me of this suffering.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't keep waiting for you.
Good morning.
Give me back my wife! My daughter!
I lost my life.
I don't want to grow up!
I can finally be free.
I wanted to see you one last time.
What the hell was that dream?
Wait, it's night?
How long was I out for?
Huh?
She isn't...
Ao!
Where are you?!
Pon!
Inari?
Ao!
Hey!
Are you all right?
How many memories did you go through?
Ao, are you all right?
Mom...
I miss you...
Ao?
It's dark...
It's dark here...
I'm scared.
Cold... So cold...
I'd rather kill you than belong to someone.
I hope she gets my letter.
I can't wait for a reply.
Ao!
My cheek...
Ouch.
Um...
How did...
Oh, right.
I have to hurry and find Ai's memory.
Hey!
Sit down! You can't even walk straight!
I don't have time!
I'm going to lose Ai!
The doctor said we should
prepare for the worst.
I don't have another year!
It's too risky!
When am I supposed to take risks if not now?!
I won't even have anything
to risk without Ai!
I get it, but...
At least take a break. Please.
I'll wake you up.
You promise you'll wake me up?
Yeah.
I will.
Okay.
Just for a bit, then...
Thanks...
Hey, Ai...
Look at how hard Ao's trying.
You care about her, don't you?
Please come out.
Inari?
What's wrong?
No way.
She can't touch the Shichieichou now.
Pon!
Damn it!
Stay away!
Pon!
What's this?
Did you protect her?
It's morning?
Wh-Why?!
You said you'd wake me up!
It's okay.
It's not okay!
What if something happens to Ai?!
Ai's right here.
See?
Here.
Where?
I don't see her.
Oh...
I guess I can't see her.
No wonder I couldn't find her.
I had my eyes closed to her.
For how much I tell myself
I want to help her,
I'm afraid of what she really thinks.
I've only been thinking about myself.
I'm so low.
That's not true!
You put yourself through the wringer
with reckless abandon, all for her.
You've done so much!
Don't say you're low.
You've done admirably.
Hairi...
But I can't see Ai!
Then I'll help you see her.
You'll help me?
How?
You think I'm a liar!
Ao-chan!
It's my fault.
I should have believed in the glowing
butterfly Ao-chan said she saw.
Ao-chan would never lie.
She hates that kind of thing.
I need to find a glowing butterfly.
I can find one for her.
That way, no one'll think she's lying anymore.
I can't be happy when Ao-chan isn't.
I can't smile when Ao-chan can't.
I'm Ao-chan's big sister.
I can keep going because
Ao-chan says I'm amazing.
I still need to find a butterfly.
I still need to make up with Ao-chan.
Ao-chan...
Ai...
Ai was always thinking of me.
Your sister truly was amazing.
Yeah.
I'm so proud of her.
What's wrong?
I see it.
Ai...
That's you, isn't it?
Let's go home, Ai.
Now then...
Are you gonna do it?
Obviously.
Ai, wake up.
Is Ai going to wake up now?
I think her memories are back, at least.
Now...
I'll keep an eye on Ai.
Take a nap.
I'll do that.
I promise I'll wake you up this time.
Ai...
Good night.