That tickles...
Ao-chan.
Ai?!
Ao-chan...
You're seriously hurting me.
Ai!
I can't breathe, Ao-chan.
Ai! Ai!
There's so much I want to tell you.
I've wanted to apologize
to you all this time.
But...
Thank you.
For believing in me.
All this time.
Thank you.
No.
You're the one who's done so much for me.
I heard your voice the whole time.
You kept me together.
I'm back because of you.
Thank you, Ao-chan.
Takahara Hairi-san, correct?
You know me?
Ao-chan's been telling me
about you all along.
Thank you for supporting her.
I was just doing the right thing.
But I don't approve of you dating.
Ao-chan is my darling, precious sister.
I can't let her date someone
unworthy of her.
I guess I can't go against what Ai says.
You know, though, Ai...
Hairi's a really good guy.
Even I fell for him.
Yes, I know.
So I won't stop you.
Now that I'm relieved, I'm getting sleepy.
Sorry, Hairi, I'm going
to nap a little longer...
Yeah, all right.
Me too.
Ai, let's talk lots when we wake up.
Yeah.
Lots.
Good night, Ai.
Good night, Ao-chan.
Hairi, wake me up again.
Ai waking up was big news on the island.
The doctors were shocked.
They said it was a miracle.
But I knew it was more than that.
Ai...
You really did wake up.
Do you recognize me?
Yeah.
Miki-chan, right?
Ai, what about me?
Sure.
Been a while, Tenzen-chan.
A swing and a miss!
I simply made a stronger impression on her.
To be honest, I just remember
that there were two boys around.
I've never cared who was who.
We were friends as kids, weren't we?
Right?
You're Ao-chan's goofy minions.
Not even her pals?!
She's actually awake.
Shiroha-chan...
It's been so long.
It has.
See you around.
Wait, that's it?
I mean...
There're so many people here.
Just pretend the men are
frog-shaped paperweights.
Ouch!
Ao's asleep, huh?
Yeah.
Can't believe she's sleeping in
at a time like this.
Yeah.
I can't wait for her to wake up.
And so we continued to banter
in the sisters' hospital room.
We waited for Ao to wake up...
but she never did that day.
All the way out here?
That's unusual.
You should wait longer after you knock.
That's just impolite.
Uh, sorry.
Were you hoping to catch a peek or something?
Er...
I'm not sure why,
but I can't help resenting you.
I'm sure it's nothing.
Anyway, how's Ao?
As cute as ever.
I know that.
I mean...
I see.
It's been two whole days.
For her to stay asleep for so long...
This hasn't happened since
I met her, at least.
The doctor says the cause is
unknown, just as it was for me.
But it has to be the Shichieichou, doesn't it?
Ao told you?
Yes.
As I slept.
Apparently, you need sleep in
order to organize your memories.
Maybe she just hasn't been able
to catch up on organizing.
This is my fault.
Don't say that.
It'd be denying all the work she put in.
Sorry.
Ao's going to wake up.
You can just thank her when she does.
That'll be enough to make it up to her.
Hairi-san...
Come back to us soon, please.
We promised we'd date for real
once we found Ai's memories, remember?
What?
We're having a moment here. Shush.
Apologies.
I just heard something
I'm having trouble accepting.
Given that Ao-chan is your type
and I'm her twin sister,
are you perhaps in love with me as well?
What makes you think that?
Well, you see...
I'd be open to it if it's with Ao-chan.
You'd have two beautiful women.
That's not a nice joke.
I'm hardly joking.
I'd like to be faithful to Ao-chan,
for now, at least.
Then I'd like to be faithful to her as well.
Well, we're going to need her
to wake up before anything else.
You're right.
Pon!
A tanuki?
No, a fox.
It's been helping us look for
the Shichieichou all this while.
Its name is Inari.
I've heard the name before.
I thought it might be missing Ao.
Don't tell the doctors, though.
You can't wake her up either, huh?
Ao-chan is talking in her
sleep more often, though.
She is?
She was mumbling your name.
Mine?
Man, she's seeing me even in her dreams, huh?
What did she mean by "we can't outside"?
She's just dreaming.
And what was she so "thrilled" about?
It's a dream.
And what does she want to "do again"?
She's dreaming!
Ao-chan's been tainted!
Hang on! If anything, she was the one who...
Moop.
Hairi-san, if you wouldn't mind,
could you please talk to her?
Talk to her? I don't know... About what?
Anything to convince her that the
real world is more fun than her dreams.
All right.
Well, I don't know about fun, but...
You see, I used to swim.
And I got tapped to compete in the
relay as soon as I hit high school.
Not bad, right?
But during a meet that summer...
Thank you for talking to Ao.
Nah, it was a nice chance for me too.
I don't know if that did any good, though.
I'm sure she's happy to learn more about you.
I've been so touched by Ao's
straightforward tenacity.
She has a strength that I don't.
I think that's what attracted me to her.
Yes.
I'm proud of her.
Hairi...
Ao?
Together forever...
She's dreaming, isn't she?
Coffee at sunrise...
Yeah, let's try it.
Excuse me?
So just skip all the good stuff.
I tried the service myself.
I guess even I can do it.
Pon.
That's another one.
I don't even need to touch them like Ao.
Pon!
The flowers have nearly all fallen.
Guess that means the mountain
ritual's almost over.
No...
It isn't just the end of the festival.
Summer break's about to end too.
Once summer is over, I have to go home.
You'll wake up by then, right, Ao?
Yes?
Ao!
Did I sleep too much?
Ao-chan?
Sorry, Ai.
You finally woke up, and now
I've been asleep for so long.
It's okay.
I got to hear your voice.
I'm all good now.
I'll go get the doctor.
Wait.
I want a breath of fresh air first.
Oh.
Shall I open the window?
No, I mean I want to go for a walk.
So...
Carry me.
I remember everything you did for me.
Where's this coming from?
I can't move around very well yet,
but I'll do my best.
I'll do the same things you do.
All right.
That's something to look forward to.
I don't mind going outside,
but not for long.
You've been asleep for so long.
Don't push it.
Please do this for her, if only for a bit.
While she can still stay awake.
Huh? What are you talking about?
What are they doing here?
Wait, Ao...
Are these...
I've touched so many memories.
My head's kind of a mess.
I can hear people's voices all the time.
It's hard to hold on to myself.
Ao...
No...
I have to take these little ones
home while I can stay awake.
You're the only one I can ask.
No...
Never mind that.
We have to do something for you!
Hairi-san.
Please.
Please grant her wish.
We just have to go to the
Mayoi Tachibana, right?
Maybe we can take a few
detours along the way.
Detours?
So then...
Ao?
I-I'm okay.
But I might need you to hurry a little.
Pon!
Ao, it's Inari.
Inari.
I had you worried too, huh?
Thanks for helping me so much.
Inari, can you take us
to the Mayoi Tachibana?
Pon!
I think it was around here that I saw
you doing the ritual the first time.
I told you not to come in here, and...
you wouldn't listen to me at all.
But I had fun this summer.
We hung out every day,
did stupid stuff, got reckless...
and you always stuck
around when I dozed off.
Thanks.
You know, I have to go home
after summer break.
But I'll get a job and come back
here on the weekends.
Fall, winter, spring...
I'll spend them with you on the island.
And we can hang out all
summer again next year.
That makes me so happy.
But I'll be...
Even if you're still asleep,
I'll be here on this island.
Hairi.
It'll be my duty to wake you up.
Go slow at first.
I'll always be gentle.
That might get a bit stale, though.
We're here, Ao.
The Mayoi Tachibana.
Ao?
So many...
Since when?
H-Hey!
What are you—
What is...
Are these all the memories she can't get
through in her sleep flowing out of her?
In that case, maybe if all the Shicheichou
keep leaving her, Ao will wake up.
Inari?
Ao!
Wake up!
You still have your memories
inside you, don't you?
Ao!
Don't tell me...
Is she among them?
You can't be serious!
Wait up!
Ao!
He attacked me in my sleep.
But he was worried? About me?
What a weirdo.
He saw me undressing
and he threw shaved ice on me!
What the hell?!
I kinda had fun, but...
Look at him, getting so worked up
over a bunch of kids. What a brat.
But you really did intend to lose, didn't you?
At least I know you're not a bad guy.
H-He said I'm pretty!
And he asked if he could touch me...
He meant my tonbodama?!
My heart was racing!
I can't believe I heard that!
What do I do?
He said he's in love with me!
How do I feel?
Er, um...
I don't know yet.
We're embracing!
He's so warm!
And strong!
My heart's pounding!
Thank goodness!
Hairi's safe.
I'm so relieved...
No fair.
How can I say no to that?
Crap, this is bad.
I'm getting tickled about this.
I'm so happy.
This is bliss.
I feel safe with Hairi here.
I love him.
We just kissed.
I want to be with Hairi.
Even after the summer.
I want to be with him forever.
Hairi... Hairi...
I'm sorry.
I'll always love you.
Ao...
Were those your memories?
You thought of me that much?
This isn't goodbye.
Don't apologize.
You're just going to sleep, aren't you?
Let's go home, Ao.
Ao-chan...
Give me a year.
The Mayoi Tachibana will bloom again.
And then I'll find Ao during
the mountain ritual.
You're thinking the same thing, aren't you?
I'll just be doing what Ao-chan did.
I'm simply returning the favor.
Okay. You're gonna have
to work hard on your PT.
Hairi-san, I'd like to ask you a favor.
Please continue to come visit Ao-chan.
Tell her what you see,
what you hear, what you experience.
Fill in the gaps for her while she's asleep.
I'd prefer to give her back
the time she gave me.
But I can't walk too well yet.
No worries.
I was talking to Ao about it.
I'll head home once summer break is over,
but I'll find a part-time job, save
up money, and spend my weekends here.
I'll spend the fall, winter, and
spring here on this island with her.
Then we'll spend the next
summer together again.
Hairi-san...
Besides, there's something I've
promised her even before that.
It's always my job to wake her up.
Don't worry.
I'm sure he'll find you.
I'll be...
Yeah.
I'm okay still.
Well, wanna get started?
I heard a voice all the while.
A voice that kept me at ease.
A voice I loved.
A voice that brought a smile out of me.
A gentle light swaying my heart.
It was the tiniest bit smothering...
Warmth is filling my body.
I know what I would say first.
What I've been saying all this time.
What I've been wanting to say all along.
Good morning.