Let's eat!
Yum!
More, please!
I-I'll boil some more. Just a sec.
She's sound asleep.
And with a happy stomach to boot.
A-Are you two siblings?
No, n-not exactly.
Oh.
You seem kind of alike.
Well, we are related.
Anyway, this sure was a surprise.
Are you his girlfriend?
Not my girlfriend.
Not his girlfriend.
I never expected you to drop by.
I just came to thank you
for walking me home yesterday.
I didn't think I'd end up making lunch.
Sorry, I just wanted Umi-chan
to get to try your cooking too.
I apologize for that.
It's fine.
This was fun.
I haven't been anywhere
so lively in a long time.
Hey...
Okay, I'm leaving.
Bad things will happen if you're with me.
Because you're some kind
of special priestess for the island?
Is that why you're trying
to keep everyone away?
Well then, goodbye.
Wait.
Listen, um...
Wanna hang out tomorrow?
Special Move: Bukeshohatto!
My powerful play was finally too much for it.
What's this dude on about?
Either way, what'll we do about this?
Well, there's plenty to do
other than table tennis.
Right, Shiroha?
Well, if you'll excuse me...
Hey, hang on!
You came all this way!
Not a problem.
I've already begged Tokuda
and pulled some strings for a new table.
Tokuda?
The son of the island's
sports store owner.
However, there's just one problem.
What's that?
I have no money.
Which is why we have to make
some as fast as we can.
Say, what do you get paid, Ao?
Grandma's pickles.
They've been fermenting for 200 years.
They're the best around!
In-kind payment, huh?
Nomiki, your water guns
are custom jobs, aren't they?
They're worth a fair bit, yeah?
They're extremely dangerous.
How could I sell them?
And you've been shooting
us with them all this time?
Um...
Eek!
They have food stalls at the port.
Selling yakisoba and stuff.
I thought maybe we could try doing that.
That sounds good!
Shiroha's cooking will sell for sure.
Sounds fun!
Think of it like a school festival.
Except there won't be nearly
as much competition.
We can borrow a cart from the town hall.
There are plenty of ingredients
across the island too.
But...
We'll be counting on you as our chef, Shiroha.
You mind?
I-I'll do my best.
Paella
Torishirojima-style paella!
It's our grand opening!
Line Up Here
Paella's hard to come by on the island!
The line starts here!
Here you are.
Great, thanks.
Thank you very much.
Welcome.
I'd like three.
That'll be 1,500 yen.
We might run out of rice.
Got it.
What's the meaning of this?
What do you want me to say?
I'll give you the table.
But I don't want your money.
Not if Naruse Shiroha's involved.
Tokuda...
Are you in love with Shiroha?
It's not that.
The Naruses are the reason we're
able to do business on the island.
So we refuse to take their money.
That's our rule.
Welcome to our secret base!
By the way, about the money
we ended up not using...
I think Shiroha should get it.
Agreed!
I mean, Shiroha basically earned
the cash and the table herself.
I don't need it.
I won't ever use it.
True.
Not on this island, anyway.
Why not go to the main island, then?
Yeah!
You might find something you want there.
The main island...
I don't go there by myself.
In that case, take Takahara.
It's a date.
I'll kindly pass.
Huh? Tomorrow?
Do you have time?
Oh, yeah.
Then I'd like to treat you tomorrow.
Treat me?
I'd like to buy you a meal.
Oh, th-then let's meet up at the diner.
'Tis the port, sir.
The port?
Thencewhen please and thank thee, sir lad.
Her formalities were falling
apart there at the end.
Thanks for waiting.
H-Hey.
H-Heya.
Er... Thanks for this.
It's fine.
Just returning the favor.
F-For inviting me along.
Huh?
You invited me today, though.
Ah, I mean in general.
I appreciate the gesture.
It's nothing.
Well, should we get going?
Yeah.
Thanks.
So, what are you going to treat me to today?
Oh, there's a shop in a
magazine I was curious about.
Exquisite Western Cuisine
Wow.
You did your research, huh?
Their lunches are supposed to be good.
Oh, this?
It's a limited edition model.
I got it for winning a meet.
A meet?
Er, well, y'know...
You never wear it on the island, though.
You never really think about
the time on the island.
I only ever wear it when I get serious.
Get serious...?
Wait, hang on, hang on!
When I said that, I just meant...
Yes.
I doth understand...
Dear Customers,
Closing Notice
We are closing as of May 30th.
We thank you deeply for your patronage
all this time, and we wish you happiness
and prosperity going forward.
-Owner
I should have checked.
Don't worry about it.
This is plenty good.
H-How embarrassing.
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing.
You can board that train
and get off at the fifth stop.
Then there's a limited express train
that takes you to my place.
What's it like there?
Normal?
It's a slow, boring city.
But it's not bad.
There are some fun places.
I see.
Show me around if we ever have time.
That might be kind of difficult.
I see...
I go to an all-boys school.
They'd never let me hear the end
of it if they caught me with a girl.
We should head back.
Where?
Where? To the island, of course.
I still haven't figured out
how to spend the summer.
Ah.
Hairi.
Um, thanks for to—
Natsutori Ritual
The Natsutori ritual?
"Our ancestors' souls inhabit lanterns
sent out to sea by a priestess."
"A traditional Torishirojima custom."
Huh.
Are you part of this—
Get away.
Leave the island. Now.
What's with you all of a sudden?
This isn't sudden.
I've said it all along.
But hey, like I said, I still haven't
figured out how to spend the summer.
You never will.
Thanks for today.
Goodbye.
Shiroha?
Welcome ho—
What's wrong?
Did you have a fight with Onee-chan?
I wish that's all it was.
Welcome home.
A letter came for you.
1853-7 Torishirojima-cho,
Aohama-shi, Kagawa
Takahara Hairi-sama
701-65 Minamimatsuhara,
Tohno-shi, Okayama
Minamimatsuhara High Swim Team
Are you going home?
I'm not leaving.
I'm headed out for a bit.
Hairi-kun, you look different
than when you arrived.
Maybe because I got a tan.
You really like to run off on me,
don't you, Shiroha?
Not that I have room to talk
after fleeing to this island.
You were fleeing?
I was just another guy on the
swim team at a public high school.
But some of my classmates
were really good.
The upperclassmen supported me, too.
They made me the star of the team
and said I should aim to win.
But I couldn't even finish.
No one held it against me.
I was so grateful I could cry.
I was dead set on winning after that.
But I failed.
In the end, I was out of place
at school, at home, and in town.
So I fled to this island.
But they're all such good people.
Even after everything I screwed up,
they've made a place for me to return.
Oh. In that case...
I'm not going.
I can figure out how to spend
the summer if I'm with you.
That's what I figure.
Hairi...
No.
I can't be with you.
Shiroha?
Someone told me they like me.
A long time ago.
A boy on the island.
I didn't know him well,
so I turned him down.
But he kept approaching me.
I didn't know what to do.
One day, I saw it...
It wasn't a dream.
All I can really say is that I saw it...
Him falling from a cliff and drowning.
Shiroha's going to curse and kill us.
It was so vividly real.
I thought it might actually happen.
I got scared, so I chased him down.
And then...
It really did happen.
I have this weird power.
I have since I was little.
I can see the future.
And it's always bad.
Precognition?
Or...
I'm the one determining the future.
I didn't know what to do the other day.
I thought you should just get lost.
Hang on.
Slow down a little.
Then I saw it again...
I'm going to die this summer.
What did you just say?
I've seen it.
A dark sky.
Lots of red lights.
The raging sea.
And I get dragged into it.
At the Natsutori ritual.
The Natsutori ritual?
That poster at the port.
Yeah.
I'm going to be the priestess.
Is it really such a dangerous a role?
No.
I mean, I'm not going into the sea at night.
But that's what I saw.
I was there with someone.
Me?
That's why you're avoiding me
and trying to get me off the island.
I wasn't certain, but I saw the
future more clearly that afternoon.
The other person is wearing a watch.
I don't mind dying.
How could you say that?
But I don't want to take anyone with me.
Not you or anybody else.
So why do you keep seeking me out?
Shiroha...
I believe you.
I don't get it, but I'm not brushing it off.
I believe it because it's you saying it.
Okay.
Thank you.
In that case...
So let's work through this together.
If the future you saw
is really waiting for you,
we'll do everything we can to avoid it.
There's nothing we can do.
I couldn't save that boy.
But he didn't die.
Maybe you stopped the worst
outcome by warning him.
But...
Do you really believe you're okay with dying?
Of course. That's why you were trying
so hard to learn to swim.
W-Well...
Let me help you.
Let's do everything we can.
H-Hairi...
Thanks.
I know Shiroha's isolating
herself over a silly rumor.
It's a small island.
Rumors are never forgotten.
But if Shiroha contributes to the island,
no one will care about that anymore.
Is that why you're putting her up to being
the priestess of the Natsutori ritual?
I'm not calling it off for some vague reason
like "something bad is going to happen."
But...
That's all I have to say.
In that case...
If you won't let her out of it,
at least let me stay with her
during the festivities.
I'll protect her.
Hairi...
Kid, why's a stranger like you
so invested in Shiroha?
She's a friend.
Also, I think...
No, never mind.
In that case, prove to me
that you're prepared.