Underwater combat honors
the god of the sea.
In times of great need, the men of this island
have long proven their resolve in the water.
If you are truly prepared,
you'll have to prove it, son!
Let's do everything we can.
Is that all you've got, son?!
Not again...
I can't.
This is it for you!
You've never even seen
what she's like when she's alone!
Hairi! You got this!
Shiroha!
What?
He threw him out!
He won!
Hairi won!
Ten years ago, Shiroha
lost both of her parents.
She's been closed off ever since.
Never made many friends.
Had terrible rumors spread about her too.
She's been forced to spend her summers alone.
Take good care of her.
Grandpa...
I will.
I'll be by her side during
the Natsudori ritual.
I'll protect her.
That ought to dispel the silly rumors.
Hairi...
About that...
The priestess in the Natsudori ritual
may only be accompanied by family.
Family...?
N-N-N-N-No way. That can't be right.
Hairi and me... m-m-m-m-married?
Naturally, it would be entirely symbolic.
I owe Shiroha.
You do?
So if she's going to be in danger,
I want to be by her side to help.
If...
If it isn't a bother...
I'd appreciate it.
Please be my spouse.
Wow!
You two are getting married?!
It's just an act.
You're going to be busy
with the butterfly covenant and such,
so don't worry about the shed.
Break a leg.
Thank you.
Marriage!
We'll be lighting them and sending them
off to sea the day of the festival.
Don't forget to bring them.
Of course.
The red lights Shiroha says
she saw were these lanterns.
Hey, Ao...
Yeah?
Is she okay?
Oh, that's Hotta-chan.
Her mother fell ill, and last winter...
Hotta-chan.
Do you know what Obon is?
I don't.
It's the one time of year
the dead come back.
The dead come back?!
Sorry.
I didn't mean you can see them.
Anyway, they return on the night
of the Natsudori ritual.
It's scary to go out in the dark, right?
Yeah.
That's why we have to light
the way for them with these lanterns.
So they feel safe on their way.
Okay.
You have a dress rehearsal today, don't you?
Yeah.
Shiroha should be there by now.
Hmm...
According to her vision,
you two are drowning, aren't you?
Could it be because you're
in those kimonos in the water?
I can see that.
What?
About the kimono...
How do I get it off of you?
Why would you ask that?
I don't know if I'll be able to
when the time comes.
What time?
H-Have you lost your mind?
Th-The covenant isn't like that.
You're gonna have to lose it
if you fall in the water.
Not even a kappa could swim in that thing.
I see.
But don't you mean a hippo (kaba)?
S-Sorry.
I was just trying to make
a little wordplay joke...
Either way, you're right.
I can't swim in this.
Right?
Ryoichi and Tenzen pointed it out to me,
so I figured I should consider it.
I'll consider it too, then.
Hairi...
Thanks.
For thinking about me.
For everything.
Tomorrow's the big day.
Katou residence.
Hi, Nomiki.
Shiroha did?!
Why would she do that?
Isn't the priestess supposed
to cloister herself in the hall?
I don't know.
But Ao's pretending to be her for now.
Ryoichi and Tenzen are looking for Shiroha.
Got it.
I'll look for her too.
I have an idea where she might be.
Everyone's worried about you.
You could've at least told someone.
Sorry.
I just really wanted to come here.
The closer we get to the Natsudori ritual,
the more vivid it gets.
I can see your face clearly now.
Why did you talk to me?
Then you took me places...
I should have been alone.
I don't mind going away.
But I can't stand the thought of losing
someone I care about again.
I'm still glad I met you.
You being here saved me.
So please don't talk like that.
I'm sure everyone feels the same.
None of us could stand losing you.
Sorry.
About what?
I don't know, but...
Sorry.
We should get back.
Wait.
It's almost time.
I want you to see it.
See what?
Fireflies.
Sea fireflies.
Sea fireflies...
Fireflies in the sea?
This is a secret place my father
showed me a long time ago.
They haven't glowed since.
But they're glowing again this summer.
It's been ten years.
Ten years?
I must be lucky.
You know...
There was a time I wanted
to go into the future.
Into the future?
I guess I got tired of waiting.
I wanted to speed up time
and see them again.
Maybe that's why I wanted to go.
Do you still want to?
There's no telling how long it'd take.
So I'm good now.
I see.
Welcome back.
Thanks.
Welcome to Torishirojima Island
Thanks for visiting Torishirojima
SAUSAGES
GRILLED SQUID
YAKISOBA
Say hi to your wife for me.
I will.
See you.
I've gotten so used to this path.
Was that...
a rainbow-colored butterfly?
Umi-chan?
Onii-chan.
What are you doing here?
I was chasing a butterfly.
And what are you doing here?
Just taking a little walk.
I see.
Well...
Shall we go back?
That's okay.
I wanna walk around a little more.
What were you doing?!
It's about to start!
Sorry.
I ran into someone I know.
Just hurry.
You have to finish the butterfly covenant
or we can't start the Natsudori ritual.
Got it.
We hereby begin the butterfly covenant.
Heave ho!
We carried that boat last year too,
but I swear it's getting heavier.
It must get heavier
the more wishes it carries.
Yo.
Looks like nothing happened.
Good for you, huh?
Rain?
Lucky break we finished
before it started, huh?
Too bad we won't get to see
the lanterns off,
but we should head back.
Yeah.
Hairi!
Have you seen Hotta-chan?
No, I haven't.
We can't find her anywhere.
Nomiki's calling for her on the PA.
Catch her if you find her.
Hairi...
The future I saw...
With you and me in the water, yeah?
But everything's already...
I just saw it clearly!
The other person I thought I saw...
It was a little girl!
Was it Hotta-chan?
But why's she in the sea?
The boat!
She's on the boat!
We have to bring her back!
But how?!
Hey! Over here!
Where are you, Hotta-chan?
Dad's gonna smack me later
for taking the boat without telling him.
You'd better be safe!
Hey! Over there!
On it!
Hotta-chan!
Onii-san!
Thank goodness.
I thought I could see my mom!
I thought this boat would take me to her!
I'm sorry!
Give me your hand!
Over here!
Hairi!
Shiroha!
Ryoichi, take Hotta!
Hairi...
I got you!
Shiroha?
No... that's not her.
We are the weavers of time.
Seek as you may, stranger,
it will be futile.
Even if you meet this summer,
that is all it will be.
We shall simply continue to weave.
Where are you?
Which way do I go?
Is that....
This way.
Hey.
Thank you for all you did.
Nah.
We both did a good job.
There's something
I've been wanting to tell you.
The first time I laid eyes on you...
Hairi...
I knew you were swimming
in your underwear.
Sorry I never said anything.
Why would you tell me now?!
I mean, there was so much
going on. I was overwhelmed.
I have no idea what to say right now.
A-A-A-A-And that's what you chose?!
You're right.
I'm such a dosukoi.
I've been thinking...
The future is as dark as that sea was.
Normally, there's no way
to see what's ahead.
But you cast a ray of light.
I think that's your real power.
Isn't that awesome?
What's wrong, Shiroha?
N-N-Nothing.
Nothing at all.
Just something I saw.
What did you see?
Was it something ominous again?
It's nothing.
It wasn't ominous at all.
What's wrong?
I just remembered.
Remembered what?
How to spend summer break.
How did I ever forget?
It's such a simple, basic thing.
I remembered that I love summer.
Hai—
We will be departing soon.
To all passengers, please complete boarding.
There's two things
I want to say before I go.
Now what?
Hey...
It was brief, but I had fun.
I had fun too.
Also, I...
I've fallen in love with you.
Shiroha?
What?!
Me too!
I've fallen in love with you too!
I'll come back to this island—
Due to technical difficulties,
we will be turning back.
Why are you coming back?!
I'm back.
I know.
Next time for sure.
Next time?
What do I mean?
What am I...?