Get up.
No sleeping on the job.
Hey, it's Hitomi.
Dozing off again, Kyouko?
Huh? Was I sleeping?
You were out cold.
It's getting hard to tell
whether I'm awake or asleep.
Whether I'm a butterfly or a person...
Say what?
Never heard of that? It's from a legend.
Nope, nor do I care about
your bookworm trivia.
Sheesh.
You're so rude, Hitomi.
So, what brings you here?
Oh, I wanted to ask you for a favor.
You're going to meet a girl someday.
A girl? Someday?
That's pretty vague.
You'll know who I'm talking
about as soon as you meet her.
Okay. Got it.
I'll meet a girl,
and I'll know when I see her.
Um...
Welcome.
Let's see... What's your name?
Umi.
Umi-chan it is.
Well, come on in.
And one more thing.
You'll likely meet a boy too.
I'm Takahara Hairi.
Nice to meet you.
It's nice to meet you too.
I'm Misaki Kyouko.
I want you to take care of them both.
Umi-chan's name is written with the
characters for "wing" and "future."
Umi
Wow.
That's a pretty cool name.
Nice to meet you, Umi-chan.
Don't call me "-chan."
What? So I'm the only one who can't?
Don't.
Hey, come to think of it...
Umi
Hairi
You both have "wing" in your name.
Okay, well...
Umi?
Yeah.
Guess we're hanging out for the summer, huh?
That's, uh, a lot of stuff.
Grandma was a pretty serious pack rat.
She had a habit of holding on
to anything that looked rare.
Which is why I've been called to help.
Thanks so much for coming.
Oh, is it time for dinner already?
I'm sorry, though. My cooking is
too unique to serve to anyone else.
There's a dining hall down the hill.
Could I ask you to take Umi-chan?
Thanks.
Well, shall we head home?
Hang on tight.
Off we go!
Uh-oh.
I can't believe we ran out of gas.
We really are in the middle of nowhere.
You mean the stars?
Yeah, the stars.
Look at all of them.
I see them.
Who are you?
Uh, I'm Takahara Hairi.
And this is...
Umi.
Umi?
Yeah.
You?
Shiroha.
Shiroha? That your first name or last?
First name.
How did you know?
You could guess?
So, Shiroha, right?
What are you doing here?
I'm swimming.
I mean, I can see that part.
But why at this hour?
It's not well lit. I think it's dangerous.
What if you get a leg cramp
when no one's here?
You should at least come when
other people are around.
Dosukoi.
Huh?
Dosukoi!
She was a weird one, huh?
She was pretty.
True enough.
I'd come to Torishirojima to help sort
through my grandmother's belongings.
That was how my summer break
started when I was seventeen.
I'm hungry.
Want me to make something?
Any requests?
Fried rice.
Time to eat.
Well? Like it?
Seven points.
Huh? Out of how many?
A hundred.
That's devastatingly low.
I don't want it.
I'm sorry, it's still not ready.
No harm in waiting a little longer.
I know!
Why don't you play with Umi-chan
for me, if you don't mind?
Sure.
Without anything to do anymore,
I explored the island with Umi.
In just a few days, I met lots of people.
They were all a little eccentric,
but everyone was friendly.
A new place, new friends...
A new summer.
I thought maybe I could become
a new person here.
Umi, behold my fried rice rematch.
Let's eat.
Eight points.
Ugh.
You wanna know how to make fried rice?
Let me think.
From what I remember...
Shiroha's fried rice was the best.
Shiroha's fried rice?
Shiroha's parents used to run a diner.
Right.
That's where Shiroha got her flavors from.
It's so peaceful here.
Hello.
I never took you for the fishing type.
The tides aren't working for me today.
What'll you do with your catch?
Eat it. As you should.
You've got a tug.
Here we go!
You're going to eat that?
I-It's the right thing to do.
Don't force yourself.
S-Sea hare is a delicacy.
It tastes like abalone if
you simmer it for an hour.
I hope.
You hope, huh?
Could you lend me your rod?
Don't underestimate the waters of Torishiro.
This isn't exactly an easy spot for a novice.
Got one.
Are you a pro?
No, I'm a beginner.
Wanna give it a try?
Got one.
God?
My name's Umi.
It's ready.
It's so incredibly firm yet chewy!
It's fresh out of the sea.
Like it, Umi?
Ninety-five points!
I'm glad you like it.
Oh, yeah.
Could you teach us how to make fried rice?
What? That's rather sudden.
I want to make fried rice
that'll impress Umi.
The most important part
of fried rice is heat.
First, you need a wok, and...
Wait.
We only have a normal frying pan.
You're out of luck.
Fried rice is serious business.
I want to eat with my family...
Huh? What about family?
You know, like when everyone gets together.
I wouldn't know what that's like.
I don't have parents.
Let's go home.
Yeah?
Guess we should get going.
Well, Shiroha, thanks for the fish.
Yeah.
Bye.
Hey, are you sure you didn't want
to hang out with Shiroha a little longer?
It's fine.
You're a kid. You ought
to ask for things you want.
Kids don't need to hold back.
Okay.
Kyouko-san?
Is something wrong?
Hairi-kun.
Are you by yourself?
Yeah. Just taking a walk.
Is something the matter?
Umi-chan's missing.
My house is always quiet.
It's been a while since Dad said
"I'm home" when he gets back.
I don't know how long.
Those words only ever make things lonelier.
There you are.
Dad?
Nope.
I'm not your dad.
Do you miss him?
He's busy.
Well, dads have to work.
He's just doing his job.
Yeah.
Dad told me a long time ago...
He used to work really hard on something,
but he failed.
He told me he regretted running away.
He ran?
I ran too.
There were people who were kind to me.
People who worried about me.
But I ran.
That's why I'm here.
I want to apologize, but I can't now.
I don't want to run anymore.
Umi...
Yeah, you're right.
We shouldn't run from summer anymore.
Let's go home.
Kyouko-san's worried.
What were you even doing out?
Dad wasn't at home.
Don't call me that.
Wait, you were looking for me?
How come?
Because I don't want to run.
I want to stay with you.
Okay.
Everyone's here.
Umi-chan!
Thank goodness.
Sorry for worrying you.
I'm just glad you're safe.
Everyone, thanks for looking for Umi.
Hey...
Is there anything you want to do?
Anything I want to do?
It's not every day you get
to come to an island like this.
Let's do something
to make the summer memorable.
Something I want to do?
Mom...
Playing house, huh?
I dunno if I can do that at my age.
No.
There's something I want to do with my mom.
All right.
Shall we get Kyouko-san to call her
and ask her to come to the island?
No.
I don't have one.
I don't have a mom anymore.
Oh.
Wanna look for one?
Wanna look for a mom?
Look for one?
Let's find someone who'll be your mom.
You again.
Um...
Could you hear me out?
Uh...
I see.
Umi-chan doesn't have a mom either.
Sorry. This was insensitive.
Listen, why are you going to so much trouble?
She says she doesn't want to run away.
She doesn't want to run?
I never asked from what or anything.
But I fled to this island
after something happened back home.
I came here to get my mind off stuff.
Meanwhile, here's this little kid
saying she doesn't want to run.
So I want to help her.
A watermelon bar.
Bring me one whenever I ask.
And if I do?
You'll get one watermelon
bar's worth of mothering.
That'll be our deal.
Well?
Thank you!
Get this, Umi!
Shiroha says she'll be your mom!
H-Hello.
Oop?
Come on, now.
What do you say when someone says hello?
Oop...
Sorry, looks like she's being shy again.
Huh? Shiroha?
Oop...
Are you nervous?
I-I'm not nervous.
I just don't know how to talk to kids.
Picture Diary
This one.
That'll be 189 yen.
But together with this set
of twelve colored pencils,
I'll sell you both for 1,000 yen.
Sold!
Pleasure doing business!
Thanks, Ao.
Look at him, going all-out.
Dad's working so hard.
Shall we kick off our fun summer break, Umi?
This is a magic picture diary.
Picture Diary
Umi
Write about what you want
to do, and it'll come true.
Wow!
Y-You can actually buy a magic picture diary?
Huh?
August 1st.
Dad sang a song while pretending
to be Quetzalcoatl.
It was so much fun.
Wow, it really is a magic picture diary!
Whoa.
Say, Umi...
Don't you want to see Mom be Quetzalcoatl?
Mom pretended to be Quetzalcoatl
and sang a song for me.
Well, why don't you fill in the rest
of the diary for tomorrow onward?
Okay!
August 2nd.
I made origami with Mom.
She's really good at it.
Hold this part.
Okay.
Now close your eyes for a second.
There.
You can open them.
Mysterious, right?
It's magic!
Maybe it is.
Teach me magic, Mo—
Can I call you Mom?
Mom...
That went far!
The trick to throwing them
is to be gentle and steady.
I've never seen one fly so long.
Best ever?
Yeah, best ever!
Mom's paper airplane is awesome!
My Hyper Mustang Special Dimension
IV Mk III flies better.
Ha.
Snap!
I still have my Super Mustang
Fire Cosmic Mode Level 7.
I haven't shown you my true power yet.
Um...
I want to be friendly.
I want to throw paper
airplanes without fighting.
Not competing, but cooperating.
All of us together.
Yeah!
Ultra Pork Horizon Wee Explosion Four!
Ready and...
Takeoff!