If only Mom were here...
I give it 41 points.
Heck yeah!
A passing grade!
I don't understand.
How can it still taste like this
when you followed my recipe?
You need to practice more, Dad.
Stop calling me that.
Picture Diary
Umi
August 8th. Sunny.
Mom and I played at the pool today.
The slide was so much fun.
Mom, were you watching?
I was.
You did great, Umi-chan.
Thanks, guys.
Seeing her so happy made
pulling that all-nighter worth it.
Besides, Umi's so-called magic
picture diary says this happens, right?
So we had to make it come true.
Yeah!
Magic is absolute.
Guys...
August 11th. Sunny.
Mom and I played hide-and-seek.
Everyone else played with us too.
It was so much fun.
Two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine... ten!
Umi, hurry up and hide!
Are you ready?
I'm ready!
I guess the others are staying quiet so
they don't give away their locations.
Is Umi all right?
Found you.
H-How did that happen?!
You were obvious, peeking out like that.
Up for match two, Kanou!
Here!
Found you, Tenzen-kun.
Shoot!
My tournament habits got me!
Nude party!
Keep your clothes on!
Ryoichi, Nomiki, got you both.
Hey, there's a pervy book here.
Wh-Wh-Where?!
D-D-Don't get the wrong idea!
I just didn't want any littering!
That just leaves Umi-chan.
Where could she be?
Umi-chan, I found—
Got you, Umi-chan.
You found me!
How'd you know where she was?
Just a guess.
I thought she might imitate you.
All right, who's "it" next?
Me?
Gotcha, Tenzen!
Gotcha, Ryoichi!
What?!
Gotcha, Nomiki!
Shoot!
Gotcha, Ao—
I-I-It's not what you think!
We're down to just Umi and Shiroha.
Gotcha, Shiroha—
She fell asleep waiting.
August 12th. Cloudy, then clear.
Mom and I sang together.
Sailors like seagulls
Lined up on the water
White hats, white shirts, white clothes
Riding, plap plap on the waves
I'm defeated.
I've been branded a failure
as a singing instructor.
Be strong, Tsumugi!
Don't give up!
I told you, I have my own singing style.
Singing is hard.
Don't say that, you two.
The most important skill in singing
is breathing with your chest!
You mean with your abdomen.
Traitor.
How?
Okay, let's all sing together!
It's fun when you all do it together!
You too, Dad.
Me?
Sailors like seagulls
Lined up on the water
White hats, white shirts, white clothes
Their singing style is so creative.
August 13th. Sunny, then rain.
Mom read me a book.
So, what kind of story do you want?
We asked Kamome if there might be
any good books for us to read you.
So I figured, why not just
write a picture book?
I'll help too.
You can make picture books?
Yup, you sure can.
Butterflies.
Butterflies?
I want to hear a story about a butterfly.
One with really pretty wings takes flight.
Then it flutters away and goes all over.
You might want to try a brighter color there.
You think so?
You know, though, this might be quicker
if you just did it yourself.
Yeah, maybe.
But this book is going to be special to
Umi-chan because you're the one writing it.
Like this?
Yup.
You're doing great.
Okay.
All done!
The Butterfly's Long, Long Journey
Good for you, Umi-chan.
Read it to me, Mom!
Okay, here we go.
"Long, long ago, the world had no color."
"And in this colorless world, there was
a butterfly with beautiful wings."
"Its wings were all sorts of colors..."
Thank you for having me.
Come back anytime.
I can't believe you made
an entire picture book!
Too bad Umi-chan fell asleep
halfway through it, though.
Especially after Hairi gave
it such a beautiful ending.
No harm done.
We can pick back up next time.
Mom, are you going home?
You woke up?
Sorry, Umi-chan.
See you tomorrow.
Okay.
Dad, could you walk them home?
Don't worry. It's still light out.
Thanks, Umi-chan.
Take an umbrella.
It's going to rain.
Rain?
Dad...
All right.
Thanks for everything today.
It was nothing.
I'm just glad Umi-chan was happy.
I noticed you stopped telling
her not to call you "Dad."
Yeah, I'm kinda getting used to it.
I guess being her dad is fine.
As long as it doesn't bug you, that is.
We'll see.
We'll see?
We'll sea...
Gull.
Ahem!
I should get going.
See you new parents later!
I wonder if I'm any good at being a mom.
I think I told you, but I don't have parents.
So I don't know how other people
spend time with theirs.
Do you think I'm being the mom
that Umi-chan wants me to be?
You know, when I first met Umi,
she was kind of stiff.
Like, shy around new people.
But she's beaming every day now.
And that's thanks to you.
I don't think there's a
right way to be a mom.
I think you just need to do for her
what you would have wanted done for you.
What I would have wanted done for me?
Yeah.
Okay.
Then if I'm being a proper mom, I'm happy too.
Umi nailed the weather forecast.
August 13th
Sunny, then rain. Mom read me a book.
Next, fold this over to here.
Like this?
Yup.
I did it!
Good job, Umi-chan.
Sunny, then rain.
"Sunny, then rain," huh?
Umi wrote this two days ago, didn't she?
It's like she saw it.
Nah.
Just a coincidence.
Nothing to worry about.
Fried rice? First thing in the morning?
I made it myself.
This feels great!
I'm gonna get my license when I turn sixteen!
Hello? Wake up, Takahara-san!
Hairi-san!
Dad.
Wake up.
Sorry.
I had a weird dream.
Hold this part, Dad.
Okay.
Here?
Yup.
Now close your eyes.
Okay.
You can open them.
Hey! How'd you do that?
Mysterious, right?
It actually goes like this.
Wow. That's amazing.
Mom taught me how to make it.
The mommy boat is pretty.
Mom's going to get on a boat.
Shiroha?
Umi-chan...
Are you talking about the Natsudori ritual?
The Natsudori ritual...?
Did you say "Natsudori" ritual?
Yeah.
It's a ceremony that's been passed
down throughout generations.
Basically, it's a festival.
And you're involved?
Yeah.
But no one should know that
yet besides my grandpa.
Umi-chan, you knew I was
going to be on a boat?
Yeah.
And you knew about the rain yesterday?
Do you know about tomorrow too?
Tomorrow?
Yup!
Shiroha?
Mom?
I'm done.
No more playing mom.
No.
No, no!
Mom!
Stay away from me.
I'm sorry.
H-Hey!
Umi?
Dad...
She'll be back.
Mom will come again tomorrow, right?
Yeah. Don't worry about it.
I'm sure she'll be back.
Hey! Wait up, Shiroha!
Shiroha!
I'm cursed.
I'm sorry.
Sorry, Umi...
Shiroha's...
We keep missing each other...
But I won't run.
Because this summer is surely the last.
Umi, what's that?
Mom.
Your mom?
When did we take this?
The 31st?
That doesn't make sense.
Today's only...
Sunny, then thunderstorms.
Take an umbrella.
It's going to rain.
Mom's going to get on a boat.
Do you know about tomorrow too?
Yup!
Umi, hey...
Can you...
I came to see Mom.
Because Mom's gone now.
Because I never knew her.
So...
So you came to this island?
From the future?
Yeah.
So...
Ever since I was little, I've been able
to send my soul a little into the past.
Every time something upset me,
I'd go back like I was running away.
But I always found my way to the same future.
My dad told me that we used to live
on this island when I was born.
But he took me away from here.
He said we'd never come near it again.
He said to forget it.
He never talked about my mom, either.
I think my dad hates me.
It was because I was born.
It's my fault my mom died.
But my dad told me once...
about a summer break he spent with her.
He met her by chance on this island.
They went fishing, flew paper airplanes,
sang songs, played at the pool...
I was jealous of him.
I've never had a summer like that.
I wished I could spend
a summer like that with my mom.
But he went back to the island on his own.
He left me behind.
That's why I came by myself.
By yourself?
Yeah.
I'm fine as long as I have my smartphone apps.
Smartphone apps?
Even my first time on the island,
it felt so nostalgic.
I went to my grandpa's place
and got a picture of my mom.
My dad threw away all his old photos.
That was the first time I saw her.
She's so pretty.
But my dad almost caught me.
I didn't want him to take
the picture away, so I ran.
And I ran, and I ran, and...
Mom...
When I came to, I was here.
Not just my soul, but my body too.
And I've been repeating this
summer over and over.
All so I could spend it with my mom.
But something feels like it's fading away.
I think this summer is my last.
Are you saying your mom is...
Yeah.
I knew it was her right away.
Because she was with you, Dad.
Me? I'm your...
I had no idea.
You believe me?
To be honest, I'm not really following.
This is all so sudden.
It's happening so fast that
I can't wrap my head around it.
But I believe you.
I trust you, Umi.
Still, though...
Future me is horrible.
No.
I've been through so many summers.
I watched you every time,
and I've learned this much...
I know that you're kind.
I'm glad you're my dad.
Umi...
Umi-chan...
You've been on such a long,
lonely journey, haven't you?
I'll make it happen, Umi.
I'll make this summer
break a fun one for you.