Morning, huh?
Umi? When did you...
Mom...
We're going to make summer fun for you again.
Your mom and dad will...
I'll bring Shiroha back. I promise.
I'm cursed.
I'm sorry.
I've gotta figure out
what's going on with her.
Shaved Ice
"I'm cursed," huh?
Do you know anything about that?
Why do you want to know?
For Umi-chan's sake?
Or for Shiroha's?
For my own sake... I think.
What?
Somehow, seeing Umi and Shiroha
together made me happy.
Coming to the island,
I was basically running away.
But seeing them together makes
me feel like I can regain what I've lost.
I want to make this a good summer
for both Umi and Shiroha.
You're pretty greedy.
Or maybe just a do-gooder.
I do know what Shiroha meant
by what she said. But, well...
Hairi, you should hear it for yourself.
It's tugging.
I-I got something!
Starfish tastes like uni.
So it's a delicacy, huh?
Shiroha, Umi's waiting for you.
I told you, I'm not playing mom anymore.
Is that related to you being "cursed"?
You apologized to me yesterday.
And you wouldn't have if this
didn't concern me in some way.
I want you to stay away
from me once I tell you.
I can't promise that.
Then I can't tell you.
Then I'll keep chasing you until you do.
Dosukoi!
I-It's been a while.
That hit hard for some reason, too.
Nevertheless, I still want you to tell me.
I can see it...
The future.
And in the future I see,
I take people with me.
That's why I've been trying
not to get close with anyone.
That could all be coincidence, right?
Yeah.
I've tried thinking that way too.
Thought about changing it.
Thought about running.
I've considered it all.
But everything ultimately leads
to the same future I see.
You don't seem surprised.
I guess you wouldn't be after Umi-chan, huh?
Yeah.
The same goes for me.
I've accepted it's possible to see the future.
That there's no changing the future I see.
She helped me realize that.
So this summer, I'm...
Shiroha...
Just what did you see?
The sea is dark.
It's raining.
I'm watching it from under the water.
And on the surface above,
there are countless red lights.
Why would you be at sea?
The Natsudori ritual.
It's an island festival.
I'm to play the main role
and board a ship to guide
the souls of our ancestors
back to the afterlife.
Something must happen
where I fall into the water.
It's painful.
I can't breathe.
My chest hurts.
So that's what you've been trying to fight.
You were practicing at the pool at night
so you could avoid drowning.
But it didn't accomplish anything.
Umi-chan helped me realize
the future hasn't changed.
It's set in stone.
That's not—
Please...
Don't come near me anymore.
I was supposed to be by myself.
So that my fate won't affect anyone else.
But I'm still sorry.
The time I spent with you two was so, so fun.
Shiroha!
Damn it.
Dad!
Where's Mom?
Sorry.
She's not coming back?
I saw you reading that before.
It's a letter from Mom.
These words are so hard...
You can't read it?
I thought she was reading it
the other day, though.
Want me to read it to you?
Uh-huh.
"Read this when you're sad."
Okay, here I go.
"When you're sad,
you don't need to hold back."
Put your honest thoughts into words.
Tell someone close to you.
Even when you can't handle it alone,
you'll get through when you share it.
"Reach out."
"If you can feel the warmth,
you'll be just fine."
Mom...
Shiroha...
What were you going through
when you wrote this letter?
And Umi...
What were you going through
when you read this letter?
What do you want to do, Umi?
What do you most want right now?
I want to see Mom.
All right.
You can count on Dad.
Okay!
Grandpa's house!
What's Grandpa like?
He's really nice.
Yeah?
He won't mind us dropping by
unannounced, then.
Hairi!
Shiroha.
Go on, Umi.
Mom...
Umi-chan...
We're here to talk.
Umi's worried about you too.
I told you not to come near me.
I don't want you involved.
And I told you I can't just drop it.
You're the one in danger, aren't you?
I don't know about this ritual
or whatever, but...
Shut it, kid!
I don't know where you heard
that goofy rumor,
but it sounds like you took it seriously.
This is a small island.
Baseless talk spread like fire, upset people,
and made Shiroha a loner.
A lo—
Playing her part in the Natsudori
ritual will change that.
Then my granddaughter can stop being a loner!
It's her own fault she's a loner!
A lo—
She's worried that if
the rumor turns out to be true,
she's going to hurt the people around her.
She's isolated herself because she's selfless!
Please stop talking about me like that.
Apologies.
Sorry.
But you aren't alone anymore.
This summer, you've been with the two of us.
We're spending our time together.
Mom...
Umi-chan...
Let's stay together going forward.
I'll protect you from the
dangerous future you saw.
Hairi...
Kid.
My granddaughter lost both
of her parents at a young age,
and I've decided to protect her myself...
From big-mouthed city boys like you!
Show me what you're made of
before flapping your gums, punk!
Fine, let's go! I'll throw down!
Slow down.
I'm not interested in getting you hurt.
We'll settle this with the
island's traditional sport...
Underwater combat!
Those buoys are dangling rope
to form a ring.
The first to throw their opponent
out in the water wins.
In the water?
Hairi...
Getting cold feet? You look pale.
Stop it, Grandpa.
I'm fine, Shiroha.
But...
He'll be okay.
Umi...
Umi-chan...
I'll be waiting.
Come when you're ready.
We're here, Hairi!
Your cheer squad's arrived!
Guys—
Where do I even begin?
This island lacks entertain—
That old man is no slouch.
We're all here to enjoy the—
Teamwork is the key to victory.
I'll give you pointers from the sidelines.
Let's take him down together.
I wanna help Dad out too!
I'm going to be underwater, though.
Thanks anyway.
I'm not as tense now.
Umi, I'm going.
Okay!
I'm fine.
I can still swim.
Umi gave me courage.
You're already here!
Cocky little punk!
He's fast!
Behold, my Fist of Genbu!
Gah!
Damn it, my turn...!
You aren't even trying.
Bwahahaha!
Not good! I'm out of breath!
Can't breathe, can you?
You're free to tap out!
He could easily throw me out of the ring...
He's just trying to make me surrender.
Not good...
I'm really out of breath.
No!
I lost so much before I came to this island!
Still...
Know when to quit!
I'll end this here and now!
Get out of here!
I don't want to run away anymore!
Dad! You got this!
Umi!
It's overrrrr!
What?!
Not so fast!
Bwuh?!
Dad!
Huh?
Umi.
Guys.
Uh...
D-Did I win?
Yeah. That was amazing!
I can't believe you took
out one of the Four Kings.
Yup, yup.
You actually beat Shiroha's grandpa!
You nearly drowned, though,
and so did Shiroha trying to save you.
That was a bit of a bummer.
I see.
So I won.
Wait, I nearly drowned?
And so did Shiroha?!
Don't endanger yourself.
Forget me. Why did you?
Well...
My body moved on its own.
And then I wound up having to rescue
both of you. You accomplished nothing.
Um...
Thank you.
The loser just looks a fool
when the winner is pathetic.
So, what do you want of me?
I'd like to protect Shiroha.
Let me stay by her side during the ritual.
I can't allow that.
Why not?!
Only those involved
in the ritual can participate.
The sole exception is for family.
This ritual is important to the island.
Its customs must be upheld.
No way...
But then how do I help Shiroha?
I'm not happy about this either.
You proved yourself as you promised.
It'll be okay.
You'll make it.
You're my mom, after all.
Shiroha, when did you have a child?!
I-I didn't!
We've been playing house.
Mom's right here.
And Dad's right here.
We're a family.
Which means you and Mom are, um...
Married!
Whoa! H-Hold it, Umi!
Son, when did you and Shiroha...
We didn't!
She's just talking about playing house!
Dad's right here.
You brat!
Get back in the water!
I'll... I'll make flotsam out of you!
And that makes you my grandpa!
You're Mom's grandpa,
so you're my grandpa too.
Your grandpa?
Me? I'm your grandpa?
Grandpa!
That so?
Forgive your gramps, won't ya?
I won't get angry anymore.
A little grandbaby, huh?
Yeah, grandkids are the greatest, aren't they?
I'm your grandkid.
So you're my great-grandpa?
My great-granddaughter...
You have my blessing!
I'll accept that you're married!
Thank you, sir!
Th-This'll only cause trouble for you.
Don't worry about me.
In fact, I'm happy to have
that kind of relationship with you.
B-But we're still only students.
I don't know how to react to being married.
I-In that case, how about we just be...
s-sweethearts instead?
His voice just cracked.
I bet he doesn't say that too often.
S-Sweethearts?
Hey, her voice cracked too.
She probably doesn't use that word often.
I'm serious about my feelings for you.
We're married, but I want you
to be my sweetheart.
B-But I...
Um...
Okay.
All right, time to celebrate the couple!
Congrats!
August 16th. Sunny.
Mom and Dad got married today.
Everyone was smiling.
I'm so happy!
Things moved quickly after that.
With the Natsudori ritual
prep coming along,
we swiftly approached
the fateful day Shiroha saw.
No chance of rain until tonight.
Okay.
I'll see you later, Hairi-kun.
Please take care of Umi for me.
You have to listen to Kyouko-san, okay?
I wanted to see Mom for myself.
There's no way we could let you on the boat.
Don't worry.
I promise I'll protect Shiroha.
To think my nephew who came for the
summer would end up getting married!
A rainbow butterfly...
I feel like I've seen that here before.
Shiroha's waiting.
We hereby begin the butterfly covenant.
Your vision was way off.
I wonder...
You made it through your duties.
I'm sure we've changed the future.
Still, something's weighing on me.
It's raining.
Good thing we're already done.
Where's Umi-chan?
I left her with Kyouko-san.
What's wrong?
Why...?
Why did I just see that?
Shiroha?
Hairi!
Umi-chan's in the boat!