Umi!
Umi-chan!
Dad!
Mom!
Umi!
Umi-chan!
Are you all right?!
Umi!
I'm sorry! I really wanted to see Mom!
It's okay. You don't need to apologize.
Come to me!
Almost there!
You can do it!
Umi-chan!
Umi!
Where are you, Umi?
Shiroha!
Is Umi asleep?
Yeah.
Sound asleep.
Kyouko-san said she'd keep
an eye on her for a while.
Okay.
I'm so glad.
Yeah. Same.
You're safe, too.
Huh? Me?
The whole point of this was changing
the future where you drown.
You're right.
I was so preoccupied with Umi-chan...
You both wound up in danger
because you were with me.
You're wrong.
Umi and I wanted to help you.
You've got nothing to feel guilty about.
But...
Listen, Shiroha, your ability
to see the future is real.
I saw it too.
I saw the red lights floating
on the surface above us.
I could only keep my cool
because you'd given me a heads-up.
Maybe... But it's not like what we did
changed all that much about the future.
Maybe you don't need to.
Just refuse to accept what you see
as the end of the story.
The future you saw was only the trigger.
There's more further ahead.
And I'll bet that future's wonderful.
Even if we have to suffer
a little hardship to get there.
How does that sound?
I've never thought of it that way.
You're too kind, Shiroha.
You're too caught up in protecting
people from yourself.
That's how you ended up a loner.
Stop calling me a loner.
Well, you're not one anymore.
I won't let you be from now on.
You're amazing, Hairi.
The future isn't a conclusion.
It's just a step towards another future.
Thinking of it that way makes it easier.
Thanks.
Well, I'm just glad I could be a help.
Our hardship at sea was just a step
toward something better to come.
Something better... to come...?
What is it, Shiroha?
E-Er, when we were in the water,
amidst the chaos...
You k-k-ki...
Ki?
You kissed me!
Th-Th-That...
wasn't really a k-k-k-k-kiss.
I was just giving you a breath.
It was an emergency measure.
Th-Then does that mean it doesn't count?
F-For sure.
Okay, then I still haven't had my first kiss.
Then neither have I.
Can we now?
Can we what?
Share our first kiss.
Is that a no?
I-I don't mind.
I don't mind, but...
But what?
Let's do it.
O-Okay, then here goes...
I'm home!
Welcome back.
Mom!
Decided to drop by?
Yeah.
Is Umi-chan all right?
She's great.
We just got back from radio calisthenics.
I see.
Thank goodness.
Time to eat!
This is amazing, Shiroha-chan.
It's nothing.
Umi, you shouldn't hold your
chopsticks like that. It's rude.
Oh?
You were holding them just fine before.
I wonder what happened.
I'll get you a spoon.
That's odd.
Is it some complication from yesterday?
The doctor said she'd be fine, though.
Umi, are you hurting anywhere?
I'm not.
Seems it isn't an injury.
You have to fold the edges
crisply or it won't fly right.
Let's make one together.
Pretty origami paper!
Go!
Ultra Great Super Mom's Light Level Max!
She's running around so happily.
She'll be all right.
I pulled a prank on Mom and got in trouble.
Dad got even more in trouble.
But it was really fun.
A prank, huh?
Maybe flip her skirt?
Wh-Why are you looking at me like that?!
I'm giving you ideas!
Man...
I picked up on this a while ago, but...
You're a perv, aren't you?
I-I-I am not!
Skirt flipping, huh? She's on to something.
What?!
See?!
That doesn't mean I'm a perv!
No, you're perverted.
And probably the most
precocious person on the island.
The skirt flip is a simple,
straightforward prank.
It requires no preparation to pull off.
I'll have to prepare emotionally.
You got this, Dad!
I called Shiroha and told her to come over.
Let's go, Umi.
Okay.
A-Ao asked me to come by.
Mom!
Umi-chan.
Like the whisper of a summer breeze...
Uh...
Are you mad?
Did you think I wouldn't be?
No.
Is it possible...
to wipe someone's
memories with a punch?
U-U-Um, so a-actually, there's a reason—
Umi-chan.
This man told you
to do a nasty thing, didn't he?
Umi-chan.
Bad girl.
You understand?
Mom got angry at me.
I'm sorry.
Creep.
Every man loves panties, right?!
Yeah! That's right!
They're just another piece
of clothing anyway!
Exactly!
You make it all weird to go and hide them!
How are those two getting rowdy over ramune?
You got what you deserved.
Okay, sure, but the skirt flip was your idea!
I swear.
Why made you want to pull
a prank on her to begin with?
I told you, it was to make Umi's
picture diary come true.
Umi?
Who's that?
Hey...
Y-Yeah, sure thing.
It was all for Umi-chan.
We wouldn't have put up
with such a stupid idea otherwise.
Umi-chan...
Right, right.
Okay, next up.
Yay!
Hmm? You got two cards there.
Katou Umi
Takahara Hairi
Katou Umi...
What the hell am I doing?!
Umi?
Who's that?
No!
No, no!
I haven't forgotten about Umi!
Umi, it's morning.
Radio calisthenics are already over.
Where's Mom?
Mom...
Mom!
Umi...
What's wrong?
Mom!
Mom...!
I'm right here.
Do you think it's mental regression?
Maybe we should take her to the hospital.
The hospital? Don't wanna!
I'm glad you're my dad.
What's wrong?
Nothing. I just had the feeling I'm
forgetting something important.
Like what?
That's the thing. I'm not sure.
August 24th.
Sunny, then rainy.
It started pouring all of a sudden.
Mom got soaked.
We took a bath together.
It was fun.
Does it itch anywhere, Umi-chan?
To the right.
Here?
Right there.
I'll leave your clothes here.
Oh, okay.
Thanks.
Oh, Dad, come join us!
The whole family!
I can't!
Too soon!
She nailed the weather in her picture diary.
I know.
Strange, isn't it?
I feel like I cheated this summer.
Cheated? How?
When you first asked me to be her mother,
I thought I could get away
with just acting the part.
I'd get my pops that way, too.
There's a ton in the freezer for you.
Yeah.
I know.
Although it seems someone
stopped eating them at some point.
I feel like it'll cheapen
all this if I take them.
I want to make sure Umi-chan
has a fun summer.
Anything for my baby.
I don't think many people get this chance.
Getting to be a mom for a summer...
I mean, I'm sure I'll get to be one, one day.
But I cheated and got to be one early.
Are you saying you want
to hurry up and have kids?
Yeah, maybe.
And I hope they'll be like Umi-chan.
Hairi?
I'll be going back home
when summer break is over.
But I can't do long distance.
I'd miss you so much I'd die.
That's intense.
What, you mean you could do long distance?
I'd die of loneliness.
And I might curse you.
Scary.
Just a figure of speech.
Okay, I guess I'll have to work
hard so I don't get cursed.
Work hard?
I'll find a part-time job, save money,
and come here every weekend.
Th-There's no way that'll work.
I'll make it work.
I want to make it work.
What's with me?
I know you're talking nonsense,
but it's making me happy.
Is this a date?
I guess it is, isn't it?
I see.
So this is a date!
Is this your first?
I go to an all-boys school.
This is my first time on a date too.
Because you were a loner.
Stop calling me that.
Why haven't we done this before?
Done what?
Gone on a date.
Dunno.
Maybe we were too shy.
I guess so.
If we get married...
Where did that come from?
I mean, I'm just thinking hypothetically.
Hypothetically what?
For example, let's say...
If we have kids...
P-Pervert!
Pervert!
Hey, don't get the wrong idea!
Please don't intimidate me.
It's nothing serious.
I was just wondering
if we'd want a boy or a girl.
A girl...?
Umi-chan...
Yeah, Umi...
How did...?
We have to get back to Umi-chan.
Right.
Umi.
Did you follow us here?
You were with us?
Photos?
Yeah.
Let's take photos together.
Yeah...
Seriously.
How could we have forgotten?
I said I would make Umi's wish
come true this summer.
Her wish to spend a fun summer with her mom.
Yet I forgot that I'd forgotten all about her.
Dad.
What is it?
You have to be the one to tell him, Umi-chan.
It'll make him happier if you do.
Dad...
Take a picture with us?
Umi...
Sure thing.
Let's take a picture together.
All three of us.
Okay!
Then, Umi-chan, you be in the middle.
Scooch in more.
Here we go.
Say cheese.
Okay, let's get this developed.
I'll contact you when it's done.
Then the three of us
can come get it together.
But I forgot about Umi again.
Torishirojima
Fireworks Festival
August 29th
Oh, right, the fireworks are tomorrow.
It's a big festival we do
once a year on the island.
It signals the end of the summer.
The end of the summer...
Umi.
Let's go see the fireworks together.
Fireworks?
Okay!
That'll be fun!
I made a promise.
I won't forget it.
Good... night...
Yup. Good night.
The Butterfly's Long, Long Journey
Oh, yeah, I haven't read this
to her to the end yet.
A butterfly with beautiful wings
travels through a colorless world.
It gives the pretty colors off its wings
to the people it meets along the way.
The butterfly continues its journey as
its wings become tattered and colorless...
Why did we write the story like this again?
Rei Miyasaka
Henry Lin
Riley Dalton
William Haggard
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Check: