Morning.
Why am I sleeping over?
I don't remember either.
We didn't do anything... I think.
Uh...
Y-You slept over?
Seems so.
I guess.
W-Well, you're in a relationship,
so I guess it's okay, but...
Anyway, what brings you here so early?
Oh, right.
Here.
You could have called me to come get them.
You two seemed so excited, so I came
as soon as they arrived this morning.
Thanks, Ao.
Wow.
I've never seen Shiroha smile like that.
Must be your doing.
You think?
This is what you call a cringe couple.
Something's missing...
Are we missing some photos?
No, I don't think that's it.
Shiroha, it's ready!
What's my score?
Oh, er, just asking.
Twenty.
It's good, though.
Thanks.
Wait...
Why did I make fried rice, though?
Shiroha's way better at it.
The Butterfly's Long, Long Journey
A picture book?
What's this doing here?
Hey, look.
I found this over there.
One, two...
Mine flew farther last time too, remember?
No.
My Super Mustang Fire Cosmic Mode Level 7 did.
You even remember what you called it.
Our promise...
We promised we'd go see the
fireworks today together, right?
Yeah.
I remember that.
SAUSAGES
GRILLED SQUID
YAKISOBA
Wow.
It really is empty here.
This is my secret spot.
We can watch them here, just the two of us.
Just the two of us, huh?
Wow.
This is bigger than I thought it'd be.
Isn't it?
Summer...
Summer's coming to an end.
Yeah.
Hairi...
We couldn't keep our promise.
I'm sorry.
Umi-chan!
I'm sorry, Umi-chan.
Mom...
You won't go anywhere anymore, right?
Please stay with Mom and Dad.
Please don't cry, Mom.
I want you to be with us always.
I'll be a better mom.
Let's make origami together again.
Let's sing more together.
Let's play hide-and-seek.
I'll find you wherever you go.
And after we have fun,
we can go home and go to bed,
saying good night to each other.
And then the next day,
we'll say good morning.
I want to tell you good morning...
Mom...
I want to stay with you longer too.
But I guess I can't.
Why?
Am I not good enough?
That's not it.
I had so much fun this summer.
It was really, really the best summer.
I'm so happy I got to be with you.
Thank you, Dad.
This summer was really fun.
It was, huh? You had fun, did you?
Well, we're just getting started on the fun.
After summer comes fall,
and then winter and spring...
They'll all be fun.
Your dad will make sure of it.
Okay.
It's so pretty.
I'm so glad I got to see the fireworks.
We kept our promise.
Then let's make another promise.
What should we do next?
I know! Let's make another diary.
For tomorrow onward.
Anything you write in it will happen.
All your wishes will come true!
So...
Please write the rest of your diary.
Thanks, Dad.
But it's okay now.
I already got to do everything I wanted.
I had so much fun this summer.
I got to spend time with my mom and dad.
But I'm sorry.
I made you both so sad.
I went and was happy all on my own...
I was so happy every day.
I had the happiness all to myself.
I've never wanted summer to keep going before!
I was happy too.
I'm so glad I met you.
Mom...
Me too.
I had so much fun spending
the summer with you.
I still wish summer would never end...
Dad...
Dad... Mom...
Thank you.
I had a lot of fun.
But this is bye-bye for a little.
Shiroha?
Why are you crying?
Huh? Am I?
You're right.
You are too, though.
Why are we...
Fireworks?
The fireworks are over.
Yeah...
I was on a long journey.
I got to make memories
I never thought I would.
They were like precious treasures to me.
The summer break that I repeated
started with a little adventure,
and I found a summer where
I made big friendships.
I found a summer in which I turned the
limited time I had into a glimmering memory.
I found a summer in which I nurtured
and guided my memories with those dear to me.
I found a summer in which I learned the vast
possibilities that come with not giving up.
And I found a final summer break
that I got to spend with my mom.
It was all fun.
I was happy.
I adored it.
But if... if I can, I want
to stay with Mom forever.
That was my wish.
The next summer, Dad came
to the island again.
Hey.
Been a while.
Yup.
It sure has.
Congratulations, Shiroha.
You're so pretty.
I can't believe she got married before I did.
Come on, they're so attached to each other.
It took them long enough.
I mean, it did take them a while
to get her grandpa's blessing.
My Shiroha is...
Shiroha is...
Oh, Kobato-san...
See that, Hitomi?
Shiroha-chan's a bride now.
They looked really, really happy.
I wished that moment could last forever.
I guess we're living together
here from now on.
Yeah.
I get to say good morning
to you every single day.
Something wrong?
Well...
I thought I heard a child's voice.
I'm looking forward to this.
Huh?
Say that again...
I said, "I'm pregnant."
You're pregnant...
Pregnant... with our baby.
Seriously?
Seriously.
A-All right!
The islanders...
My great grandpa...
My dad...
Everyone was so nice to Mom.
And they all eagerly awaited my birth.
It made me so, so happy.
You're so strong.
Can you hear me?
Mom's here.
No...
This girl...
She's already...
I haven't seen anything in a long time.
So why...?
Why?
So that's happened...
That's why you came to find me that summer.
Umi-chan...
I'm sorry.
Please don't cry, Mom.
Please don't apologize.
It isn't your fault.
Umi
Man, what an incredible coincidence.
You came up with the same name I did.
Sure enough.
Oh, but Umi's a girl's name, isn't it?
What if it's a boy?
No, don't worry.
Umi-chan, you're Umi-chan now.
That was when Mom changed a little.
Whenever Dad was at work,
she would hide out in the shed
and spend all her time reading old documents.
She seemed to be looking for ways to stop
my ability to go back into the past.
Mom!
If only...
If it weren't for that ability,
we could change the future...
Umi could've lived as a normal girl.
Dad once said that we can change
the future if we refuse to give up.
So to change that summer...
If Mom never had the ability
to see the future...
Shiroha, are you doing research again?
You've gotta cool it.
Shiroha!
Hang in there!
Doctor, please come quick!
Dear Umi-chan,
When you're sad, you don't need to hold back.
Put your honest thoughts into words.
Tell someone close to you. Even when you can't
handle it alone, you'll get through when you share it.
Reach out. If you can feel the warmth,
you'll be just fine.
Shiroha is...
It's Shiroha!
Shiroha...
She's here.
It's Umi.
Our daughter's here.
So please...
Open your eyes, Shiroha...
Mom did all this for me.
She did everything for my sake.
I don't want to see such sadness...
I want to escape!
Where am I?
A hijab.
What?
You mean deja vu?
That's the one.
Hijab.
Dad...
My soul ran away to the past again.
To that summer break.
But I don't exist here
in this summer any longer.
So my mom and dad won't
become friends again.
The future will change.
Thank goodness.
Mom doesn't have to die anymore.
Except it didn't turn out that way...
Dosukoi!
My mom and dad still met.
They met,
fell in love,
spent their summers together,
started a relationship,
and spent that same summer
together again.
Why?
I'm not even here.
Isn't the future supposed to change?
No!
Don't let this happen!
Mom!
Umi-chan...
How?
She didn't meet me this summer.
But my mom still knows me.
Oh.
I see.
It's not that she's seeing the future.
Her soul's coming back
to the past, just like me.
Please open your eyes, Shiroha.
I am born, and my mom dies.
She can't accept that reality.
She has to look away.
So she returns to that summer.
Mom's going down the same
set path over and over,
spinning around and around in a summer cage.
And my soul goes back as well.
You mean deja vu?
That's the one.
Hijab.
The same summer again.
We're being sent toward the same tragedy...
The same unavoidable future.
No...
It's not the future.
For us, we're just reliving the past.
But what do I do?
What am I supposed to do, Mom?
If it weren't for that ability,
we could change the future...
Umi could've lived as a normal girl.
That's it.
If somehow I lose the ability
to go back in time...
I already know what activates it.
It's because I want to run
from unbearable sadness.
Because I'd rather cling to the past
than face a painful future.
Which means something like that
must have happened to my mom too.
Something so sad and painful
that she wanted to run from it.
Sorry, Dad.
I won't follow you anymore.
I'm going to where I have to be.
I'm traveling somewhere so far
away that I probably won't return.
I'll go to where I don't exist.
Rei Miyasaka
Henry Lin
Riley Dalton
William Haggard
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Check: