I continue to fly.
The more I flutter, the further
I go, the more I lose.
After all those summers I spent,
after gathering so many precious
memories and so much emotion...
It all gets hazy.
But someone pushes me.
They take me by the hand.
The body I thought I'd lost is patched
together by various memories...
each one like a prayer.
That tickles.
Wait, ouch.
That hurts.
A coop?
You woke me up?
Erm...
Catherine
Thanks, Catherine.
I'm...
Um...
Where am I?
And who am I?
You say you have no idea who
you are or where you came from?
That's right.
Say hello now.
H-Hello.
Wait, Shiroha!
Her name's Shiroha-chan?
Yeah.
And I'm Naruse... Kobato.
Kobato-san.
You'll want to get a proper check-up for your
amnesia at the hospital on the main island.
I'll arrange for your trip
after you've had something to eat.
Thank you.
Thanks...
Shiroha-chan?
H-H-How do you know my name?
Oh, your dad just...
I don't have a dad.
He's dead.
Hey, how could you make her cry?
I'm sorry.
Wait, you're her dad!
I thought you were dead!
I'm her grandfather.
Couldn't you tell?
Well, eat up before it gets cold.
Right.
Thank you.
This karaage is so good.
Yeah.
That chicken's just from this morning.
No wonder it's so fresh.
Catherine?!
Have you got everything?
Um...
Shiroha-chan!
Sorry about earlier.
Why?
Well...
I was insensitive.
Insensitive?
How should I put it? I know.
I was careless.
Careless?
I was lacking delicacy.
Delicacy?
Well, the point is...
Are we done with the vocab lesson?
Oh, yes.
See you!
See you...
What's the meaning of this?
That's a very good question.
Turns out she's afraid of boats.
As soon as I saw the water before I
got on the boat, I was petrified.
Man... How embarrassing.
No kidding.
Were you careless?
Not that, exactly.
No?
"Careless" is a hard word.
Oh, sorry, that was mean.
You're being insensitive.
That's right.
So anyway, she'll be staying
with us for a while.
Um...
Are you really okay with this?
It's just me and my grandkid living here.
I'm often away at work.
Having you here won't
necessarily be a bad thing.
Just one word of caution.
Please don't mention her parents
around her. Especially her mom.
Is her mom...
Her father died in an accident a month ago.
Soon after, her mother,
who was my daughter, vanished.
It's only been a month since
she lost both her parents.
She may seem like a difficult
child to you, but she's strong.
She rarely ever cries in front of me.
Although, maybe people just lose
the ability to shed tears
in the face of such intense pain.
Anyway, that aside, your name...
So long as we're living together,
you'll need a name.
Any idea what yours might've been?
The sea...
Seven seas...
What's wrong?
That's what came to my mind.
"Seven seas."
When you can't even go out on the water?
"Seven seas"?
Nanami, huh?
Nanami?
Nanami...
Either way, that'll do for now.
Okay.
Nanami...
Is that my name?
What's this?
A wing?
A butterfly.
Nanami.
Sorry.
I heard that's your name.
Dinner's ready.
It's been a few days since I started
living with the Naruse family.
I've walked the island
in search of my memories.
Sadly, there was no sign
of me getting them back anywhere.
Kobato-san works as a fisherman.
Shiroha-chan leaves early in the morning,
comes back for lunch, and then goes out
on her own again until the evening.
And one day...
Let's eat.
Wow, Kobato-san, this is another big haul!
So much gorgeous seafood every day...
Isn't this great, Shiroha-chan?
As fresh and lavish as it is,
I don't know if having sashimi
every day is great for a kid.
Seeing her so expressionless over dinner...
That can't be good.
I hope she'll start enjoying
meals a little more.
There.
All done.
Not bad for leftovers!
Hang on, how did I know I could make
this when I have no memory?
Chao fan?
What did you make?
Shiroha-chan!
We've got chao fan.
You mean fried rice?
No, chao fan.
Fried rice?
Let's split the difference
and call it fried fan!
Fried fan!
That's right!
Fried fan.
Fried fan! Fried fan!
It's good.
Thank goodness!
As fancy and fresh as it is, you get
tired of eating sashimi every day, huh?
Well, sorry for that.
Did you make this, Nanami?
Y-Yes.
Oh, I made some for you too.
It's good.
But this is...
I-Is something wrong?
Oh, no.
Anyway, thanks for this.
I didn't know you could cook.
If you wouldn't mind,
Shiroha could benefit from...
Forget it. You're a guest here.
You don't need to cook for us.
I don't mind cooking.
Thanks for the meal.
I'm going to catch a bit of sleep.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
This tastes like Dad's.
Um...
Could you please tell me how you make it?
Sure, but I kind of just went by feeling.
Besides, your grandpa doesn't
seem to appreciate my cooking.
In that case...
I'll tell you about my secret place.
Your secret place?
It isn't open anymore?
It isn't.
Dad used to cook here.
Mom couldn't cook too much,
so she helped with other stuff.
But Dad died in an accident.
And Mom went somewhere.
She went somewhere? Where?
I don't know.
But I think she went to find Dad.
They were really close.
Shiroha-chan...
I see now.
You've been coming here every day to clean.
It's what Mom used to do.
I'll help too.
What do you think, Shiroha-chan?
It's good.
It's flavored the exact same way.
But Dad's was even better.
I guess I'd need the recipe
to make it just like his...
I think there is one.
Mom wrote a secret recipe.
Is this Shiroha-chan's...
Nanami, I found it.
Really?
Let's see, let's see!
Fried Rice
Ingredients
- Pepper
- Carrots
- Lettuce
- Lord of the river
- Legendary mountain plants
Have you ever seen the legendary
mountain plants that only appear at dusk?
- Water
Natural water beloved by birds of passage,
springing from the peak of the mountains
- Boar King
The carrion flesh of majestic beasts
beloved by birds of passage
-
What've we got here?
Pepper, carrots, lettuce...
Lord of the river?
"Have you ever seen the legendary mountain
plants that only appear at dusk?"
"Natural water beloved by birds of passage,
springing from the peak of the mountains."
"The carrion flesh of majestic beasts
beloved by birds of passage."
Hang on a second.
Those are some mystery ingredients in there.
They're all things you can find on the island.
Mom would gather them, and Dad would cook.
I even helped my mom with it!
Good for you!
Now, I'm gonna go find these. Wanna come help?
Okay!
One of the Four Gods of Torishirojima
Seiryuu
Lord of the River (*Crayfish)
One of the Four Gods of Torishirojima
Suzaku
Freebies
The Legendary Mountain Plants That Only Appear at Dusk
(*Leftover veggies from the produce shop)
One of the Four Gods of Torishirojima
Genbu
Natural Water Beloved by Birds of Passage, Springing
from the Peak of the Mountains (*Spring water to cook rice with)
One of the Four Gods of Torishirojima
Byakko
Carrion Flesh of Majestic Beasts Beloved by Birds of Passage
(*Meat from boars raised by Boar King Sawada)
We got everything we need!
I guess we'll be testing
the fried fan tomorrow.
Rest well, Shiroha-chan.
We're back!
She must have had a ton of fun.
She looked so happy.
Just what were you doing around the island?
Oh, well, y'know, stuff.
That reminds me! I met some friends of yours.
Let's see...
Seiryuu, Suzaku, Byakko, and Genbu-san.
What's this?!
One of the Four Gods of Torishirojima
(The Real) Genbu
Genbu is my designation!
Damn that little punk...
What gives him the right?!
Nanami, thanks for spending
so much time playing with Shiroha.
I appreciate it.
Oh, no, it's not a big deal.
However, I've searched all over and I still
haven't found a clue as to who you are.
Ah, my memory...
Don't worry about it.
You should be worried about it.
Anyway, about this island...
There's a diner by the hill
leading to the port.
You're free to explore as you please,
but even if she asks,
I want you to refuse to go there.
It will only make her sad.
Kobato-san...
Listen, did Shiroha-chan's mother
have any friends or anything?
Let me think.
She had plenty of friends.
She was especially close with...
Yes?
Might you be... Katou Kyouko-san?
Yup, that's me.
You must be Naruse-san's...
I'm Nanami.
I'd like to ask you
about Shiroha-chan's mother.
I've been curious myself.
I can't believe she—I mean, Hitomi—
left Shiroha-chan and vanished.
Did she ever mention anything?
Come to think of it, she came by to talk
a little bit before she disappeared.
What did you discuss?
The folklore of Shirohane.
Shirohane?
It's a story passed down on Torishirojima.
That sort of thing fascinates me,
so I've been doing research.
What is it about?
A woman becoming a butterfly
and going to see someone she loves.
She throws herself into the ocean,
gaining power by giving her life
to the god of the sea.
She transforms into a butterfly with white
wings and flies off to see her beloved.
But in exchange, she loses everything else.
She goes to see a loved one?
That's what you two talked about?
Yes.
Thinking back on it,
she had to have been desperate
to be clinging to folk tales.
What was Hitomi-san like?
Hitomi?
She had this power about her.
With her, even trivial things felt fun.
Oh, yeah! And she would always say...
I'm enjoying the moment so much that
I don't have any time to be nostalgic.
I still don't know anything.
But this folklore of Shirohane...
What was that?
So then...
Would you be the one to tell me something?
Okay, try this.
It's good.
It tastes just like Dad's.
Then...
Shiroha-chan?
Sorry, it's still not right.
It's really, really close.
I followed the recipe, but...
Can you tell me exactly what it's missing?
Let's see...
It was a little sweeter.
Sweeter, huh?
Shiroha-chan, did your dad ever
add anything when he was cooking?
Hmm...
I know! He put in little
black things at the end.
Little black things?
Sesame seeds?
They weren't sesame seeds.
I see.
But there's nothing else
written in the recipe...
What's this?
A generator?
You recognize that, huh?
But I think it's more like...
The sun, maybe, I think.
How do you put the sun in?
I don't know.
But this has to be some kind
of hint for an ingredient.
And so...
Off we go to find the sun!
Whoo!
We thought of so many places
that might be close to the sun,
but not one had anything
that seemed like an ingredient.
Hey, Shiroha!
Long time!
How've you been?
We haven't seen you since summer
break started. We missed you.
Oh, right.
I have a question for you all.
Somewhere on the island that might
have something to do with the sun?
Ai-chan, any ideas?
You're my sun, Ao-chan.
The sun...
Actually, Shiroha-san, haven't you
said something like that before?
Something about the sun being...
What's up?
Does something come to mind?
I might have said something.
Really?
So this is what the sun meant!
Grind these up, and...
Yup, it's slightly sweet.
We found it, Shiroha-chan.
The final ingredient
to the fried fan you remember.
This is my first time here...
You said you were here before.
It's the first time since my mom went away.
Shiroha-chan...
I want to go back...
to a year ago.
I want to go back.
She isn't here anymore.
She used to carry me on her back here.
We'd go back to the shop,
and Dad would be cooking.
The three of us ate together.
It was warm.
But they're gone.
They aren't here this year.
I wanted to bring back
what Shiroha-chan wanted.
But what she really wanted is...
I remember.
I was looking up at big flowers
the same way with someone.
And yet...
I can't remember.
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have made Shiroha-chan
suffer through this.
So I want...
I want to make sure Shiroha-chan
is smiling while I'm here.
Rei Miyasaka
Henry Lin
Riley Dalton
William Haggard
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Check: