How is it this time?
I think his had more pepper.
Darn.
No, I'll keep trying.
Well?
I don't want to make her cry anymore.
I'm going to make sure she's always smiling.
Dad's cooking...
This is how Dad's tasted.
Hooray!
Thanks, Nanami.
Nah, this is only something
we could've pulled off together.
Okay, maybe I'll try some
of your dad's fried fan too.
Nanami?
It's nostalgic.
How strange...
I've had this somewhere before.
What's happening?
It's okay.
You have me, Nanami.
Thanks.
What is this?
Fried fan.
Fried fan, you say?
Shiroha-chan made it.
Right?
A-Actually, I made it with Nanami.
Oh? You did, did you?
Fried fan, hmm...
This flavor...
Explain yourself!
Shiroha, I told you not to go near the diner.
B-But...
We just wanted to recreate the chao—
the fried fan that her father used to make.
Foolishness!
I... I just...
I'm sorry!
Shiroha-chan!
Why would you say such a thing?
Shiroha-chan worked so hard
on that so you could have some.
What?
Because you seemed sad too.
How could you be so awful?
All this'll ever do is keep her
captive to the past.
That's not a good enough reason!
You're hiding something.
Where is Shiroha-chan's mother?
Shiroha-chan said she went somewhere far away.
Shiroha-chan was so happy when
she was at the diner and cooking.
Yet you told me to stay away from it.
Why is that?
Isn't it a place full of good memories
of time well spent with her parents?
Not all memories are nice and pretty.
My wife once told me...
"Our lineage has a strange power.
And that power comes at a price."
Power? At a price?
"So we should strive not
to depend on our power."
I'd ask her what that meant,
but she'd only laugh and say...
"We should just enjoy the summer."
My daughter said the same thing.
That she wanted me to make sure
Shiroha could enjoy her summer break.
And then she vanished.
Shiroha lost her gentle parents.
What can a stubborn old
asshole like me do for her?
But I have kept her away from the diner
so she wouldn't be fixated on her parents.
I know I've treated her awful.
But...
And I appreciate what you've done.
She's seemed so happy since you arrived.
Her father was my son-in-law.
He was sickly, but he was a good man.
And my daughter cared for that
restless little girl with all her heart.
It's strange, don't you think?
Why am I the only one left?
An old geezer like me...
This summer is too full of sadness.
I don't want anyone to be sad.
Not Kobato-san or Shiroha-chan.
I have to end this.
That's my job.
I get the sense that I have to do it.
But why do I feel this way?
I know that!
I know what I'm about to do.
I... I'm...
These...
These are my memories!
I want to throw paper
airplanes without fighting.
Ready and...
Takeoff!
Get this, Umi!
Shiroha says she'll be your mom!
H-Hello.
Oop?
Here we go.
Say cheese.
It's so pretty.
I'm so glad I got to see the fireworks.
We kept our promise.
I came to see Mom.
Because Mom's gone now.
Because I never knew her.
So...
So you came to this island?
From the future?
Yeah.
Of course...
I came here from really far away.
To this summer break.
To help the people dear to me.
Thank you very much.
You're worried about me, aren't you?
But I don't mind.
I'd already made up my mind.
Dad?
Mom?
Why?
Why did you leave me?
Dad...
Mom...
A butterfly?
That dream again...
What was it saying?
The parents are volunteering
at Shiroha-chan's school?
Yeah.
Tomorrow afternoon.
Here.
Thank you.
But wait... It's summer break right now.
We need lanterns for the
Natsudori ritual next week.
There's a class for making them.
The parents usually take part.
I see.
This might be a good opportunity
for the two of them to make up.
I want you to go.
Huh? Me?
Th-That won't do! You have to go, Kobato-san.
I'm sure Shiroha-chan wants you there.
Even though she's been shut
in her room all this time?
Well...
I-I mean, you're really trying,
cooking and all.
Either way, the other kids
will be scared if I go.
I missed my chance to say no.
The Natsudori festival, huh?
I remember making lanterns together.
That was fun.
The Natsudori dance was lovely too.
Right...
I just have to let Shiroha-chan
in on that memory.
I'll make this a fun summer break,
just like the one the three of us had together.
Well, I'm off now.
Watch the house for me.
Sure, sure.
I know.
See you later!
Sheesh.
She can never sit still.
Lanterns
Shiroha-chan's late.
We're about to begin.
She's here!
Her grandpa's not with her.
Shiroha-chan...
Wow, I didn't expect there to be
so many kids on this island.
Shiroha-chan, we're gonna make
the prettiest lanterns ever today.
Yeah.
Okay, everyone, I'm going to tell you
about the lanterns we're making today.
Okay!
These lanterns house
the souls of the deceased.
Your grandparents, your pet cats...
Shiroha-chan?
They contain the souls of all kinds of folks.
And this special time of year is when
they get to come back for a bit.
They'll come to check in on all of us,
then go back on the day of the festival.
So, to make sure they don't
get lost in the darkness,
we light these lanterns
and send them on their way.
All right, everyone,
let's make some lanterns!
Okay!
Shiroha-chan?
I...
I don't want this.
It's goodbye once we make them, right?
They're leaving, aren't they?
Both Mom and Dad.
Well...
Then I don't want to make this!
Shiroha-chan, hey...
Shiroha-chan!
Hold it.
What did you do to Shiroha-chan?
Huh? Me?
I saw you say something to her.
You said something awful, didn't you?
I-It's a misunderstanding!
Sorry, I have to go.
You're not getting away!
Wh-What is it?
Don't bully Shiroha-chan!
Ouch! Ow, you're hurting me!
Dad...
Mom...
Where did you go?
I miss you!
I miss you...
Mom...
I'm home.
We have a guest?
I finally get to pay my respects.
Sorry for dropping in like this, Kobato-chan.
Not at all.
I'm sure they're ecstatic.
It was always Grandma Kato this,
Grandma Kato that.
They were so attached to you.
I appreciate you saying so.
But still...
I can't believe we lost Hitomi-chan too.
Must be that Naruse power.
Oh, jeez.
Being so old's made me such a worrywart.
Hardly.
Well, I'll get going.
My old man is waiting at the port.
You're more than welcome
to come together next time.
I'll take you up on that.
Say hi to Shiroha-chan for me.
U-Um...
Grandma Kato...
Why, if it isn't Shiroha-chan.
My, you've grown so tall.
What a delight to run into you here.
Maybe Hitomi-chan brought us together.
What's the matter?
Do you know about my mother?
Where did my mom go?
Where did she go after she abandoned me?
Shiroha-chan, you mustn't say such things.
You've gotten so big.
I still remember the day you were
born like it was yesterday.
Me?
Yup.
Hitomi-chan cared so much for you.
Shiroha and I have the same power.
But in order to overcome it,
I want to make sure she
has lots of fun summers.
She always thought about you above all else.
So please, believe in Hitomi-chan...
in your mother.
Shiroha and I have the same power.
What did she mean?
The same power as Mom...?
A power?
Strength? Influence?
That doesn't feel right.
Come to think of it, the first
time I had that dream...
Did I wake you? Sorry.
Mom, I had a weird dream.
What was it about?
Well...
A strange butterfly told me that
I have the power to see you.
See? Isn't that weird?
Mom?
You're right.
It was just a weird dream.
Soon after that, Mom vanished.
If she and I have the same power,
she might have gone to see Dad first.
Which means...
Shiroha-chan!
Nanami.
There you are.
Thank goodness. I was so worried.
Everyone else is worried about you too.
Shiroha-chan, are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm okay.
Rei Miyasaka
Henry Lin
Riley Dalton
William Haggard
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Check: