Ever since the parent volunteer day at school,
Shiroha-chan's barely left her room.
An all-too-quiet house...
I'm familiar with this atmosphere.
It really impresses upon you
that you have nowhere you belong.
Not every day of this
long summer has been fun.
But I've already known
a summer that was like that.
I remember a brilliant summer that
the three of us spent together as a family.
Precious memories that are all mine.
I need to share them with Shiroha-chan.
And to that end, there's
something I have to know.
Coming!
Oh my.
Hello there.
So, about what we were
talking about before...
Uh-huh.
There's something that's been bugging me.
You said the woman becomes a butterfly
and gains the ability to fly free,
but that she loses everything in exchange.
Why is that?
Say you have wings that
can take you anywhere.
Even into the past and the future.
What do you think happens
when the boundary
between the past, the future,
and everything else disappears?
Is that really freedom?
Or does it just mean you're stuck?
For me, I envision being trapped
inside something invisible.
It's no different from summer.
Summer break starts in late July
and ends in August.
That makes it special.
But what if I told you that
summer break would go on forever?
You might think you were free,
but it might not be any different
from being locked inside a giant cage.
Say you lost someone you loved
and you had the power to go back in time...
If you were desperate to see them
and you'd give up everything
to be able to do it...
What would I do in that situation?
I'd go.
I know I'm kind of contradicting
what I just said.
But I'm sure I'd go.
Not that I have that kind of power, sadly.
Thank you for having me.
It's strange.
You're suffering from amnesia,
but you're more curious about
the island than yourself, huh?
Nah...
I just thought I might learn something
if I found out more about the island.
Yeah?
I'm sure you know everything already, though.
This isn't the first time
we've had this conversation.
We did just the other day, remember?
Sorry to keep bothering you.
It's fine.
Well, I'll be going.
Summer break's almost over...
Hitomi.
Kyouko-san is right.
I don't think anyone could resist using that
power if it meant seeing someone they missed.
There's no denying that.
Maybe I don't have the right to stop
anyone from using such a power.
Still... I learned so much repeating
that summer over and over.
And I know that there isn't just one future.
But Shiroha-chan's power will
sew the future shut.
Look at all the stalls.
Your grandpa gave us some spending money.
We can get whatever you want.
Yay!
Then I want grilled squid.
Thank goodness.
She's in better spirits.
Like it?
Yeah.
It's good.
Maybe if we could keep
having moments like these,
Shiroha-chan wouldn't be tempted
to use her power.
She was supposed to spend this summer alone.
If my being here and spending time
with her can help her stay strong...
If, after all my summers,
I've saved someone...
If that someone is Shiroha-chan...
I'll be satisfied.
It would mean that my long,
long journey had a purpose.
Nanami?
I'm okay.
Don't mind me.
Let's go.
Getting to walk together like this must be
the last little bit of happiness I'm granted.
What's wrong?
When Dad died, I cried every day.
That's when I heard a voice.
A voice?
It told me I could have the power
to meet him again.
So, um, I could go see him.
I told Mom about it too.
That we might be able to go see Dad.
She was really shocked.
She must have figured it out
and gone by herself.
To see Dad again.
I've been thinking about it
all the time these days.
So what should I do?
Sorry, Nanami...
I have to go.
Wh-Where?
I'm going to see Mom.
To see her?
See? It's here to take me.
Shiroha-chan, that's...
I'm going now.
Wait!
Shiroha-chan!
Sorry, please let me through.
Wait!
Shiroha-chan!
What...
Nanami.
Why did you come?
You can't go any further.
You have to have the special power to go.
Special power?
Yeah.
I think Mom came here.
And she went to see Dad.
By seeing your dad, you mean...
She went into the past.
Mom and I shared that power.
If I make a wish, I can go back.
You did it too, didn't you?
You came here from another time, right?
Well...
Thanks for playing with me.
I wish we could play more,
but I have to go to my mom.
And where is that?
It's taking me now.
No!
You can't go!
I can finally have the power.
And with my power,
I'll go see Mom.
Don't!
Don't.
You can't go.
If you do, you'll lose
more than you can imagine.
More than I can imagine?
Use that power, and you'll lose
so many other precious moments.
I don't get it.
Was my dad dying and my mom disappearing
some kind of price I paid?
I don't...
What's going to happen
to your grandpa if you go away?
Grandpa doesn't want me around.
Do you really think that?
It's not just him, either.
Lots of other people, lots of other
happy summers are waiting for you.
Your memories are waiting for you.
You're lying!
I'm all alone!
My mom abandoned me!
You're wrong!
She never abandoned you.
She did all this for you.
I can tell.
Trust me.
She didn't go to see your dad.
She had a much more important purpose.
And it was for your sake.
She put her life on the line for you.
That's what mothers do.
Still, I wanted to be with her!
I've always been alone since she vanished.
Every day I wake up, it's silent at home.
I can cook for myself,
but it doesn't taste any good eating alone.
No one's there to see me off
when I go to school.
And it's never going to change.
I'm always going to be alone.
Shiroha-chan.
Did you have fun this summer?
Next summer's going to be even more fun.
You're lying.
No.
It's true.
I'll show you.
Don't worry.
I told you, remember?
There are people waiting for you.
Is this a dream?
No, these are memories.
Memories?
They can't be.
I don't remember having this much fun.
It all really happened.
No, it all could happen.
All sorts of people and all sorts
of fun are waiting for you.
Next year and the year after.
Nanami...
Who are you?
I'm...
Let's go home, Shiroha-chan.
We shouldn't be here anymore.
You've got to move on
to the future you just saw.
Thank you.
Thank you, Grandma.
We made it back?
Looks like it.
It's pretty.
Yeah.
Glowing butterflies...
Nanami!
Your hand's fading!
My hand?
Oh, you're right.
Yeah...
I had a feeling, but I guess
that was pretty reckless.
I was born as a weave of
countless memories.
Give them to Shiroha-chan,
and I come undone.
I can't be sewn back.
I'm out of time.
Wh-Why?
Shiroha-chan, I came here
so I could see someone dear to me.
And I did.
That's why I'm disappearing.
I'm going happy.
Nanami... You're happy?
That's right.
You're happy even though you're vanishing?!
Yup.
This is where we say goodbye.
I'm going home with those lanterns.
No...
Not again.
I'm going to be alone again.
I'm going to be by myself again!
You're going to spend lots of happy
time with people in the future.
But... But you won't be there!
Nothing you can do about me, I guess.
Why?
You did so much for me,
even though we just met this summer.
Who are you really?
I'm...
I'm Nanami.
Nanami...
Farewell.
Wait!
I...
I know you.
Umi.
Umi-chan...
Right?
How?
I look different right now.
Why, Umi-chan?!
Shiroha-chan?
Why would you...
Why did you come here?!
Mom...
Silly!
You gained that ability
to grant your own wishes!
So that you could have a fun summer break!
It was for you to find happiness...
So why?
You already made me happy.
I got to spend a wonderful summer with you.
Really, it was so much fun.
Dad was there with us.
It was the summer I always wanted.
It was such a happy summer break.
So why did you go this far?!
This is too much!
You even changed yourself!
I wanted to help you, Mom.
Still!
Everything's going to change because of this!
The summer I was supposed to spend
with you won't happen anymore.
I'm going to grow into a different person.
And if I don't get my power,
I'll never cross paths with you, Umi-chan.
You won't exist!
I know.
I knew that.
So why?!
This power's like a curse, but even so,
I was happy as long as it brought me to you.
Because there's something
I wanted to tell you.
What I never got a chance
to say to you that day.
Good morning.
Rei Miyasaka
Henry Lin
Riley Dalton
William Haggard
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Check: