Umi-chan...
Well, it's time.
I don't think there's
anything left for me to do.
I managed to help you.
I got to see you again
and say what I needed to.
And I got to hear you call my name.
I'm really... so very happy.
Huh?
I think I'm getting kinda tired...
Umi-chan!
I'm resting in Mom's lap.
It's been a long time...
Umi-chan, I just wanted
you to find happiness.
That's all.
Because... I'm your mother.
Yeah.
You're my mom.
And I'm your daughter.
That's why I got this far.
You're right.
You did good, Umi-chan.
You did great.
You did so much for me,
but I still can't thank you for it.
I want to keep being your mom.
I want you to be my little girl.
Mom...
I don't want this!
Don't go anywhere.
I want you to stay with me!
There's still so much I want to do together!
Cooking together, going shopping together,
traveling and taking pictures,
making lots of memories,
looking back on them and reminiscing,
and spending our summers together...
I don't want a summer without you.
And it's not just summer.
I want to be with you all year.
You sound more like a child than me.
This is painful...
I was going to hold it in.
I want to stay with you too.
I want to call you "Mom" more.
I want you to teach me to cook more.
I want to play with you more.
I still want to be with you more.
Mom... Mom... Mom...
I love you.
Umi-chan!
Umi-chan...
Mom, can you do something for me?
What is it?
You can ask me anything.
I want you to sing to me.
I still remember your voice.
I heard it way before that summer.
I was listening the whole time.
I was so loved...
It was so warm and happy.
I want to go back there one more time.
I want to fall asleep in your arms.
No...
Please.
Please don't say that.
You'll be gone if you fall asleep!
I don't think I can stay.
Umi-chan...
Mom.
Mom...
It's all right.
I'm right here.
I wanted to fall asleep
in her arms just like this.
Back when I didn't know Mom,
on nights when Dad was away for work...
I'd go to sleep by myself and remember.
Before even my very first memories,
someone held me gently in their arms.
I saw with my eyes, which couldn't
fully open yet, someone's blurry figure.
I remember that sensation, that warmth.
Sleeping contentedly under a bright sky...
I still remember it hazily.
In that gleaming light,
she held me with a smile.
And she was singing to me.
I've traveled through so many summers
and I've finally realized...
I finally get it.
This is what loss is.
I'm about to lose the past.
I'm losing my existence.
Everything is going to be
as if it never happened.
I'll never be born.
I'll never see them again.
Not Dad, not Mom.
But it's okay.
I still got to do what I wanted to do.
I got to see Mom and spend lots
of fun summers with her.
And in the end, we were together.
Mom...
bye-bye.
Umi-chan...
You had so, so many fun summers.
You got a lifetime's worth of summer breaks.
And you told me about all of them.
You told me how beautiful
summer memories are.
I'll never get that summer back, will I?
But I'm not supposed to want that, am I?
I get it.
I shouldn't be stuck in the past, right?
Still... But still... I remember it.
That was the best summer break I've ever had.
You made me a mother, Umi-chan.
I remember everything.
I don't want to forget any of it.
Umi-chan!
Long, long ago, there was
no color in the world,
but there was a butterfly
with beautiful wings.
Its wings were all sorts of colors.
The butterfly traveled all over the world,
sharing the beautiful hues of its wings
with everyone it met along the way.
Soon, the beautiful butterfly
had gone white.
But still, the butterfly
continued its journey.
Even with its wings in tatters, it flew on.
No one recognized it as the
beautiful butterfly anymore,
but the world was filled with color.
The world was now beautiful.
When it returned to its homeland,
the butterfly came to rest atop a flower.
The butterfly was content
to have met so many others.
Thus it fell into a silent slumber.
And the sadness everyone
felt became the rain.
Huh? There's more to it.
That's the end of the story
just based on what Umi gave us.
But it was kind of a sad ending,
so I tried adding to it.
I see.
Yeah, I like it.
After the rain passed, the butterfly
had turned into a big rainbow.
A big, beautiful bridge
to span the entire world.
Everyone looked up and said, "Thank you."
We will now be arriving at Torishirojima
Fishing Port, Torishirojima Island.
We may experience a strong
impact upon docking.
"Want to come to Torishirojima Island?"
So read the letter I received
just before summer break.
It was from my aunt, my mother's
sister, whom I've never met.
There was a photo in the envelope.
It was strangely nostalgic.
Which is why I ended up coming.
You're cleaning up Grandma's stuff?
That's right.
This is all stuff she was
holding on to for people.
She was storing all this?
And we don't need to give it back?
Most of the owners have already
passed away or aren't replying.
I wonder why they left stuff
with her in the first place.
Have you ever had an experience where...
As a kid, you were playing
outside and you'd find something,
so you put it in your pocket.
Ever do that?
Sure I did. A long time ago.
Didn't we all?
You close the zipper, you make
sure it doesn't fall out,
and you tuck it away carefully.
And yet, before you know it, it's gone.
But then one day, it comes to mind,
so you look inside your pocket
and a fragment of it is still there.
Just a fragment?
Yeah.
Just a really tiny piece.
But by then, you can't remember what it was.
I think that's what this place is.
A place to store things
that mattered to someone...
and that were then forgotten.
So this place is like a pocket, huh?
Yeah.
There's a dining hall about
ten minutes toward the port.
It's about the only place open at this hour.
Aw!
Oh well.
Guess I'll do a lap around
the island and head home.
Huh?
You can't be serious.
It's so hot...
What's wrong?
Nothing.
That guy...
Oh, I haven't seen him around.
Must be a tourist.
I see.
What's wrong?
Do you know him?
No.
I don't.
Anyway, we should run along to see Ai.
She'll be upset if we're late.
Yeah, you're right.
Let's go.
Let me pitch in starting today.
It's what I'm here for, after all.
And I don't have much else to do.
Feel free to put me to work.
Thank you.
So, what should I do?
We're sticking labels on things
and putting them where they belong.
Where they belong?
Follow your gut.
I'll give it a shot.
I had no way of knowing who
left all that clutter there,
where they came from,
or what their hopes were.
Shiratori Poems
of the Seasons
But I did my best to sort through things.
Eventually, I had a vague sense
of a story for each item.
You could call it a map through time.
A map through time, huh?
A time map.
I think I'll call it a day.
Naruse Diner
Excuse me.
Yes?
What can I get for you?
Do you have any recommendations?
Fried rice, maybe...
The fried rice?
That isn't on here.
Oh, sorry, that wasn't a
restaurant recommendation.
What is it, then?
My recommendation.
Here you are.
Please enjoy.
Thank you.
That's good!
This is really good!
Hey, what'd you use to season this?
That's a secret.
Thanks for dinner.
Thank you.
She's a weird one.
Wow, it's all sorted.
Happy to help.
I wonder how I managed
to clean it all up, though.
It's a mystery even to me.
Kyouko-san?
I know that girl.
I remember her.
I won't forget her.
So...
Umi!
A memory from a long-ago summer
that I'd held on to in my pocket...
Even if I were to lose it somehow,
I'll never forget your long journey.
Hairi-kun?
Are you all right?
You spaced out there.
Oh, right.
I'm fine.
Thanks so much, Hairi-kun.
You're a lifesaver.
I'm glad I could finally help.
"Finally"?
Have you been wanting
to help me for that long?
I'm not sure, but I had
this intense feeling, like "at last!"
How strange.
It is.
Well, I'm off.
Yup.
Come back sometime.
I will.
Hairi-kun.
Good luck.
Thanks. I'll do my best.
You're happy with this, right...
Hitomi?
Rei Miyasaka
Henry Lin
Riley Dalton
William Haggard
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Check:
Are you the guy who's been
staying at Katou-san's place?
Yeah.
I was here to help clean up
my grandma's belongings.
Oh, you're...
What, you know him?
Not really. I just passed by him.
At the beginning of summer break, I think.
Hey, listen, we're headed
to the mountain. Wanna come?
The mountain? To do what?
Training!
Mahjong!
Nah, I'm on my way home.
I see.
Right, summer break's almost over.
Thanks for the invite, though.
Bye.
Later!
Yeah, see you again!
There's always next year.
Yeah, I know.
All right!
I'm going to make it even better next year!
I'm gonna surprise everyone.
Sure, sure.
Thanks for letting me do all this.
Oh yeah, could you check on
the light switch in the cave?
It keeps dying.
Hey, aren't you hot?
Mugyu?
That stuffed animal looks hot.
I'm all right.
It's my friend.
I see.
You're friends, are you?
By the way, do you know
what's at that lighthouse?
The lighthouse?
I hang out there all the time,
but nothing, really.
You hang out there?
I have a key.
Wanna come with me?
Really?
Thanks!
Not at all.
Thank you for talking to me.
Shiratori
"I know where it's headed."
For some reason, that was the
thought that crossed my mind.
I can't put it into words,
but it was a strange sensation
tugging at my heart.
I'm sorry!
Hi, sorry, I'm getting off!
W-Wait, sir!
In the same way we get
nostalgic for the past,
I was nostalgic for an unseen future.
I'd come to the island to try
to remember something.
What that was, I didn't know myself.
But I'd spoken about it
to someone, somewhere.
And I was trying to recall it.
I couldn't just sit there...
That girl!
I have to talk to that girl!
Er...
I...
I liked your fried rice.
So...
I'd love for you to teach me how to make it.
Um...
Sure.